(function(){const t=document.createElement("link").relList;if(t&&t.supports&&t.supports("modulepreload"))return;for(const n of document.querySelectorAll('link[rel="modulepreload"]'))i(n);new MutationObserver(n=>{for(const s of n)if(s.type==="childList")for(const r of s.addedNodes)r.tagName==="LINK"&&r.rel==="modulepreload"&&i(r)}).observe(document,{childList:!0,subtree:!0});function o(n){const s={};return n.integrity&&(s.integrity=n.integrity),n.referrerPolicy&&(s.referrerPolicy=n.referrerPolicy),n.crossOrigin==="use-credentials"?s.credentials="include":n.crossOrigin==="anonymous"?s.credentials="omit":s.credentials="same-origin",s}function i(n){if(n.ep)return;n.ep=!0;const s=o(n);fetch(n.href,s)}})();function ji(e){const t=Object.create(null);for(const o of e.split(","))t[o]=1;return o=>o in t}const Z={},Tt=[],Fe=()=>{},Qn=()=>!1,Do=e=>e.charCodeAt(0)===111&&e.charCodeAt(1)===110&&(e.charCodeAt(2)>122||e.charCodeAt(2)<97),xi=e=>e.startsWith("onUpdate:"),pe=Object.assign,Pi=(e,t)=>{const o=e.indexOf(t);o>-1&&e.splice(o,1)},gr=Object.prototype.hasOwnProperty,K=(e,t)=>gr.call(e,t),k=Array.isArray,Rt=e=>mo(e)==="[object Map]",zt=e=>mo(e)==="[object Set]",Zi=e=>mo(e)==="[object Date]",B=e=>typeof e=="function",ie=e=>typeof e=="string",Ve=e=>typeof e=="symbol",J=e=>e!==null&&typeof e=="object",$n=e=>(J(e)||B(e))&&B(e.then)&&B(e.catch),Zn=Object.prototype.toString,mo=e=>Zn.call(e),yr=e=>mo(e).slice(8,-1),Jn=e=>mo(e)==="[object Object]",Ai=e=>ie(e)&&e!=="NaN"&&e[0]!=="-"&&""+parseInt(e,10)===e,Qt=ji(",key,ref,ref_for,ref_key,onVnodeBeforeMount,onVnodeMounted,onVnodeBeforeUpdate,onVnodeUpdated,onVnodeBeforeUnmount,onVnodeUnmounted"),ko=e=>{const t=Object.create(null);return(o=>t[o]||(t[o]=e(o)))},br=/-\w/g,ht=ko(e=>e.replace(br,t=>t.slice(1).toUpperCase())),vr=/\B([A-Z])/g,St=ko(e=>e.replace(vr,"-$1").toLowerCase()),Xn=ko(e=>e.charAt(0).toUpperCase()+e.slice(1)),Zo=ko(e=>e?`on${Xn(e)}`:""),ft=(e,t)=>!Object.is(e,t),wo=(e,...t)=>{for(let o=0;o<e.length;o++)e[o](...t)},es=(e,t,o,i=!1)=>{Object.defineProperty(e,t,{configurable:!0,enumerable:!1,writable:i,value:o})},Lo=e=>{const t=parseFloat(e);return isNaN(t)?e:t};let Ji;const Ho=()=>Ji||(Ji=typeof globalThis<"u"?globalThis:typeof self<"u"?self:typeof window<"u"?window:typeof global<"u"?global:{});function Go(e){if(k(e)){const t={};for(let o=0;o<e.length;o++){const i=e[o],n=ie(i)?qr(i):Go(i);if(n)for(const s in n)t[s]=n[s]}return t}else if(ie(e)||J(e))return e}const Mr=/;(?![^(]*\))/g,Er=/:([^]+)/,wr=/\/\*[^]*?\*\//g;function qr(e){const t={};return e.replace(wr,"").split(Mr).forEach(o=>{if(o){const i=o.split(Er);i.length>1&&(t[i[0].trim()]=i[1].trim())}}),t}function Bo(e){let t="";if(ie(e))t=e;else if(k(e))for(let o=0;o<e.length;o++){const i=Bo(e[o]);i&&(t+=i+" ")}else if(J(e))for(const o in e)e[o]&&(t+=o+" ");return t.trim()}const Or="itemscope,allowfullscreen,formnovalidate,ismap,nomodule,novalidate,readonly",_r=ji(Or);function ts(e){return!!e||e===""}function Sr(e,t){if(e.length!==t.length)return!1;let o=!0;for(let i=0;o&&i<e.length;i++)o=fo(e[i],t[i]);return o}function fo(e,t){if(e===t)return!0;let o=Zi(e),i=Zi(t);if(o||i)return o&&i?e.getTime()===t.getTime():!1;if(o=Ve(e),i=Ve(t),o||i)return e===t;if(o=k(e),i=k(t),o||i)return o&&i?Sr(e,t):!1;if(o=J(e),i=J(t),o||i){if(!o||!i)return!1;const n=Object.keys(e).length,s=Object.keys(t).length;if(n!==s)return!1;for(const r in e){const a=e.hasOwnProperty(r),c=t.hasOwnProperty(r);if(a&&!c||!a&&c||!fo(e[r],t[r]))return!1}}return String(e)===String(t)}function Ii(e,t){return e.findIndex(o=>fo(o,t))}const os=e=>!!(e&&e.__v_isRef===!0),we=e=>ie(e)?e:e==null?"":k(e)||J(e)&&(e.toString===Zn||!B(e.toString))?os(e)?we(e.value):JSON.stringify(e,is,2):String(e),is=(e,t)=>os(t)?is(e,t.value):Rt(t)?{[`Map(${t.size})`]:[...t.entries()].reduce((o,[i,n],s)=>(o[Jo(i,s)+" =>"]=n,o),{})}:zt(t)?{[`Set(${t.size})`]:[...t.values()].map(o=>Jo(o))}:Ve(t)?Jo(t):J(t)&&!k(t)&&!Jn(t)?String(t):t,Jo=(e,t="")=>{var o;return Ve(e)?`Symbol(${(o=e.description)!=null?o:t})`:e};let ve;class jr{constructor(t=!1){this.detached=t,this._active=!0,this._on=0,this.effects=[],this.cleanups=[],this._isPaused=!1,this.parent=ve,!t&&ve&&(this.index=(ve.scopes||(ve.scopes=[])).push(this)-1)}get active(){return this._active}pause(){if(this._active){this._isPaused=!0;let t,o;if(this.scopes)for(t=0,o=this.scopes.length;t<o;t++)this.scopes[t].pause();for(t=0,o=this.effects.length;t<o;t++)this.effects[t].pause()}}resume(){if(this._active&&this._isPaused){this._isPaused=!1;let t,o;if(this.scopes)for(t=0,o=this.scopes.length;t<o;t++)this.scopes[t].resume();for(t=0,o=this.effects.length;t<o;t++)this.effects[t].resume()}}run(t){if(this._active){const o=ve;try{return ve=this,t()}finally{ve=o}}}on(){++this._on===1&&(this.prevScope=ve,ve=this)}off(){this._on>0&&--this._on===0&&(ve=this.prevScope,this.prevScope=void 0)}stop(t){if(this._active){this._active=!1;let o,i;for(o=0,i=this.effects.length;o<i;o++)this.effects[o].stop();for(this.effects.length=0,o=0,i=this.cleanups.length;o<i;o++)this.cleanups[o]();if(this.cleanups.length=0,this.scopes){for(o=0,i=this.scopes.length;o<i;o++)this.scopes[o].stop(!0);this.scopes.length=0}if(!this.detached&&this.parent&&!t){const n=this.parent.scopes.pop();n&&n!==this&&(this.parent.scopes[this.index]=n,n.index=this.index)}this.parent=void 0}}}function xr(){return ve}let ee;const Xo=new WeakSet;class ns{constructor(t){this.fn=t,this.deps=void 0,this.depsTail=void 0,this.flags=5,this.next=void 0,this.cleanup=void 0,this.scheduler=void 0,ve&&ve.active&&ve.effects.push(this)}pause(){this.flags|=64}resume(){this.flags&64&&(this.flags&=-65,Xo.has(this)&&(Xo.delete(this),this.trigger()))}notify(){this.flags&2&&!(this.flags&32)||this.flags&8||rs(this)}run(){if(!(this.flags&1))return this.fn();this.flags|=2,Xi(this),cs(this);const t=ee,o=Ie;ee=this,Ie=!0;try{return this.fn()}finally{as(this),ee=t,Ie=o,this.flags&=-3}}stop(){if(this.flags&1){for(let t=this.deps;t;t=t.nextDep)Ri(t);this.deps=this.depsTail=void 0,Xi(this),this.onStop&&this.onStop(),this.flags&=-2}}trigger(){this.flags&64?Xo.add(this):this.scheduler?this.scheduler():this.runIfDirty()}runIfDirty(){pi(this)&&this.run()}get dirty(){return pi(this)}}let ss=0,$t,Zt;function rs(e,t=!1){if(e.flags|=8,t){e.next=Zt,Zt=e;return}e.next=$t,$t=e}function Ci(){ss++}function Ti(){if(--ss>0)return;if(Zt){let t=Zt;for(Zt=void 0;t;){const o=t.next;t.next=void 0,t.flags&=-9,t=o}}let e;for(;$t;){let t=$t;for($t=void 0;t;){const o=t.next;if(t.next=void 0,t.flags&=-9,t.flags&1)try{t.trigger()}catch(i){e||(e=i)}t=o}}if(e)throw e}function cs(e){for(let t=e.deps;t;t=t.nextDep)t.version=-1,t.prevActiveLink=t.dep.activeLink,t.dep.activeLink=t}function as(e){let t,o=e.depsTail,i=o;for(;i;){const n=i.prevDep;i.version===-1?(i===o&&(o=n),Ri(i),Pr(i)):t=i,i.dep.activeLink=i.prevActiveLink,i.prevActiveLink=void 0,i=n}e.deps=t,e.depsTail=o}function pi(e){for(let t=e.deps;t;t=t.nextDep)if(t.dep.version!==t.version||t.dep.computed&&(ls(t.dep.computed)||t.dep.version!==t.version))return!0;return!!e._dirty}function ls(e){if(e.flags&4&&!(e.flags&16)||(e.flags&=-17,e.globalVersion===so)||(e.globalVersion=so,!e.isSSR&&e.flags&128&&(!e.deps&&!e._dirty||!pi(e))))return;e.flags|=2;const t=e.dep,o=ee,i=Ie;ee=e,Ie=!0;try{cs(e);const n=e.fn(e._value);(t.version===0||ft(n,e._value))&&(e.flags|=128,e._value=n,t.version++)}catch(n){throw t.version++,n}finally{ee=o,Ie=i,as(e),e.flags&=-3}}function Ri(e,t=!1){const{dep:o,prevSub:i,nextSub:n}=e;if(i&&(i.nextSub=n,e.prevSub=void 0),n&&(n.prevSub=i,e.nextSub=void 0),o.subs===e&&(o.subs=i,!i&&o.computed)){o.computed.flags&=-5;for(let s=o.computed.deps;s;s=s.nextDep)Ri(s,!0)}!t&&!--o.sc&&o.map&&o.map.delete(o.key)}function Pr(e){const{prevDep:t,nextDep:o}=e;t&&(t.nextDep=o,e.prevDep=void 0),o&&(o.prevDep=t,e.nextDep=void 0)}let Ie=!0;const us=[];function tt(){us.push(Ie),Ie=!1}function ot(){const e=us.pop();Ie=e===void 0?!0:e}function Xi(e){const{cleanup:t}=e;if(e.cleanup=void 0,t){const o=ee;ee=void 0;try{t()}finally{ee=o}}}let so=0;class Ar{constructor(t,o){this.sub=t,this.dep=o,this.version=o.version,this.nextDep=this.prevDep=this.nextSub=this.prevSub=this.prevActiveLink=void 0}}class Ni{constructor(t){this.computed=t,this.version=0,this.activeLink=void 0,this.subs=void 0,this.map=void 0,this.key=void 0,this.sc=0,this.__v_skip=!0}track(t){if(!ee||!Ie||ee===this.computed)return;let o=this.activeLink;if(o===void 0||o.sub!==ee)o=this.activeLink=new Ar(ee,this),ee.deps?(o.prevDep=ee.depsTail,ee.depsTail.nextDep=o,ee.depsTail=o):ee.deps=ee.depsTail=o,ps(o);else if(o.version===-1&&(o.version=this.version,o.nextDep)){const i=o.nextDep;i.prevDep=o.prevDep,o.prevDep&&(o.prevDep.nextDep=i),o.prevDep=ee.depsTail,o.nextDep=void 0,ee.depsTail.nextDep=o,ee.depsTail=o,ee.deps===o&&(ee.deps=i)}return o}trigger(t){this.version++,so++,this.notify(t)}notify(t){Ci();try{for(let o=this.subs;o;o=o.prevSub)o.sub.notify()&&o.sub.dep.notify()}finally{Ti()}}}function ps(e){if(e.dep.sc++,e.sub.flags&4){const t=e.dep.computed;if(t&&!e.dep.subs){t.flags|=20;for(let i=t.deps;i;i=i.nextDep)ps(i)}const o=e.dep.subs;o!==e&&(e.prevSub=o,o&&(o.nextSub=e)),e.dep.subs=e}}const mi=new WeakMap,qt=Symbol(""),di=Symbol(""),ro=Symbol("");function le(e,t,o){if(Ie&&ee){let i=mi.get(e);i||mi.set(e,i=new Map);let n=i.get(o);n||(i.set(o,n=new Ni),n.map=i,n.key=o),n.track()}}function Je(e,t,o,i,n,s){const r=mi.get(e);if(!r){so++;return}const a=c=>{c&&c.trigger()};if(Ci(),t==="clear")r.forEach(a);else{const c=k(e),m=c&&Ai(o);if(c&&o==="length"){const u=Number(i);r.forEach((d,g)=>{(g==="length"||g===ro||!Ve(g)&&g>=u)&&a(d)})}else switch((o!==void 0||r.has(void 0))&&a(r.get(o)),m&&a(r.get(ro)),t){case"add":c?m&&a(r.get("length")):(a(r.get(qt)),Rt(e)&&a(r.get(di)));break;case"delete":c||(a(r.get(qt)),Rt(e)&&a(r.get(di)));break;case"set":Rt(e)&&a(r.get(qt));break}}Ti()}function At(e){const t=V(e);return t===e?t:(le(t,"iterate",ro),Pe(e)?t:t.map(Ce))}function zo(e){return le(e=V(e),"iterate",ro),e}function lt(e,t){return it(e)?Ot(e)?kt(Ce(t)):kt(t):Ce(t)}const Ir={__proto__:null,[Symbol.iterator](){return ei(this,Symbol.iterator,e=>lt(this,e))},concat(...e){return At(this).concat(...e.map(t=>k(t)?At(t):t))},entries(){return ei(this,"entries",e=>(e[1]=lt(this,e[1]),e))},every(e,t){return Qe(this,"every",e,t,void 0,arguments)},filter(e,t){return Qe(this,"filter",e,t,o=>o.map(i=>lt(this,i)),arguments)},find(e,t){return Qe(this,"find",e,t,o=>lt(this,o),arguments)},findIndex(e,t){return Qe(this,"findIndex",e,t,void 0,arguments)},findLast(e,t){return Qe(this,"findLast",e,t,o=>lt(this,o),arguments)},findLastIndex(e,t){return Qe(this,"findLastIndex",e,t,void 0,arguments)},forEach(e,t){return Qe(this,"forEach",e,t,void 0,arguments)},includes(...e){return ti(this,"includes",e)},indexOf(...e){return ti(this,"indexOf",e)},join(e){return At(this).join(e)},lastIndexOf(...e){return ti(this,"lastIndexOf",e)},map(e,t){return Qe(this,"map",e,t,void 0,arguments)},pop(){return Wt(this,"pop")},push(...e){return Wt(this,"push",e)},reduce(e,...t){return en(this,"reduce",e,t)},reduceRight(e,...t){return en(this,"reduceRight",e,t)},shift(){return Wt(this,"shift")},some(e,t){return Qe(this,"some",e,t,void 0,arguments)},splice(...e){return Wt(this,"splice",e)},toReversed(){return At(this).toReversed()},toSorted(e){return At(this).toSorted(e)},toSpliced(...e){return At(this).toSpliced(...e)},unshift(...e){return Wt(this,"unshift",e)},values(){return ei(this,"values",e=>lt(this,e))}};function ei(e,t,o){const i=zo(e),n=i[t]();return i!==e&&!Pe(e)&&(n._next=n.next,n.next=()=>{const s=n._next();return s.done||(s.value=o(s.value)),s}),n}const Cr=Array.prototype;function Qe(e,t,o,i,n,s){const r=zo(e),a=r!==e&&!Pe(e),c=r[t];if(c!==Cr[t]){const d=c.apply(e,s);return a?Ce(d):d}let m=o;r!==e&&(a?m=function(d,g){return o.call(this,lt(e,d),g,e)}:o.length>2&&(m=function(d,g){return o.call(this,d,g,e)}));const u=c.call(r,m,i);return a&&n?n(u):u}function en(e,t,o,i){const n=zo(e);let s=o;return n!==e&&(Pe(e)?o.length>3&&(s=function(r,a,c){return o.call(this,r,a,c,e)}):s=function(r,a,c){return o.call(this,r,lt(e,a),c,e)}),n[t](s,...i)}function ti(e,t,o){const i=V(e);le(i,"iterate",ro);const n=i[t](...o);return(n===-1||n===!1)&&Li(o[0])?(o[0]=V(o[0]),i[t](...o)):n}function Wt(e,t,o=[]){tt(),Ci();const i=V(e)[t].apply(e,o);return Ti(),ot(),i}const Tr=ji("__proto__,__v_isRef,__isVue"),ms=new Set(Object.getOwnPropertyNames(Symbol).filter(e=>e!=="arguments"&&e!=="caller").map(e=>Symbol[e]).filter(Ve));function Rr(e){Ve(e)||(e=String(e));const t=V(this);return le(t,"has",e),t.hasOwnProperty(e)}class ds{constructor(t=!1,o=!1){this._isReadonly=t,this._isShallow=o}get(t,o,i){if(o==="__v_skip")return t.__v_skip;const n=this._isReadonly,s=this._isShallow;if(o==="__v_isReactive")return!n;if(o==="__v_isReadonly")return n;if(o==="__v_isShallow")return s;if(o==="__v_raw")return i===(n?s?Fr:ys:s?gs:hs).get(t)||Object.getPrototypeOf(t)===Object.getPrototypeOf(i)?t:void 0;const r=k(t);if(!n){let c;if(r&&(c=Ir[o]))return c;if(o==="hasOwnProperty")return Rr}const a=Reflect.get(t,o,ue(t)?t:i);if((Ve(o)?ms.has(o):Tr(o))||(n||le(t,"get",o),s))return a;if(ue(a)){const c=r&&Ai(o)?a:a.value;return n&&J(c)?hi(c):c}return J(a)?n?hi(a):Uo(a):a}}class fs extends ds{constructor(t=!1){super(!1,t)}set(t,o,i,n){let s=t[o];const r=k(t)&&Ai(o);if(!this._isShallow){const m=it(s);if(!Pe(i)&&!it(i)&&(s=V(s),i=V(i)),!r&&ue(s)&&!ue(i))return m||(s.value=i),!0}const a=r?Number(o)<t.length:K(t,o),c=Reflect.set(t,o,i,ue(t)?t:n);return t===V(n)&&(a?ft(i,s)&&Je(t,"set",o,i):Je(t,"add",o,i)),c}deleteProperty(t,o){const i=K(t,o);t[o];const n=Reflect.deleteProperty(t,o);return n&&i&&Je(t,"delete",o,void 0),n}has(t,o){const i=Reflect.has(t,o);return(!Ve(o)||!ms.has(o))&&le(t,"has",o),i}ownKeys(t){return le(t,"iterate",k(t)?"length":qt),Reflect.ownKeys(t)}}class Nr extends ds{constructor(t=!1){super(!0,t)}set(t,o){return!0}deleteProperty(t,o){return!0}}const Dr=new fs,kr=new Nr,Lr=new fs(!0);const fi=e=>e,yo=e=>Reflect.getPrototypeOf(e);function Hr(e,t,o){return function(...i){const n=this.__v_raw,s=V(n),r=Rt(s),a=e==="entries"||e===Symbol.iterator&&r,c=e==="keys"&&r,m=n[e](...i),u=o?fi:t?kt:Ce;return!t&&le(s,"iterate",c?di:qt),{next(){const{value:d,done:g}=m.next();return g?{value:d,done:g}:{value:a?[u(d[0]),u(d[1])]:u(d),done:g}},[Symbol.iterator](){return this}}}}function bo(e){return function(...t){return e==="delete"?!1:e==="clear"?void 0:this}}function Gr(e,t){const o={get(n){const s=this.__v_raw,r=V(s),a=V(n);e||(ft(n,a)&&le(r,"get",n),le(r,"get",a));const{has:c}=yo(r),m=t?fi:e?kt:Ce;if(c.call(r,n))return m(s.get(n));if(c.call(r,a))return m(s.get(a));s!==r&&s.get(n)},get size(){const n=this.__v_raw;return!e&&le(V(n),"iterate",qt),n.size},has(n){const s=this.__v_raw,r=V(s),a=V(n);return e||(ft(n,a)&&le(r,"has",n),le(r,"has",a)),n===a?s.has(n):s.has(n)||s.has(a)},forEach(n,s){const r=this,a=r.__v_raw,c=V(a),m=t?fi:e?kt:Ce;return!e&&le(c,"iterate",qt),a.forEach((u,d)=>n.call(s,m(u),m(d),r))}};return pe(o,e?{add:bo("add"),set:bo("set"),delete:bo("delete"),clear:bo("clear")}:{add(n){!t&&!Pe(n)&&!it(n)&&(n=V(n));const s=V(this);return yo(s).has.call(s,n)||(s.add(n),Je(s,"add",n,n)),this},set(n,s){!t&&!Pe(s)&&!it(s)&&(s=V(s));const r=V(this),{has:a,get:c}=yo(r);let m=a.call(r,n);m||(n=V(n),m=a.call(r,n));const u=c.call(r,n);return r.set(n,s),m?ft(s,u)&&Je(r,"set",n,s):Je(r,"add",n,s),this},delete(n){const s=V(this),{has:r,get:a}=yo(s);let c=r.call(s,n);c||(n=V(n),c=r.call(s,n)),a&&a.call(s,n);const m=s.delete(n);return c&&Je(s,"delete",n,void 0),m},clear(){const n=V(this),s=n.size!==0,r=n.clear();return s&&Je(n,"clear",void 0,void 0),r}}),["keys","values","entries",Symbol.iterator].forEach(n=>{o[n]=Hr(n,e,t)}),o}function Di(e,t){const o=Gr(e,t);return(i,n,s)=>n==="__v_isReactive"?!e:n==="__v_isReadonly"?e:n==="__v_raw"?i:Reflect.get(K(o,n)&&n in i?o:i,n,s)}const Br={get:Di(!1,!1)},zr={get:Di(!1,!0)},Ur={get:Di(!0,!1)};const hs=new WeakMap,gs=new WeakMap,ys=new WeakMap,Fr=new WeakMap;function Wr(e){switch(e){case"Object":case"Array":return 1;case"Map":case"Set":case"WeakMap":case"WeakSet":return 2;default:return 0}}function Vr(e){return e.__v_skip||!Object.isExtensible(e)?0:Wr(yr(e))}function Uo(e){return it(e)?e:ki(e,!1,Dr,Br,hs)}function bs(e){return ki(e,!1,Lr,zr,gs)}function hi(e){return ki(e,!0,kr,Ur,ys)}function ki(e,t,o,i,n){if(!J(e)||e.__v_raw&&!(t&&e.__v_isReactive))return e;const s=Vr(e);if(s===0)return e;const r=n.get(e);if(r)return r;const a=new Proxy(e,s===2?i:o);return n.set(e,a),a}function Ot(e){return it(e)?Ot(e.__v_raw):!!(e&&e.__v_isReactive)}function it(e){return!!(e&&e.__v_isReadonly)}function Pe(e){return!!(e&&e.__v_isShallow)}function Li(e){return e?!!e.__v_raw:!1}function V(e){const t=e&&e.__v_raw;return t?V(t):e}function Kr(e){return!K(e,"__v_skip")&&Object.isExtensible(e)&&es(e,"__v_skip",!0),e}const Ce=e=>J(e)?Uo(e):e,kt=e=>J(e)?hi(e):e;function ue(e){return e?e.__v_isRef===!0:!1}function Ae(e){return vs(e,!1)}function Yr(e){return vs(e,!0)}function vs(e,t){return ue(e)?e:new Qr(e,t)}class Qr{constructor(t,o){this.dep=new Ni,this.__v_isRef=!0,this.__v_isShallow=!1,this._rawValue=o?t:V(t),this._value=o?t:Ce(t),this.__v_isShallow=o}get value(){return this.dep.track(),this._value}set value(t){const o=this._rawValue,i=this.__v_isShallow||Pe(t)||it(t);t=i?t:V(t),ft(t,o)&&(this._rawValue=t,this._value=i?t:Ce(t),this.dep.trigger())}}function _t(e){return ue(e)?e.value:e}const $r={get:(e,t,o)=>t==="__v_raw"?e:_t(Reflect.get(e,t,o)),set:(e,t,o,i)=>{const n=e[t];return ue(n)&&!ue(o)?(n.value=o,!0):Reflect.set(e,t,o,i)}};function Ms(e){return Ot(e)?e:new Proxy(e,$r)}class Zr{constructor(t,o,i){this.fn=t,this.setter=o,this._value=void 0,this.dep=new Ni(this),this.__v_isRef=!0,this.deps=void 0,this.depsTail=void 0,this.flags=16,this.globalVersion=so-1,this.next=void 0,this.effect=this,this.__v_isReadonly=!o,this.isSSR=i}notify(){if(this.flags|=16,!(this.flags&8)&&ee!==this)return rs(this,!0),!0}get value(){const t=this.dep.track();return ls(this),t&&(t.version=this.dep.version),this._value}set value(t){this.setter&&this.setter(t)}}function Jr(e,t,o=!1){let i,n;return B(e)?i=e:(i=e.get,n=e.set),new Zr(i,n,o)}const vo={},jo=new WeakMap;let Et;function Xr(e,t=!1,o=Et){if(o){let i=jo.get(o);i||jo.set(o,i=[]),i.push(e)}}function ec(e,t,o=Z){const{immediate:i,deep:n,once:s,scheduler:r,augmentJob:a,call:c}=o,m=I=>n?I:Pe(I)||n===!1||n===0?Xe(I,1):Xe(I);let u,d,g,h,M=!1,_=!1;if(ue(e)?(d=()=>e.value,M=Pe(e)):Ot(e)?(d=()=>m(e),M=!0):k(e)?(_=!0,M=e.some(I=>Ot(I)||Pe(I)),d=()=>e.map(I=>{if(ue(I))return I.value;if(Ot(I))return m(I);if(B(I))return c?c(I,2):I()})):B(e)?t?d=c?()=>c(e,2):e:d=()=>{if(g){tt();try{g()}finally{ot()}}const I=Et;Et=u;try{return c?c(e,3,[h]):e(h)}finally{Et=I}}:d=Fe,t&&n){const I=d,$=n===!0?1/0:n;d=()=>Xe(I(),$)}const G=xr(),C=()=>{u.stop(),G&&G.active&&Pi(G.effects,u)};if(s&&t){const I=t;t=(...$)=>{I(...$),C()}}let A=_?new Array(e.length).fill(vo):vo;const N=I=>{if(!(!(u.flags&1)||!u.dirty&&!I))if(t){const $=u.run();if(n||M||(_?$.some((re,te)=>ft(re,A[te])):ft($,A))){g&&g();const re=Et;Et=u;try{const te=[$,A===vo?void 0:_&&A[0]===vo?[]:A,h];A=$,c?c(t,3,te):t(...te)}finally{Et=re}}}else u.run()};return a&&a(N),u=new ns(d),u.scheduler=r?()=>r(N,!1):N,h=I=>Xr(I,!1,u),g=u.onStop=()=>{const I=jo.get(u);if(I){if(c)c(I,4);else for(const $ of I)$();jo.delete(u)}},t?i?N(!0):A=u.run():r?r(N.bind(null,!0),!0):u.run(),C.pause=u.pause.bind(u),C.resume=u.resume.bind(u),C.stop=C,C}function Xe(e,t=1/0,o){if(t<=0||!J(e)||e.__v_skip||(o=o||new Map,(o.get(e)||0)>=t))return e;if(o.set(e,t),t--,ue(e))Xe(e.value,t,o);else if(k(e))for(let i=0;i<e.length;i++)Xe(e[i],t,o);else if(zt(e)||Rt(e))e.forEach(i=>{Xe(i,t,o)});else if(Jn(e)){for(const i in e)Xe(e[i],t,o);for(const i of Object.getOwnPropertySymbols(e))Object.prototype.propertyIsEnumerable.call(e,i)&&Xe(e[i],t,o)}return e}function ho(e,t,o,i){try{return i?e(...i):e()}catch(n){Fo(n,t,o)}}function Ke(e,t,o,i){if(B(e)){const n=ho(e,t,o,i);return n&&$n(n)&&n.catch(s=>{Fo(s,t,o)}),n}if(k(e)){const n=[];for(let s=0;s<e.length;s++)n.push(Ke(e[s],t,o,i));return n}}function Fo(e,t,o,i=!0){const n=t?t.vnode:null,{errorHandler:s,throwUnhandledErrorInProduction:r}=t&&t.appContext.config||Z;if(t){let a=t.parent;const c=t.proxy,m=`https://vuejs.org/error-reference/#runtime-${o}`;for(;a;){const u=a.ec;if(u){for(let d=0;d<u.length;d++)if(u[d](e,c,m)===!1)return}a=a.parent}if(s){tt(),ho(s,null,10,[e,c,m]),ot();return}}tc(e,o,n,i,r)}function tc(e,t,o,i=!0,n=!1){if(n)throw e;console.error(e)}const fe=[];let ze=-1;const Nt=[];let ut=null,It=0;const Es=Promise.resolve();let xo=null;function Hi(e){const t=xo||Es;return e?t.then(this?e.bind(this):e):t}function oc(e){let t=ze+1,o=fe.length;for(;t<o;){const i=t+o>>>1,n=fe[i],s=co(n);s<e||s===e&&n.flags&2?t=i+1:o=i}return t}function Gi(e){if(!(e.flags&1)){const t=co(e),o=fe[fe.length-1];!o||!(e.flags&2)&&t>=co(o)?fe.push(e):fe.splice(oc(t),0,e),e.flags|=1,ws()}}function ws(){xo||(xo=Es.then(Os))}function ic(e){k(e)?Nt.push(...e):ut&&e.id===-1?ut.splice(It+1,0,e):e.flags&1||(Nt.push(e),e.flags|=1),ws()}function tn(e,t,o=ze+1){for(;o<fe.length;o++){const i=fe[o];if(i&&i.flags&2){if(e&&i.id!==e.uid)continue;fe.splice(o,1),o--,i.flags&4&&(i.flags&=-2),i(),i.flags&4||(i.flags&=-2)}}}function qs(e){if(Nt.length){const t=[...new Set(Nt)].sort((o,i)=>co(o)-co(i));if(Nt.length=0,ut){ut.push(...t);return}for(ut=t,It=0;It<ut.length;It++){const o=ut[It];o.flags&4&&(o.flags&=-2),o.flags&8||o(),o.flags&=-2}ut=null,It=0}}const co=e=>e.id==null?e.flags&2?-1:1/0:e.id;function Os(e){try{for(ze=0;ze<fe.length;ze++){const t=fe[ze];t&&!(t.flags&8)&&(t.flags&4&&(t.flags&=-2),ho(t,t.i,t.i?15:14),t.flags&4||(t.flags&=-2))}}finally{for(;ze<fe.length;ze++){const t=fe[ze];t&&(t.flags&=-2)}ze=-1,fe.length=0,qs(),xo=null,(fe.length||Nt.length)&&Os()}}let xe=null,_s=null;function Po(e){const t=xe;return xe=e,_s=e&&e.type.__scopeId||null,t}function nc(e,t=xe,o){if(!t||e._n)return e;const i=(...n)=>{i._d&&Co(-1);const s=Po(t);let r;try{r=e(...n)}finally{Po(s),i._d&&Co(1)}return r};return i._n=!0,i._c=!0,i._d=!0,i}function Mo(e,t){if(xe===null)return e;const o=Yo(xe),i=e.dirs||(e.dirs=[]);for(let n=0;n<t.length;n++){let[s,r,a,c=Z]=t[n];s&&(B(s)&&(s={mounted:s,updated:s}),s.deep&&Xe(r),i.push({dir:s,instance:o,value:r,oldValue:void 0,arg:a,modifiers:c}))}return e}function vt(e,t,o,i){const n=e.dirs,s=t&&t.dirs;for(let r=0;r<n.length;r++){const a=n[r];s&&(a.oldValue=s[r].value);let c=a.dir[i];c&&(tt(),Ke(c,o,8,[e.el,a,e,t]),ot())}}const sc=Symbol("_vte"),rc=e=>e.__isTeleport,cc=Symbol("_leaveCb");function Bi(e,t){e.shapeFlag&6&&e.component?(e.transition=t,Bi(e.component.subTree,t)):e.shapeFlag&128?(e.ssContent.transition=t.clone(e.ssContent),e.ssFallback.transition=t.clone(e.ssFallback)):e.transition=t}function Ss(e,t){return B(e)?pe({name:e.name},t,{setup:e}):e}function js(e){e.ids=[e.ids[0]+e.ids[2]+++"-",0,0]}const Ao=new WeakMap;function Jt(e,t,o,i,n=!1){if(k(e)){e.forEach((M,_)=>Jt(M,t&&(k(t)?t[_]:t),o,i,n));return}if(Xt(i)&&!n){i.shapeFlag&512&&i.type.__asyncResolved&&i.component.subTree.component&&Jt(e,t,o,i.component.subTree);return}const s=i.shapeFlag&4?Yo(i.component):i.el,r=n?null:s,{i:a,r:c}=e,m=t&&t.r,u=a.refs===Z?a.refs={}:a.refs,d=a.setupState,g=V(d),h=d===Z?Qn:M=>K(g,M);if(m!=null&&m!==c){if(on(t),ie(m))u[m]=null,h(m)&&(d[m]=null);else if(ue(m)){m.value=null;const M=t;M.k&&(u[M.k]=null)}}if(B(c))ho(c,a,12,[r,u]);else{const M=ie(c),_=ue(c);if(M||_){const G=()=>{if(e.f){const C=M?h(c)?d[c]:u[c]:c.value;if(n)k(C)&&Pi(C,s);else if(k(C))C.includes(s)||C.push(s);else if(M)u[c]=[s],h(c)&&(d[c]=u[c]);else{const A=[s];c.value=A,e.k&&(u[e.k]=A)}}else M?(u[c]=r,h(c)&&(d[c]=r)):_&&(c.value=r,e.k&&(u[e.k]=r))};if(r){const C=()=>{G(),Ao.delete(e)};C.id=-1,Ao.set(e,C),Ee(C,o)}else on(e),G()}}}function on(e){const t=Ao.get(e);t&&(t.flags|=8,Ao.delete(e))}Ho().requestIdleCallback;Ho().cancelIdleCallback;const Xt=e=>!!e.type.__asyncLoader,xs=e=>e.type.__isKeepAlive;function ac(e,t){Ps(e,"a",t)}function lc(e,t){Ps(e,"da",t)}function Ps(e,t,o=he){const i=e.__wdc||(e.__wdc=()=>{let n=o;for(;n;){if(n.isDeactivated)return;n=n.parent}return e()});if(Wo(t,i,o),o){let n=o.parent;for(;n&&n.parent;)xs(n.parent.vnode)&&uc(i,t,o,n),n=n.parent}}function uc(e,t,o,i){const n=Wo(t,e,i,!0);As(()=>{Pi(i[t],n)},o)}function Wo(e,t,o=he,i=!1){if(o){const n=o[e]||(o[e]=[]),s=t.__weh||(t.__weh=(...r)=>{tt();const a=go(o),c=Ke(t,o,e,r);return a(),ot(),c});return i?n.unshift(s):n.push(s),s}}const nt=e=>(t,o=he)=>{(!lo||e==="sp")&&Wo(e,(...i)=>t(...i),o)},pc=nt("bm"),zi=nt("m"),mc=nt("bu"),dc=nt("u"),fc=nt("bum"),As=nt("um"),hc=nt("sp"),gc=nt("rtg"),yc=nt("rtc");function bc(e,t=he){Wo("ec",e,t)}const vc=Symbol.for("v-ndc");function gi(e,t,o,i){let n;const s=o,r=k(e);if(r||ie(e)){const a=r&&Ot(e);let c=!1,m=!1;a&&(c=!Pe(e),m=it(e),e=zo(e)),n=new Array(e.length);for(let u=0,d=e.length;u<d;u++)n[u]=t(c?m?kt(Ce(e[u])):Ce(e[u]):e[u],u,void 0,s)}else if(typeof e=="number"){n=new Array(e);for(let a=0;a<e;a++)n[a]=t(a+1,a,void 0,s)}else if(J(e))if(e[Symbol.iterator])n=Array.from(e,(a,c)=>t(a,c,void 0,s));else{const a=Object.keys(e);n=new Array(a.length);for(let c=0,m=a.length;c<m;c++){const u=a[c];n[c]=t(e[u],u,c,s)}}else n=[];return n}const yi=e=>e?Zs(e)?Yo(e):yi(e.parent):null,eo=pe(Object.create(null),{$:e=>e,$el:e=>e.vnode.el,$data:e=>e.data,$props:e=>e.props,$attrs:e=>e.attrs,$slots:e=>e.slots,$refs:e=>e.refs,$parent:e=>yi(e.parent),$root:e=>yi(e.root),$host:e=>e.ce,$emit:e=>e.emit,$options:e=>Cs(e),$forceUpdate:e=>e.f||(e.f=()=>{Gi(e.update)}),$nextTick:e=>e.n||(e.n=Hi.bind(e.proxy)),$watch:e=>Ac.bind(e)}),oi=(e,t)=>e!==Z&&!e.__isScriptSetup&&K(e,t),Mc={get({_:e},t){if(t==="__v_skip")return!0;const{ctx:o,setupState:i,data:n,props:s,accessCache:r,type:a,appContext:c}=e;if(t[0]!=="$"){const g=r[t];if(g!==void 0)switch(g){case 1:return i[t];case 2:return n[t];case 4:return o[t];case 3:return s[t]}else{if(oi(i,t))return r[t]=1,i[t];if(n!==Z&&K(n,t))return r[t]=2,n[t];if(K(s,t))return r[t]=3,s[t];if(o!==Z&&K(o,t))return r[t]=4,o[t];bi&&(r[t]=0)}}const m=eo[t];let u,d;if(m)return t==="$attrs"&&le(e.attrs,"get",""),m(e);if((u=a.__cssModules)&&(u=u[t]))return u;if(o!==Z&&K(o,t))return r[t]=4,o[t];if(d=c.config.globalProperties,K(d,t))return d[t]},set({_:e},t,o){const{data:i,setupState:n,ctx:s}=e;return oi(n,t)?(n[t]=o,!0):i!==Z&&K(i,t)?(i[t]=o,!0):K(e.props,t)||t[0]==="$"&&t.slice(1)in e?!1:(s[t]=o,!0)},has({_:{data:e,setupState:t,accessCache:o,ctx:i,appContext:n,props:s,type:r}},a){let c;return!!(o[a]||e!==Z&&a[0]!=="$"&&K(e,a)||oi(t,a)||K(s,a)||K(i,a)||K(eo,a)||K(n.config.globalProperties,a)||(c=r.__cssModules)&&c[a])},defineProperty(e,t,o){return o.get!=null?e._.accessCache[t]=0:K(o,"value")&&this.set(e,t,o.value,null),Reflect.defineProperty(e,t,o)}};function nn(e){return k(e)?e.reduce((t,o)=>(t[o]=null,t),{}):e}let bi=!0;function Ec(e){const t=Cs(e),o=e.proxy,i=e.ctx;bi=!1,t.beforeCreate&&sn(t.beforeCreate,e,"bc");const{data:n,computed:s,methods:r,watch:a,provide:c,inject:m,created:u,beforeMount:d,mounted:g,beforeUpdate:h,updated:M,activated:_,deactivated:G,beforeDestroy:C,beforeUnmount:A,destroyed:N,unmounted:I,render:$,renderTracked:re,renderTriggered:te,errorCaptured:Re,serverPrefetch:st,expose:Ne,inheritAttrs:rt,components:yt,directives:De,filters:Ut}=t;if(m&&wc(m,i,null),r)for(const Q in r){const F=r[Q];B(F)&&(i[Q]=F.bind(o))}if(n){const Q=n.call(o,o);J(Q)&&(e.data=Uo(Q))}if(bi=!0,s)for(const Q in s){const F=s[Q],Ye=B(F)?F.bind(o,o):B(F.get)?F.get.bind(o,o):Fe,ct=!B(F)&&B(F.set)?F.set.bind(o):Fe,ke=ae({get:Ye,set:ct});Object.defineProperty(i,Q,{enumerable:!0,configurable:!0,get:()=>ke.value,set:ge=>ke.value=ge})}if(a)for(const Q in a)Is(a[Q],i,o,Q);if(c){const Q=B(c)?c.call(o):c;Reflect.ownKeys(Q).forEach(F=>{qo(F,Q[F])})}u&&sn(u,e,"c");function se(Q,F){k(F)?F.forEach(Ye=>Q(Ye.bind(o))):F&&Q(F.bind(o))}if(se(pc,d),se(zi,g),se(mc,h),se(dc,M),se(ac,_),se(lc,G),se(bc,Re),se(yc,re),se(gc,te),se(fc,A),se(As,I),se(hc,st),k(Ne))if(Ne.length){const Q=e.exposed||(e.exposed={});Ne.forEach(F=>{Object.defineProperty(Q,F,{get:()=>o[F],set:Ye=>o[F]=Ye,enumerable:!0})})}else e.exposed||(e.exposed={});$&&e.render===Fe&&(e.render=$),rt!=null&&(e.inheritAttrs=rt),yt&&(e.components=yt),De&&(e.directives=De),st&&js(e)}function wc(e,t,o=Fe){k(e)&&(e=vi(e));for(const i in e){const n=e[i];let s;J(n)?"default"in n?s=We(n.from||i,n.default,!0):s=We(n.from||i):s=We(n),ue(s)?Object.defineProperty(t,i,{enumerable:!0,configurable:!0,get:()=>s.value,set:r=>s.value=r}):t[i]=s}}function sn(e,t,o){Ke(k(e)?e.map(i=>i.bind(t.proxy)):e.bind(t.proxy),t,o)}function Is(e,t,o,i){let n=i.includes(".")?Ns(o,i):()=>o[i];if(ie(e)){const s=t[e];B(s)&&to(n,s)}else if(B(e))to(n,e.bind(o));else if(J(e))if(k(e))e.forEach(s=>Is(s,t,o,i));else{const s=B(e.handler)?e.handler.bind(o):t[e.handler];B(s)&&to(n,s,e)}}function Cs(e){const t=e.type,{mixins:o,extends:i}=t,{mixins:n,optionsCache:s,config:{optionMergeStrategies:r}}=e.appContext,a=s.get(t);let c;return a?c=a:!n.length&&!o&&!i?c=t:(c={},n.length&&n.forEach(m=>Io(c,m,r,!0)),Io(c,t,r)),J(t)&&s.set(t,c),c}function Io(e,t,o,i=!1){const{mixins:n,extends:s}=t;s&&Io(e,s,o,!0),n&&n.forEach(r=>Io(e,r,o,!0));for(const r in t)if(!(i&&r==="expose")){const a=qc[r]||o&&o[r];e[r]=a?a(e[r],t[r]):t[r]}return e}const qc={data:rn,props:cn,emits:cn,methods:Yt,computed:Yt,beforeCreate:me,created:me,beforeMount:me,mounted:me,beforeUpdate:me,updated:me,beforeDestroy:me,beforeUnmount:me,destroyed:me,unmounted:me,activated:me,deactivated:me,errorCaptured:me,serverPrefetch:me,components:Yt,directives:Yt,watch:_c,provide:rn,inject:Oc};function rn(e,t){return t?e?function(){return pe(B(e)?e.call(this,this):e,B(t)?t.call(this,this):t)}:t:e}function Oc(e,t){return Yt(vi(e),vi(t))}function vi(e){if(k(e)){const t={};for(let o=0;o<e.length;o++)t[e[o]]=e[o];return t}return e}function me(e,t){return e?[...new Set([].concat(e,t))]:t}function Yt(e,t){return e?pe(Object.create(null),e,t):t}function cn(e,t){return e?k(e)&&k(t)?[...new Set([...e,...t])]:pe(Object.create(null),nn(e),nn(t??{})):t}function _c(e,t){if(!e)return t;if(!t)return e;const o=pe(Object.create(null),e);for(const i in t)o[i]=me(e[i],t[i]);return o}function Ts(){return{app:null,config:{isNativeTag:Qn,performance:!1,globalProperties:{},optionMergeStrategies:{},errorHandler:void 0,warnHandler:void 0,compilerOptions:{}},mixins:[],components:{},directives:{},provides:Object.create(null),optionsCache:new WeakMap,propsCache:new WeakMap,emitsCache:new WeakMap}}let Sc=0;function jc(e,t){return function(i,n=null){B(i)||(i=pe({},i)),n!=null&&!J(n)&&(n=null);const s=Ts(),r=new WeakSet,a=[];let c=!1;const m=s.app={_uid:Sc++,_component:i,_props:n,_container:null,_context:s,_instance:null,version:aa,get config(){return s.config},set config(u){},use(u,...d){return r.has(u)||(u&&B(u.install)?(r.add(u),u.install(m,...d)):B(u)&&(r.add(u),u(m,...d))),m},mixin(u){return s.mixins.includes(u)||s.mixins.push(u),m},component(u,d){return d?(s.components[u]=d,m):s.components[u]},directive(u,d){return d?(s.directives[u]=d,m):s.directives[u]},mount(u,d,g){if(!c){const h=m._ceVNode||_e(i,n);return h.appContext=s,g===!0?g="svg":g===!1&&(g=void 0),e(h,u,g),c=!0,m._container=u,u.__vue_app__=m,Yo(h.component)}},onUnmount(u){a.push(u)},unmount(){c&&(Ke(a,m._instance,16),e(null,m._container),delete m._container.__vue_app__)},provide(u,d){return s.provides[u]=d,m},runWithContext(u){const d=Dt;Dt=m;try{return u()}finally{Dt=d}}};return m}}let Dt=null;function qo(e,t){if(he){let o=he.provides;const i=he.parent&&he.parent.provides;i===o&&(o=he.provides=Object.create(i)),o[e]=t}}function We(e,t,o=!1){const i=oa();if(i||Dt){let n=Dt?Dt._context.provides:i?i.parent==null||i.ce?i.vnode.appContext&&i.vnode.appContext.provides:i.parent.provides:void 0;if(n&&e in n)return n[e];if(arguments.length>1)return o&&B(t)?t.call(i&&i.proxy):t}}const xc=Symbol.for("v-scx"),Pc=()=>We(xc);function to(e,t,o){return Rs(e,t,o)}function Rs(e,t,o=Z){const{immediate:i,deep:n,flush:s,once:r}=o,a=pe({},o),c=t&&i||!t&&s!=="post";let m;if(lo){if(s==="sync"){const h=Pc();m=h.__watcherHandles||(h.__watcherHandles=[])}else if(!c){const h=()=>{};return h.stop=Fe,h.resume=Fe,h.pause=Fe,h}}const u=he;a.call=(h,M,_)=>Ke(h,u,M,_);let d=!1;s==="post"?a.scheduler=h=>{Ee(h,u&&u.suspense)}:s!=="sync"&&(d=!0,a.scheduler=(h,M)=>{M?h():Gi(h)}),a.augmentJob=h=>{t&&(h.flags|=4),d&&(h.flags|=2,u&&(h.id=u.uid,h.i=u))};const g=ec(e,t,a);return lo&&(m?m.push(g):c&&g()),g}function Ac(e,t,o){const i=this.proxy,n=ie(e)?e.includes(".")?Ns(i,e):()=>i[e]:e.bind(i,i);let s;B(t)?s=t:(s=t.handler,o=t);const r=go(this),a=Rs(n,s.bind(i),o);return r(),a}function Ns(e,t){const o=t.split(".");return()=>{let i=e;for(let n=0;n<o.length&&i;n++)i=i[o[n]];return i}}const Ic=(e,t)=>t==="modelValue"||t==="model-value"?e.modelModifiers:e[`${t}Modifiers`]||e[`${ht(t)}Modifiers`]||e[`${St(t)}Modifiers`];function Cc(e,t,...o){if(e.isUnmounted)return;const i=e.vnode.props||Z;let n=o;const s=t.startsWith("update:"),r=s&&Ic(i,t.slice(7));r&&(r.trim&&(n=o.map(u=>ie(u)?u.trim():u)),r.number&&(n=o.map(Lo)));let a,c=i[a=Zo(t)]||i[a=Zo(ht(t))];!c&&s&&(c=i[a=Zo(St(t))]),c&&Ke(c,e,6,n);const m=i[a+"Once"];if(m){if(!e.emitted)e.emitted={};else if(e.emitted[a])return;e.emitted[a]=!0,Ke(m,e,6,n)}}const Tc=new WeakMap;function Ds(e,t,o=!1){const i=o?Tc:t.emitsCache,n=i.get(e);if(n!==void 0)return n;const s=e.emits;let r={},a=!1;if(!B(e)){const c=m=>{const u=Ds(m,t,!0);u&&(a=!0,pe(r,u))};!o&&t.mixins.length&&t.mixins.forEach(c),e.extends&&c(e.extends),e.mixins&&e.mixins.forEach(c)}return!s&&!a?(J(e)&&i.set(e,null),null):(k(s)?s.forEach(c=>r[c]=null):pe(r,s),J(e)&&i.set(e,r),r)}function Vo(e,t){return!e||!Do(t)?!1:(t=t.slice(2).replace(/Once$/,""),K(e,t[0].toLowerCase()+t.slice(1))||K(e,St(t))||K(e,t))}function an(e){const{type:t,vnode:o,proxy:i,withProxy:n,propsOptions:[s],slots:r,attrs:a,emit:c,render:m,renderCache:u,props:d,data:g,setupState:h,ctx:M,inheritAttrs:_}=e,G=Po(e);let C,A;try{if(o.shapeFlag&4){const I=n||i,$=I;C=Ue(m.call($,I,u,d,h,g,M)),A=a}else{const I=t;C=Ue(I.length>1?I(d,{attrs:a,slots:r,emit:c}):I(d,null)),A=t.props?a:Rc(a)}}catch(I){oo.length=0,Fo(I,e,1),C=_e(gt)}let N=C;if(A&&_!==!1){const I=Object.keys(A),{shapeFlag:$}=N;I.length&&$&7&&(s&&I.some(xi)&&(A=Nc(A,s)),N=Lt(N,A,!1,!0))}return o.dirs&&(N=Lt(N,null,!1,!0),N.dirs=N.dirs?N.dirs.concat(o.dirs):o.dirs),o.transition&&Bi(N,o.transition),C=N,Po(G),C}const Rc=e=>{let t;for(const o in e)(o==="class"||o==="style"||Do(o))&&((t||(t={}))[o]=e[o]);return t},Nc=(e,t)=>{const o={};for(const i in e)(!xi(i)||!(i.slice(9)in t))&&(o[i]=e[i]);return o};function Dc(e,t,o){const{props:i,children:n,component:s}=e,{props:r,children:a,patchFlag:c}=t,m=s.emitsOptions;if(t.dirs||t.transition)return!0;if(o&&c>=0){if(c&1024)return!0;if(c&16)return i?ln(i,r,m):!!r;if(c&8){const u=t.dynamicProps;for(let d=0;d<u.length;d++){const g=u[d];if(r[g]!==i[g]&&!Vo(m,g))return!0}}}else return(n||a)&&(!a||!a.$stable)?!0:i===r?!1:i?r?ln(i,r,m):!0:!!r;return!1}function ln(e,t,o){const i=Object.keys(t);if(i.length!==Object.keys(e).length)return!0;for(let n=0;n<i.length;n++){const s=i[n];if(t[s]!==e[s]&&!Vo(o,s))return!0}return!1}function kc({vnode:e,parent:t},o){for(;t;){const i=t.subTree;if(i.suspense&&i.suspense.activeBranch===e&&(i.el=e.el),i===e)(e=t.vnode).el=o,t=t.parent;else break}}const ks={},Ls=()=>Object.create(ks),Hs=e=>Object.getPrototypeOf(e)===ks;function Lc(e,t,o,i=!1){const n={},s=Ls();e.propsDefaults=Object.create(null),Gs(e,t,n,s);for(const r in e.propsOptions[0])r in n||(n[r]=void 0);o?e.props=i?n:bs(n):e.type.props?e.props=n:e.props=s,e.attrs=s}function Hc(e,t,o,i){const{props:n,attrs:s,vnode:{patchFlag:r}}=e,a=V(n),[c]=e.propsOptions;let m=!1;if((i||r>0)&&!(r&16)){if(r&8){const u=e.vnode.dynamicProps;for(let d=0;d<u.length;d++){let g=u[d];if(Vo(e.emitsOptions,g))continue;const h=t[g];if(c)if(K(s,g))h!==s[g]&&(s[g]=h,m=!0);else{const M=ht(g);n[M]=Mi(c,a,M,h,e,!1)}else h!==s[g]&&(s[g]=h,m=!0)}}}else{Gs(e,t,n,s)&&(m=!0);let u;for(const d in a)(!t||!K(t,d)&&((u=St(d))===d||!K(t,u)))&&(c?o&&(o[d]!==void 0||o[u]!==void 0)&&(n[d]=Mi(c,a,d,void 0,e,!0)):delete n[d]);if(s!==a)for(const d in s)(!t||!K(t,d))&&(delete s[d],m=!0)}m&&Je(e.attrs,"set","")}function Gs(e,t,o,i){const[n,s]=e.propsOptions;let r=!1,a;if(t)for(let c in t){if(Qt(c))continue;const m=t[c];let u;n&&K(n,u=ht(c))?!s||!s.includes(u)?o[u]=m:(a||(a={}))[u]=m:Vo(e.emitsOptions,c)||(!(c in i)||m!==i[c])&&(i[c]=m,r=!0)}if(s){const c=V(o),m=a||Z;for(let u=0;u<s.length;u++){const d=s[u];o[d]=Mi(n,c,d,m[d],e,!K(m,d))}}return r}function Mi(e,t,o,i,n,s){const r=e[o];if(r!=null){const a=K(r,"default");if(a&&i===void 0){const c=r.default;if(r.type!==Function&&!r.skipFactory&&B(c)){const{propsDefaults:m}=n;if(o in m)i=m[o];else{const u=go(n);i=m[o]=c.call(null,t),u()}}else i=c;n.ce&&n.ce._setProp(o,i)}r[0]&&(s&&!a?i=!1:r[1]&&(i===""||i===St(o))&&(i=!0))}return i}const Gc=new WeakMap;function Bs(e,t,o=!1){const i=o?Gc:t.propsCache,n=i.get(e);if(n)return n;const s=e.props,r={},a=[];let c=!1;if(!B(e)){const u=d=>{c=!0;const[g,h]=Bs(d,t,!0);pe(r,g),h&&a.push(...h)};!o&&t.mixins.length&&t.mixins.forEach(u),e.extends&&u(e.extends),e.mixins&&e.mixins.forEach(u)}if(!s&&!c)return J(e)&&i.set(e,Tt),Tt;if(k(s))for(let u=0;u<s.length;u++){const d=ht(s[u]);un(d)&&(r[d]=Z)}else if(s)for(const u in s){const d=ht(u);if(un(d)){const g=s[u],h=r[d]=k(g)||B(g)?{type:g}:pe({},g),M=h.type;let _=!1,G=!0;if(k(M))for(let C=0;C<M.length;++C){const A=M[C],N=B(A)&&A.name;if(N==="Boolean"){_=!0;break}else N==="String"&&(G=!1)}else _=B(M)&&M.name==="Boolean";h[0]=_,h[1]=G,(_||K(h,"default"))&&a.push(d)}}const m=[r,a];return J(e)&&i.set(e,m),m}function un(e){return e[0]!=="$"&&!Qt(e)}const Ui=e=>e==="_"||e==="_ctx"||e==="$stable",Fi=e=>k(e)?e.map(Ue):[Ue(e)],Bc=(e,t,o)=>{if(t._n)return t;const i=nc((...n)=>Fi(t(...n)),o);return i._c=!1,i},zs=(e,t,o)=>{const i=e._ctx;for(const n in e){if(Ui(n))continue;const s=e[n];if(B(s))t[n]=Bc(n,s,i);else if(s!=null){const r=Fi(s);t[n]=()=>r}}},Us=(e,t)=>{const o=Fi(t);e.slots.default=()=>o},Fs=(e,t,o)=>{for(const i in t)(o||!Ui(i))&&(e[i]=t[i])},zc=(e,t,o)=>{const i=e.slots=Ls();if(e.vnode.shapeFlag&32){const n=t._;n?(Fs(i,t,o),o&&es(i,"_",n,!0)):zs(t,i)}else t&&Us(e,t)},Uc=(e,t,o)=>{const{vnode:i,slots:n}=e;let s=!0,r=Z;if(i.shapeFlag&32){const a=t._;a?o&&a===1?s=!1:Fs(n,t,o):(s=!t.$stable,zs(t,n)),r=t}else t&&(Us(e,t),r={default:1});if(s)for(const a in n)!Ui(a)&&r[a]==null&&delete n[a]},Ee=Yc;function Fc(e){return Wc(e)}function Wc(e,t){const o=Ho();o.__VUE__=!0;const{insert:i,remove:n,patchProp:s,createElement:r,createText:a,createComment:c,setText:m,setElementText:u,parentNode:d,nextSibling:g,setScopeId:h=Fe,insertStaticContent:M}=e,_=(l,p,f,b=null,E=null,y=null,S=void 0,O=null,q=!!p.dynamicChildren)=>{if(l===p)return;l&&!Vt(l,p)&&(b=v(l),ge(l,E,y,!0),l=null),p.patchFlag===-2&&(q=!1,p.dynamicChildren=null);const{type:w,ref:D,shapeFlag:x}=p;switch(w){case Ko:G(l,p,f,b);break;case gt:C(l,p,f,b);break;case ni:l==null&&A(p,f,b,S);break;case je:yt(l,p,f,b,E,y,S,O,q);break;default:x&1?$(l,p,f,b,E,y,S,O,q):x&6?De(l,p,f,b,E,y,S,O,q):(x&64||x&128)&&w.process(l,p,f,b,E,y,S,O,q,T)}D!=null&&E?Jt(D,l&&l.ref,y,p||l,!p):D==null&&l&&l.ref!=null&&Jt(l.ref,null,y,l,!0)},G=(l,p,f,b)=>{if(l==null)i(p.el=a(p.children),f,b);else{const E=p.el=l.el;p.children!==l.children&&m(E,p.children)}},C=(l,p,f,b)=>{l==null?i(p.el=c(p.children||""),f,b):p.el=l.el},A=(l,p,f,b)=>{[l.el,l.anchor]=M(l.children,p,f,b,l.el,l.anchor)},N=({el:l,anchor:p},f,b)=>{let E;for(;l&&l!==p;)E=g(l),i(l,f,b),l=E;i(p,f,b)},I=({el:l,anchor:p})=>{let f;for(;l&&l!==p;)f=g(l),n(l),l=f;n(p)},$=(l,p,f,b,E,y,S,O,q)=>{if(p.type==="svg"?S="svg":p.type==="math"&&(S="mathml"),l==null)re(p,f,b,E,y,S,O,q);else{const w=l.el&&l.el._isVueCE?l.el:null;try{w&&w._beginPatch(),st(l,p,E,y,S,O,q)}finally{w&&w._endPatch()}}},re=(l,p,f,b,E,y,S,O)=>{let q,w;const{props:D,shapeFlag:x,transition:R,dirs:H}=l;if(q=l.el=r(l.type,y,D&&D.is,D),x&8?u(q,l.children):x&16&&Re(l.children,q,null,b,E,ii(l,y),S,O),H&&vt(l,null,b,"created"),te(q,l,l.scopeId,S,b),D){for(const X in D)X!=="value"&&!Qt(X)&&s(q,X,null,D[X],y,b);"value"in D&&s(q,"value",null,D.value,y),(w=D.onVnodeBeforeMount)&&Be(w,b,l)}H&&vt(l,null,b,"beforeMount");const U=Vc(E,R);U&&R.beforeEnter(q),i(q,p,f),((w=D&&D.onVnodeMounted)||U||H)&&Ee(()=>{w&&Be(w,b,l),U&&R.enter(q),H&&vt(l,null,b,"mounted")},E)},te=(l,p,f,b,E)=>{if(f&&h(l,f),b)for(let y=0;y<b.length;y++)h(l,b[y]);if(E){let y=E.subTree;if(p===y||Ks(y.type)&&(y.ssContent===p||y.ssFallback===p)){const S=E.vnode;te(l,S,S.scopeId,S.slotScopeIds,E.parent)}}},Re=(l,p,f,b,E,y,S,O,q=0)=>{for(let w=q;w<l.length;w++){const D=l[w]=O?pt(l[w]):Ue(l[w]);_(null,D,p,f,b,E,y,S,O)}},st=(l,p,f,b,E,y,S)=>{const O=p.el=l.el;let{patchFlag:q,dynamicChildren:w,dirs:D}=p;q|=l.patchFlag&16;const x=l.props||Z,R=p.props||Z;let H;if(f&&Mt(f,!1),(H=R.onVnodeBeforeUpdate)&&Be(H,f,p,l),D&&vt(p,l,f,"beforeUpdate"),f&&Mt(f,!0),(x.innerHTML&&R.innerHTML==null||x.textContent&&R.textContent==null)&&u(O,""),w?Ne(l.dynamicChildren,w,O,f,b,ii(p,E),y):S||F(l,p,O,null,f,b,ii(p,E),y,!1),q>0){if(q&16)rt(O,x,R,f,E);else if(q&2&&x.class!==R.class&&s(O,"class",null,R.class,E),q&4&&s(O,"style",x.style,R.style,E),q&8){const U=p.dynamicProps;for(let X=0;X<U.length;X++){const Y=U[X],ye=x[Y],be=R[Y];(be!==ye||Y==="value")&&s(O,Y,ye,be,E,f)}}q&1&&l.children!==p.children&&u(O,p.children)}else!S&&w==null&&rt(O,x,R,f,E);((H=R.onVnodeUpdated)||D)&&Ee(()=>{H&&Be(H,f,p,l),D&&vt(p,l,f,"updated")},b)},Ne=(l,p,f,b,E,y,S)=>{for(let O=0;O<p.length;O++){const q=l[O],w=p[O],D=q.el&&(q.type===je||!Vt(q,w)||q.shapeFlag&198)?d(q.el):f;_(q,w,D,null,b,E,y,S,!0)}},rt=(l,p,f,b,E)=>{if(p!==f){if(p!==Z)for(const y in p)!Qt(y)&&!(y in f)&&s(l,y,p[y],null,E,b);for(const y in f){if(Qt(y))continue;const S=f[y],O=p[y];S!==O&&y!=="value"&&s(l,y,O,S,E,b)}"value"in f&&s(l,"value",p.value,f.value,E)}},yt=(l,p,f,b,E,y,S,O,q)=>{const w=p.el=l?l.el:a(""),D=p.anchor=l?l.anchor:a("");let{patchFlag:x,dynamicChildren:R,slotScopeIds:H}=p;H&&(O=O?O.concat(H):H),l==null?(i(w,f,b),i(D,f,b),Re(p.children||[],f,D,E,y,S,O,q)):x>0&&x&64&&R&&l.dynamicChildren?(Ne(l.dynamicChildren,R,f,E,y,S,O),(p.key!=null||E&&p===E.subTree)&&Ws(l,p,!0)):F(l,p,f,D,E,y,S,O,q)},De=(l,p,f,b,E,y,S,O,q)=>{p.slotScopeIds=O,l==null?p.shapeFlag&512?E.ctx.activate(p,f,b,S,q):Ut(p,f,b,E,y,S,q):jt(l,p,q)},Ut=(l,p,f,b,E,y,S)=>{const O=l.component=ta(l,b,E);if(xs(l)&&(O.ctx.renderer=T),ia(O,!1,S),O.asyncDep){if(E&&E.registerDep(O,se,S),!l.el){const q=O.subTree=_e(gt);C(null,q,p,f),l.placeholder=q.el}}else se(O,l,p,f,E,y,S)},jt=(l,p,f)=>{const b=p.component=l.component;if(Dc(l,p,f))if(b.asyncDep&&!b.asyncResolved){Q(b,p,f);return}else b.next=p,b.update();else p.el=l.el,b.vnode=p},se=(l,p,f,b,E,y,S)=>{const O=()=>{if(l.isMounted){let{next:x,bu:R,u:H,parent:U,vnode:X}=l;{const He=Vs(l);if(He){x&&(x.el=X.el,Q(l,x,S)),He.asyncDep.then(()=>{l.isUnmounted||O()});return}}let Y=x,ye;Mt(l,!1),x?(x.el=X.el,Q(l,x,S)):x=X,R&&wo(R),(ye=x.props&&x.props.onVnodeBeforeUpdate)&&Be(ye,U,x,X),Mt(l,!0);const be=an(l),Le=l.subTree;l.subTree=be,_(Le,be,d(Le.el),v(Le),l,E,y),x.el=be.el,Y===null&&kc(l,be.el),H&&Ee(H,E),(ye=x.props&&x.props.onVnodeUpdated)&&Ee(()=>Be(ye,U,x,X),E)}else{let x;const{el:R,props:H}=p,{bm:U,m:X,parent:Y,root:ye,type:be}=l,Le=Xt(p);Mt(l,!1),U&&wo(U),!Le&&(x=H&&H.onVnodeBeforeMount)&&Be(x,Y,p),Mt(l,!0);{ye.ce&&ye.ce._def.shadowRoot!==!1&&ye.ce._injectChildStyle(be);const He=l.subTree=an(l);_(null,He,f,b,l,E,y),p.el=He.el}if(X&&Ee(X,E),!Le&&(x=H&&H.onVnodeMounted)){const He=p;Ee(()=>Be(x,Y,He),E)}(p.shapeFlag&256||Y&&Xt(Y.vnode)&&Y.vnode.shapeFlag&256)&&l.a&&Ee(l.a,E),l.isMounted=!0,p=f=b=null}};l.scope.on();const q=l.effect=new ns(O);l.scope.off();const w=l.update=q.run.bind(q),D=l.job=q.runIfDirty.bind(q);D.i=l,D.id=l.uid,q.scheduler=()=>Gi(D),Mt(l,!0),w()},Q=(l,p,f)=>{p.component=l;const b=l.vnode.props;l.vnode=p,l.next=null,Hc(l,p.props,b,f),Uc(l,p.children,f),tt(),tn(l),ot()},F=(l,p,f,b,E,y,S,O,q=!1)=>{const w=l&&l.children,D=l?l.shapeFlag:0,x=p.children,{patchFlag:R,shapeFlag:H}=p;if(R>0){if(R&128){ct(w,x,f,b,E,y,S,O,q);return}else if(R&256){Ye(w,x,f,b,E,y,S,O,q);return}}H&8?(D&16&&Se(w,E,y),x!==w&&u(f,x)):D&16?H&16?ct(w,x,f,b,E,y,S,O,q):Se(w,E,y,!0):(D&8&&u(f,""),H&16&&Re(x,f,b,E,y,S,O,q))},Ye=(l,p,f,b,E,y,S,O,q)=>{l=l||Tt,p=p||Tt;const w=l.length,D=p.length,x=Math.min(w,D);let R;for(R=0;R<x;R++){const H=p[R]=q?pt(p[R]):Ue(p[R]);_(l[R],H,f,null,E,y,S,O,q)}w>D?Se(l,E,y,!0,!1,x):Re(p,f,b,E,y,S,O,q,x)},ct=(l,p,f,b,E,y,S,O,q)=>{let w=0;const D=p.length;let x=l.length-1,R=D-1;for(;w<=x&&w<=R;){const H=l[w],U=p[w]=q?pt(p[w]):Ue(p[w]);if(Vt(H,U))_(H,U,f,null,E,y,S,O,q);else break;w++}for(;w<=x&&w<=R;){const H=l[x],U=p[R]=q?pt(p[R]):Ue(p[R]);if(Vt(H,U))_(H,U,f,null,E,y,S,O,q);else break;x--,R--}if(w>x){if(w<=R){const H=R+1,U=H<D?p[H].el:b;for(;w<=R;)_(null,p[w]=q?pt(p[w]):Ue(p[w]),f,U,E,y,S,O,q),w++}}else if(w>R)for(;w<=x;)ge(l[w],E,y,!0),w++;else{const H=w,U=w,X=new Map;for(w=U;w<=R;w++){const Me=p[w]=q?pt(p[w]):Ue(p[w]);Me.key!=null&&X.set(Me.key,w)}let Y,ye=0;const be=R-U+1;let Le=!1,He=0;const Ft=new Array(be);for(w=0;w<be;w++)Ft[w]=0;for(w=H;w<=x;w++){const Me=l[w];if(ye>=be){ge(Me,E,y,!0);continue}let Ge;if(Me.key!=null)Ge=X.get(Me.key);else for(Y=U;Y<=R;Y++)if(Ft[Y-U]===0&&Vt(Me,p[Y])){Ge=Y;break}Ge===void 0?ge(Me,E,y,!0):(Ft[Ge-U]=w+1,Ge>=He?He=Ge:Le=!0,_(Me,p[Ge],f,null,E,y,S,O,q),ye++)}const Yi=Le?Kc(Ft):Tt;for(Y=Yi.length-1,w=be-1;w>=0;w--){const Me=U+w,Ge=p[Me],Qi=p[Me+1],$i=Me+1<D?Qi.el||Qi.placeholder:b;Ft[w]===0?_(null,Ge,f,$i,E,y,S,O,q):Le&&(Y<0||w!==Yi[Y]?ke(Ge,f,$i,2):Y--)}}},ke=(l,p,f,b,E=null)=>{const{el:y,type:S,transition:O,children:q,shapeFlag:w}=l;if(w&6){ke(l.component.subTree,p,f,b);return}if(w&128){l.suspense.move(p,f,b);return}if(w&64){S.move(l,p,f,T);return}if(S===je){i(y,p,f);for(let x=0;x<q.length;x++)ke(q[x],p,f,b);i(l.anchor,p,f);return}if(S===ni){N(l,p,f);return}if(b!==2&&w&1&&O)if(b===0)O.beforeEnter(y),i(y,p,f),Ee(()=>O.enter(y),E);else{const{leave:x,delayLeave:R,afterLeave:H}=O,U=()=>{l.ctx.isUnmounted?n(y):i(y,p,f)},X=()=>{y._isLeaving&&y[cc](!0),x(y,()=>{U(),H&&H()})};R?R(y,U,X):X()}else i(y,p,f)},ge=(l,p,f,b=!1,E=!1)=>{const{type:y,props:S,ref:O,children:q,dynamicChildren:w,shapeFlag:D,patchFlag:x,dirs:R,cacheIndex:H}=l;if(x===-2&&(E=!1),O!=null&&(tt(),Jt(O,null,f,l,!0),ot()),H!=null&&(p.renderCache[H]=void 0),D&256){p.ctx.deactivate(l);return}const U=D&1&&R,X=!Xt(l);let Y;if(X&&(Y=S&&S.onVnodeBeforeUnmount)&&Be(Y,p,l),D&6)bt(l.component,f,b);else{if(D&128){l.suspense.unmount(f,b);return}U&&vt(l,null,p,"beforeUnmount"),D&64?l.type.remove(l,p,f,T,b):w&&!w.hasOnce&&(y!==je||x>0&&x&64)?Se(w,p,f,!1,!0):(y===je&&x&384||!E&&D&16)&&Se(q,p,f),b&&xt(l)}(X&&(Y=S&&S.onVnodeUnmounted)||U)&&Ee(()=>{Y&&Be(Y,p,l),U&&vt(l,null,p,"unmounted")},f)},xt=l=>{const{type:p,el:f,anchor:b,transition:E}=l;if(p===je){Pt(f,b);return}if(p===ni){I(l);return}const y=()=>{n(f),E&&!E.persisted&&E.afterLeave&&E.afterLeave()};if(l.shapeFlag&1&&E&&!E.persisted){const{leave:S,delayLeave:O}=E,q=()=>S(f,y);O?O(l.el,y,q):q()}else y()},Pt=(l,p)=>{let f;for(;l!==p;)f=g(l),n(l),l=f;n(p)},bt=(l,p,f)=>{const{bum:b,scope:E,job:y,subTree:S,um:O,m:q,a:w}=l;pn(q),pn(w),b&&wo(b),E.stop(),y&&(y.flags|=8,ge(S,l,p,f)),O&&Ee(O,p),Ee(()=>{l.isUnmounted=!0},p)},Se=(l,p,f,b=!1,E=!1,y=0)=>{for(let S=y;S<l.length;S++)ge(l[S],p,f,b,E)},v=l=>{if(l.shapeFlag&6)return v(l.component.subTree);if(l.shapeFlag&128)return l.suspense.next();const p=g(l.anchor||l.el),f=p&&p[sc];return f?g(f):p};let P=!1;const j=(l,p,f)=>{l==null?p._vnode&&ge(p._vnode,null,null,!0):_(p._vnode||null,l,p,null,null,null,f),p._vnode=l,P||(P=!0,tn(),qs(),P=!1)},T={p:_,um:ge,m:ke,r:xt,mt:Ut,mc:Re,pc:F,pbc:Ne,n:v,o:e};return{render:j,hydrate:void 0,createApp:jc(j)}}function ii({type:e,props:t},o){return o==="svg"&&e==="foreignObject"||o==="mathml"&&e==="annotation-xml"&&t&&t.encoding&&t.encoding.includes("html")?void 0:o}function Mt({effect:e,job:t},o){o?(e.flags|=32,t.flags|=4):(e.flags&=-33,t.flags&=-5)}function Vc(e,t){return(!e||e&&!e.pendingBranch)&&t&&!t.persisted}function Ws(e,t,o=!1){const i=e.children,n=t.children;if(k(i)&&k(n))for(let s=0;s<i.length;s++){const r=i[s];let a=n[s];a.shapeFlag&1&&!a.dynamicChildren&&((a.patchFlag<=0||a.patchFlag===32)&&(a=n[s]=pt(n[s]),a.el=r.el),!o&&a.patchFlag!==-2&&Ws(r,a)),a.type===Ko&&a.patchFlag!==-1&&(a.el=r.el),a.type===gt&&!a.el&&(a.el=r.el)}}function Kc(e){const t=e.slice(),o=[0];let i,n,s,r,a;const c=e.length;for(i=0;i<c;i++){const m=e[i];if(m!==0){if(n=o[o.length-1],e[n]<m){t[i]=n,o.push(i);continue}for(s=0,r=o.length-1;s<r;)a=s+r>>1,e[o[a]]<m?s=a+1:r=a;m<e[o[s]]&&(s>0&&(t[i]=o[s-1]),o[s]=i)}}for(s=o.length,r=o[s-1];s-- >0;)o[s]=r,r=t[r];return o}function Vs(e){const t=e.subTree.component;if(t)return t.asyncDep&&!t.asyncResolved?t:Vs(t)}function pn(e){if(e)for(let t=0;t<e.length;t++)e[t].flags|=8}const Ks=e=>e.__isSuspense;function Yc(e,t){t&&t.pendingBranch?k(e)?t.effects.push(...e):t.effects.push(e):ic(e)}const je=Symbol.for("v-fgt"),Ko=Symbol.for("v-txt"),gt=Symbol.for("v-cmt"),ni=Symbol.for("v-stc"),oo=[];let Oe=null;function ce(e=!1){oo.push(Oe=e?null:[])}function Qc(){oo.pop(),Oe=oo[oo.length-1]||null}let ao=1;function Co(e,t=!1){ao+=e,e<0&&Oe&&t&&(Oe.hasOnce=!0)}function Ys(e){return e.dynamicChildren=ao>0?Oe||Tt:null,Qc(),ao>0&&Oe&&Oe.push(e),e}function qe(e,t,o,i,n,s){return Ys(L(e,t,o,i,n,s,!0))}function To(e,t,o,i,n){return Ys(_e(e,t,o,i,n,!0))}function Ro(e){return e?e.__v_isVNode===!0:!1}function Vt(e,t){return e.type===t.type&&e.key===t.key}const Qs=({key:e})=>e??null,Oo=({ref:e,ref_key:t,ref_for:o})=>(typeof e=="number"&&(e=""+e),e!=null?ie(e)||ue(e)||B(e)?{i:xe,r:e,k:t,f:!!o}:e:null);function L(e,t=null,o=null,i=0,n=null,s=e===je?0:1,r=!1,a=!1){const c={__v_isVNode:!0,__v_skip:!0,type:e,props:t,key:t&&Qs(t),ref:t&&Oo(t),scopeId:_s,slotScopeIds:null,children:o,component:null,suspense:null,ssContent:null,ssFallback:null,dirs:null,transition:null,el:null,anchor:null,target:null,targetStart:null,targetAnchor:null,staticCount:0,shapeFlag:s,patchFlag:i,dynamicProps:n,dynamicChildren:null,appContext:null,ctx:xe};return a?(Wi(c,o),s&128&&e.normalize(c)):o&&(c.shapeFlag|=ie(o)?8:16),ao>0&&!r&&Oe&&(c.patchFlag>0||s&6)&&c.patchFlag!==32&&Oe.push(c),c}const _e=$c;function $c(e,t=null,o=null,i=0,n=null,s=!1){if((!e||e===vc)&&(e=gt),Ro(e)){const a=Lt(e,t,!0);return o&&Wi(a,o),ao>0&&!s&&Oe&&(a.shapeFlag&6?Oe[Oe.indexOf(e)]=a:Oe.push(a)),a.patchFlag=-2,a}if(ca(e)&&(e=e.__vccOpts),t){t=Zc(t);let{class:a,style:c}=t;a&&!ie(a)&&(t.class=Bo(a)),J(c)&&(Li(c)&&!k(c)&&(c=pe({},c)),t.style=Go(c))}const r=ie(e)?1:Ks(e)?128:rc(e)?64:J(e)?4:B(e)?2:0;return L(e,t,o,i,n,r,s,!0)}function Zc(e){return e?Li(e)||Hs(e)?pe({},e):e:null}function Lt(e,t,o=!1,i=!1){const{props:n,ref:s,patchFlag:r,children:a,transition:c}=e,m=t?Jc(n||{},t):n,u={__v_isVNode:!0,__v_skip:!0,type:e.type,props:m,key:m&&Qs(m),ref:t&&t.ref?o&&s?k(s)?s.concat(Oo(t)):[s,Oo(t)]:Oo(t):s,scopeId:e.scopeId,slotScopeIds:e.slotScopeIds,children:a,target:e.target,targetStart:e.targetStart,targetAnchor:e.targetAnchor,staticCount:e.staticCount,shapeFlag:e.shapeFlag,patchFlag:t&&e.type!==je?r===-1?16:r|16:r,dynamicProps:e.dynamicProps,dynamicChildren:e.dynamicChildren,appContext:e.appContext,dirs:e.dirs,transition:c,component:e.component,suspense:e.suspense,ssContent:e.ssContent&&Lt(e.ssContent),ssFallback:e.ssFallback&&Lt(e.ssFallback),placeholder:e.placeholder,el:e.el,anchor:e.anchor,ctx:e.ctx,ce:e.ce};return c&&i&&Bi(u,c.clone(u)),u}function $s(e=" ",t=0){return _e(Ko,null,e,t)}function Eo(e="",t=!1){return t?(ce(),To(gt,null,e)):_e(gt,null,e)}function Ue(e){return e==null||typeof e=="boolean"?_e(gt):k(e)?_e(je,null,e.slice()):Ro(e)?pt(e):_e(Ko,null,String(e))}function pt(e){return e.el===null&&e.patchFlag!==-1||e.memo?e:Lt(e)}function Wi(e,t){let o=0;const{shapeFlag:i}=e;if(t==null)t=null;else if(k(t))o=16;else if(typeof t=="object")if(i&65){const n=t.default;n&&(n._c&&(n._d=!1),Wi(e,n()),n._c&&(n._d=!0));return}else{o=32;const n=t._;!n&&!Hs(t)?t._ctx=xe:n===3&&xe&&(xe.slots._===1?t._=1:(t._=2,e.patchFlag|=1024))}else B(t)?(t={default:t,_ctx:xe},o=32):(t=String(t),i&64?(o=16,t=[$s(t)]):o=8);e.children=t,e.shapeFlag|=o}function Jc(...e){const t={};for(let o=0;o<e.length;o++){const i=e[o];for(const n in i)if(n==="class")t.class!==i.class&&(t.class=Bo([t.class,i.class]));else if(n==="style")t.style=Go([t.style,i.style]);else if(Do(n)){const s=t[n],r=i[n];r&&s!==r&&!(k(s)&&s.includes(r))&&(t[n]=s?[].concat(s,r):r)}else n!==""&&(t[n]=i[n])}return t}function Be(e,t,o,i=null){Ke(e,t,7,[o,i])}const Xc=Ts();let ea=0;function ta(e,t,o){const i=e.type,n=(t?t.appContext:e.appContext)||Xc,s={uid:ea++,vnode:e,type:i,parent:t,appContext:n,root:null,next:null,subTree:null,effect:null,update:null,job:null,scope:new jr(!0),render:null,proxy:null,exposed:null,exposeProxy:null,withProxy:null,provides:t?t.provides:Object.create(n.provides),ids:t?t.ids:["",0,0],accessCache:null,renderCache:[],components:null,directives:null,propsOptions:Bs(i,n),emitsOptions:Ds(i,n),emit:null,emitted:null,propsDefaults:Z,inheritAttrs:i.inheritAttrs,ctx:Z,data:Z,props:Z,attrs:Z,slots:Z,refs:Z,setupState:Z,setupContext:null,suspense:o,suspenseId:o?o.pendingId:0,asyncDep:null,asyncResolved:!1,isMounted:!1,isUnmounted:!1,isDeactivated:!1,bc:null,c:null,bm:null,m:null,bu:null,u:null,um:null,bum:null,da:null,a:null,rtg:null,rtc:null,ec:null,sp:null};return s.ctx={_:s},s.root=t?t.root:s,s.emit=Cc.bind(null,s),e.ce&&e.ce(s),s}let he=null;const oa=()=>he||xe;let No,Ei;{const e=Ho(),t=(o,i)=>{let n;return(n=e[o])||(n=e[o]=[]),n.push(i),s=>{n.length>1?n.forEach(r=>r(s)):n[0](s)}};No=t("__VUE_INSTANCE_SETTERS__",o=>he=o),Ei=t("__VUE_SSR_SETTERS__",o=>lo=o)}const go=e=>{const t=he;return No(e),e.scope.on(),()=>{e.scope.off(),No(t)}},mn=()=>{he&&he.scope.off(),No(null)};function Zs(e){return e.vnode.shapeFlag&4}let lo=!1;function ia(e,t=!1,o=!1){t&&Ei(t);const{props:i,children:n}=e.vnode,s=Zs(e);Lc(e,i,s,t),zc(e,n,o||t);const r=s?na(e,t):void 0;return t&&Ei(!1),r}function na(e,t){const o=e.type;e.accessCache=Object.create(null),e.proxy=new Proxy(e.ctx,Mc);const{setup:i}=o;if(i){tt();const n=e.setupContext=i.length>1?ra(e):null,s=go(e),r=ho(i,e,0,[e.props,n]),a=$n(r);if(ot(),s(),(a||e.sp)&&!Xt(e)&&js(e),a){if(r.then(mn,mn),t)return r.then(c=>{dn(e,c)}).catch(c=>{Fo(c,e,0)});e.asyncDep=r}else dn(e,r)}else Js(e)}function dn(e,t,o){B(t)?e.type.__ssrInlineRender?e.ssrRender=t:e.render=t:J(t)&&(e.setupState=Ms(t)),Js(e)}function Js(e,t,o){const i=e.type;e.render||(e.render=i.render||Fe);{const n=go(e);tt();try{Ec(e)}finally{ot(),n()}}}const sa={get(e,t){return le(e,"get",""),e[t]}};function ra(e){const t=o=>{e.exposed=o||{}};return{attrs:new Proxy(e.attrs,sa),slots:e.slots,emit:e.emit,expose:t}}function Yo(e){return e.exposed?e.exposeProxy||(e.exposeProxy=new Proxy(Ms(Kr(e.exposed)),{get(t,o){if(o in t)return t[o];if(o in eo)return eo[o](e)},has(t,o){return o in t||o in eo}})):e.proxy}function ca(e){return B(e)&&"__vccOpts"in e}const ae=(e,t)=>Jr(e,t,lo);function Xs(e,t,o){try{Co(-1);const i=arguments.length;return i===2?J(t)&&!k(t)?Ro(t)?_e(e,null,[t]):_e(e,t):_e(e,null,t):(i>3?o=Array.prototype.slice.call(arguments,2):i===3&&Ro(o)&&(o=[o]),_e(e,t,o))}finally{Co(1)}}const aa="3.5.25";let wi;const fn=typeof window<"u"&&window.trustedTypes;if(fn)try{wi=fn.createPolicy("vue",{createHTML:e=>e})}catch{}const er=wi?e=>wi.createHTML(e):e=>e,la="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg",ua="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML",Ze=typeof document<"u"?document:null,hn=Ze&&Ze.createElement("template"),pa={insert:(e,t,o)=>{t.insertBefore(e,o||null)},remove:e=>{const t=e.parentNode;t&&t.removeChild(e)},createElement:(e,t,o,i)=>{const n=t==="svg"?Ze.createElementNS(la,e):t==="mathml"?Ze.createElementNS(ua,e):o?Ze.createElement(e,{is:o}):Ze.createElement(e);return e==="select"&&i&&i.multiple!=null&&n.setAttribute("multiple",i.multiple),n},createText:e=>Ze.createTextNode(e),createComment:e=>Ze.createComment(e),setText:(e,t)=>{e.nodeValue=t},setElementText:(e,t)=>{e.textContent=t},parentNode:e=>e.parentNode,nextSibling:e=>e.nextSibling,querySelector:e=>Ze.querySelector(e),setScopeId(e,t){e.setAttribute(t,"")},insertStaticContent(e,t,o,i,n,s){const r=o?o.previousSibling:t.lastChild;if(n&&(n===s||n.nextSibling))for(;t.insertBefore(n.cloneNode(!0),o),!(n===s||!(n=n.nextSibling)););else{hn.innerHTML=er(i==="svg"?`<svg>${e}</svg>`:i==="mathml"?`<math>${e}</math>`:e);const a=hn.content;if(i==="svg"||i==="mathml"){const c=a.firstChild;for(;c.firstChild;)a.appendChild(c.firstChild);a.removeChild(c)}t.insertBefore(a,o)}return[r?r.nextSibling:t.firstChild,o?o.previousSibling:t.lastChild]}},ma=Symbol("_vtc");function da(e,t,o){const i=e[ma];i&&(t=(t?[t,...i]:[...i]).join(" ")),t==null?e.removeAttribute("class"):o?e.setAttribute("class",t):e.className=t}const gn=Symbol("_vod"),fa=Symbol("_vsh"),ha=Symbol(""),ga=/(?:^|;)\s*display\s*:/;function ya(e,t,o){const i=e.style,n=ie(o);let s=!1;if(o&&!n){if(t)if(ie(t))for(const r of t.split(";")){const a=r.slice(0,r.indexOf(":")).trim();o[a]==null&&_o(i,a,"")}else for(const r in t)o[r]==null&&_o(i,r,"");for(const r in o)r==="display"&&(s=!0),_o(i,r,o[r])}else if(n){if(t!==o){const r=i[ha];r&&(o+=";"+r),i.cssText=o,s=ga.test(o)}}else t&&e.removeAttribute("style");gn in e&&(e[gn]=s?i.display:"",e[fa]&&(i.display="none"))}const yn=/\s*!important$/;function _o(e,t,o){if(k(o))o.forEach(i=>_o(e,t,i));else if(o==null&&(o=""),t.startsWith("--"))e.setProperty(t,o);else{const i=ba(e,t);yn.test(o)?e.setProperty(St(i),o.replace(yn,""),"important"):e[i]=o}}const bn=["Webkit","Moz","ms"],si={};function ba(e,t){const o=si[t];if(o)return o;let i=ht(t);if(i!=="filter"&&i in e)return si[t]=i;i=Xn(i);for(let n=0;n<bn.length;n++){const s=bn[n]+i;if(s in e)return si[t]=s}return t}const vn="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink";function Mn(e,t,o,i,n,s=_r(t)){i&&t.startsWith("xlink:")?o==null?e.removeAttributeNS(vn,t.slice(6,t.length)):e.setAttributeNS(vn,t,o):o==null||s&&!ts(o)?e.removeAttribute(t):e.setAttribute(t,s?"":Ve(o)?String(o):o)}function En(e,t,o,i,n){if(t==="innerHTML"||t==="textContent"){o!=null&&(e[t]=t==="innerHTML"?er(o):o);return}const s=e.tagName;if(t==="value"&&s!=="PROGRESS"&&!s.includes("-")){const a=s==="OPTION"?e.getAttribute("value")||"":e.value,c=o==null?e.type==="checkbox"?"on":"":String(o);(a!==c||!("_value"in e))&&(e.value=c),o==null&&e.removeAttribute(t),e._value=o;return}let r=!1;if(o===""||o==null){const a=typeof e[t];a==="boolean"?o=ts(o):o==null&&a==="string"?(o="",r=!0):a==="number"&&(o=0,r=!0)}try{e[t]=o}catch{}r&&e.removeAttribute(n||t)}function dt(e,t,o,i){e.addEventListener(t,o,i)}function va(e,t,o,i){e.removeEventListener(t,o,i)}const wn=Symbol("_vei");function Ma(e,t,o,i,n=null){const s=e[wn]||(e[wn]={}),r=s[t];if(i&&r)r.value=i;else{const[a,c]=Ea(t);if(i){const m=s[t]=Oa(i,n);dt(e,a,m,c)}else r&&(va(e,a,r,c),s[t]=void 0)}}const qn=/(?:Once|Passive|Capture)$/;function Ea(e){let t;if(qn.test(e)){t={};let i;for(;i=e.match(qn);)e=e.slice(0,e.length-i[0].length),t[i[0].toLowerCase()]=!0}return[e[2]===":"?e.slice(3):St(e.slice(2)),t]}let ri=0;const wa=Promise.resolve(),qa=()=>ri||(wa.then(()=>ri=0),ri=Date.now());function Oa(e,t){const o=i=>{if(!i._vts)i._vts=Date.now();else if(i._vts<=o.attached)return;Ke(_a(i,o.value),t,5,[i])};return o.value=e,o.attached=qa(),o}function _a(e,t){if(k(t)){const o=e.stopImmediatePropagation;return e.stopImmediatePropagation=()=>{o.call(e),e._stopped=!0},t.map(i=>n=>!n._stopped&&i&&i(n))}else return t}const On=e=>e.charCodeAt(0)===111&&e.charCodeAt(1)===110&&e.charCodeAt(2)>96&&e.charCodeAt(2)<123,Sa=(e,t,o,i,n,s)=>{const r=n==="svg";t==="class"?da(e,i,r):t==="style"?ya(e,o,i):Do(t)?xi(t)||Ma(e,t,o,i,s):(t[0]==="."?(t=t.slice(1),!0):t[0]==="^"?(t=t.slice(1),!1):ja(e,t,i,r))?(En(e,t,i),!e.tagName.includes("-")&&(t==="value"||t==="checked"||t==="selected")&&Mn(e,t,i,r,s,t!=="value")):e._isVueCE&&(/[A-Z]/.test(t)||!ie(i))?En(e,ht(t),i,s,t):(t==="true-value"?e._trueValue=i:t==="false-value"&&(e._falseValue=i),Mn(e,t,i,r))};function ja(e,t,o,i){if(i)return!!(t==="innerHTML"||t==="textContent"||t in e&&On(t)&&B(o));if(t==="spellcheck"||t==="draggable"||t==="translate"||t==="autocorrect"||t==="sandbox"&&e.tagName==="IFRAME"||t==="form"||t==="list"&&e.tagName==="INPUT"||t==="type"&&e.tagName==="TEXTAREA")return!1;if(t==="width"||t==="height"){const n=e.tagName;if(n==="IMG"||n==="VIDEO"||n==="CANVAS"||n==="SOURCE")return!1}return On(t)&&ie(o)?!1:t in e}const Ht=e=>{const t=e.props["onUpdate:modelValue"]||!1;return k(t)?o=>wo(t,o):t};function xa(e){e.target.composing=!0}function _n(e){const t=e.target;t.composing&&(t.composing=!1,t.dispatchEvent(new Event("input")))}const et=Symbol("_assign");function Sn(e,t,o){return t&&(e=e.trim()),o&&(e=Lo(e)),e}const Pa={created(e,{modifiers:{lazy:t,trim:o,number:i}},n){e[et]=Ht(n);const s=i||n.props&&n.props.type==="number";dt(e,t?"change":"input",r=>{r.target.composing||e[et](Sn(e.value,o,s))}),(o||s)&&dt(e,"change",()=>{e.value=Sn(e.value,o,s)}),t||(dt(e,"compositionstart",xa),dt(e,"compositionend",_n),dt(e,"change",_n))},mounted(e,{value:t}){e.value=t??""},beforeUpdate(e,{value:t,oldValue:o,modifiers:{lazy:i,trim:n,number:s}},r){if(e[et]=Ht(r),e.composing)return;const a=(s||e.type==="number")&&!/^0\d/.test(e.value)?Lo(e.value):e.value,c=t??"";a!==c&&(document.activeElement===e&&e.type!=="range"&&(i&&t===o||n&&e.value.trim()===c)||(e.value=c))}},Aa={deep:!0,created(e,t,o){e[et]=Ht(o),dt(e,"change",()=>{const i=e._modelValue,n=uo(e),s=e.checked,r=e[et];if(k(i)){const a=Ii(i,n),c=a!==-1;if(s&&!c)r(i.concat(n));else if(!s&&c){const m=[...i];m.splice(a,1),r(m)}}else if(zt(i)){const a=new Set(i);s?a.add(n):a.delete(n),r(a)}else r(tr(e,s))})},mounted:jn,beforeUpdate(e,t,o){e[et]=Ht(o),jn(e,t,o)}};function jn(e,{value:t,oldValue:o},i){e._modelValue=t;let n;if(k(t))n=Ii(t,i.props.value)>-1;else if(zt(t))n=t.has(i.props.value);else{if(t===o)return;n=fo(t,tr(e,!0))}e.checked!==n&&(e.checked=n)}const xn={deep:!0,created(e,{value:t,modifiers:{number:o}},i){const n=zt(t);dt(e,"change",()=>{const s=Array.prototype.filter.call(e.options,r=>r.selected).map(r=>o?Lo(uo(r)):uo(r));e[et](e.multiple?n?new Set(s):s:s[0]),e._assigning=!0,Hi(()=>{e._assigning=!1})}),e[et]=Ht(i)},mounted(e,{value:t}){Pn(e,t)},beforeUpdate(e,t,o){e[et]=Ht(o)},updated(e,{value:t}){e._assigning||Pn(e,t)}};function Pn(e,t){const o=e.multiple,i=k(t);if(!(o&&!i&&!zt(t))){for(let n=0,s=e.options.length;n<s;n++){const r=e.options[n],a=uo(r);if(o)if(i){const c=typeof a;c==="string"||c==="number"?r.selected=t.some(m=>String(m)===String(a)):r.selected=Ii(t,a)>-1}else r.selected=t.has(a);else if(fo(uo(r),t)){e.selectedIndex!==n&&(e.selectedIndex=n);return}}!o&&e.selectedIndex!==-1&&(e.selectedIndex=-1)}}function uo(e){return"_value"in e?e._value:e.value}function tr(e,t){const o=t?"_trueValue":"_falseValue";return o in e?e[o]:t}const Ia=pe({patchProp:Sa},pa);let An;function Ca(){return An||(An=Fc(Ia))}const Ta=((...e)=>{const t=Ca().createApp(...e),{mount:o}=t;return t.mount=i=>{const n=Na(i);if(!n)return;const s=t._component;!B(s)&&!s.render&&!s.template&&(s.template=n.innerHTML),n.nodeType===1&&(n.textContent="");const r=o(n,!1,Ra(n));return n instanceof Element&&(n.removeAttribute("v-cloak"),n.setAttribute("data-v-app","")),r},t});function Ra(e){if(e instanceof SVGElement)return"svg";if(typeof MathMLElement=="function"&&e instanceof MathMLElement)return"mathml"}function Na(e){return ie(e)?document.querySelector(e):e}const Ct=typeof document<"u";function or(e){return typeof e=="object"||"displayName"in e||"props"in e||"__vccOpts"in e}function Da(e){return e.__esModule||e[Symbol.toStringTag]==="Module"||e.default&&or(e.default)}const W=Object.assign;function ci(e,t){const o={};for(const i in t){const n=t[i];o[i]=Te(n)?n.map(e):e(n)}return o}const io=()=>{},Te=Array.isArray;function In(e,t){const o={};for(const i in e)o[i]=i in t?t[i]:e[i];return o}const ir=/#/g,ka=/&/g,La=/\//g,Ha=/=/g,Ga=/\?/g,nr=/\+/g,Ba=/%5B/g,za=/%5D/g,sr=/%5E/g,Ua=/%60/g,rr=/%7B/g,Fa=/%7C/g,cr=/%7D/g,Wa=/%20/g;function Vi(e){return e==null?"":encodeURI(""+e).replace(Fa,"|").replace(Ba,"[").replace(za,"]")}function Va(e){return Vi(e).replace(rr,"{").replace(cr,"}").replace(sr,"^")}function qi(e){return Vi(e).replace(nr,"%2B").replace(Wa,"+").replace(ir,"%23").replace(ka,"%26").replace(Ua,"`").replace(rr,"{").replace(cr,"}").replace(sr,"^")}function Ka(e){return qi(e).replace(Ha,"%3D")}function Ya(e){return Vi(e).replace(ir,"%23").replace(Ga,"%3F")}function Qa(e){return Ya(e).replace(La,"%2F")}function po(e){if(e==null)return null;try{return decodeURIComponent(""+e)}catch{}return""+e}const $a=/\/$/,Za=e=>e.replace($a,"");function ai(e,t,o="/"){let i,n={},s="",r="";const a=t.indexOf("#");let c=t.indexOf("?");return c=a>=0&&c>a?-1:c,c>=0&&(i=t.slice(0,c),s=t.slice(c,a>0?a:t.length),n=e(s.slice(1))),a>=0&&(i=i||t.slice(0,a),r=t.slice(a,t.length)),i=tl(i??t,o),{fullPath:i+s+r,path:i,query:n,hash:po(r)}}function Ja(e,t){const o=t.query?e(t.query):"";return t.path+(o&&"?")+o+(t.hash||"")}function Cn(e,t){return!t||!e.toLowerCase().startsWith(t.toLowerCase())?e:e.slice(t.length)||"/"}function Xa(e,t,o){const i=t.matched.length-1,n=o.matched.length-1;return i>-1&&i===n&&Gt(t.matched[i],o.matched[n])&&ar(t.params,o.params)&&e(t.query)===e(o.query)&&t.hash===o.hash}function Gt(e,t){return(e.aliasOf||e)===(t.aliasOf||t)}function ar(e,t){if(Object.keys(e).length!==Object.keys(t).length)return!1;for(const o in e)if(!el(e[o],t[o]))return!1;return!0}function el(e,t){return Te(e)?Tn(e,t):Te(t)?Tn(t,e):e===t}function Tn(e,t){return Te(t)?e.length===t.length&&e.every((o,i)=>o===t[i]):e.length===1&&e[0]===t}function tl(e,t){if(e.startsWith("/"))return e;if(!e)return t;const o=t.split("/"),i=e.split("/"),n=i[i.length-1];(n===".."||n===".")&&i.push("");let s=o.length-1,r,a;for(r=0;r<i.length;r++)if(a=i[r],a!==".")if(a==="..")s>1&&s--;else break;return o.slice(0,s).join("/")+"/"+i.slice(r).join("/")}const at={path:"/",name:void 0,params:{},query:{},hash:"",fullPath:"/",matched:[],meta:{},redirectedFrom:void 0};let Oi=(function(e){return e.pop="pop",e.push="push",e})({}),li=(function(e){return e.back="back",e.forward="forward",e.unknown="",e})({});function ol(e){if(!e)if(Ct){const t=document.querySelector("base");e=t&&t.getAttribute("href")||"/",e=e.replace(/^\w+:\/\/[^\/]+/,"")}else e="/";return e[0]!=="/"&&e[0]!=="#"&&(e="/"+e),Za(e)}const il=/^[^#]+#/;function nl(e,t){return e.replace(il,"#")+t}function sl(e,t){const o=document.documentElement.getBoundingClientRect(),i=e.getBoundingClientRect();return{behavior:t.behavior,left:i.left-o.left-(t.left||0),top:i.top-o.top-(t.top||0)}}const Qo=()=>({left:window.scrollX,top:window.scrollY});function rl(e){let t;if("el"in e){const o=e.el,i=typeof o=="string"&&o.startsWith("#"),n=typeof o=="string"?i?document.getElementById(o.slice(1)):document.querySelector(o):o;if(!n)return;t=sl(n,e)}else t=e;"scrollBehavior"in document.documentElement.style?window.scrollTo(t):window.scrollTo(t.left!=null?t.left:window.scrollX,t.top!=null?t.top:window.scrollY)}function Rn(e,t){return(history.state?history.state.position-t:-1)+e}const _i=new Map;function cl(e,t){_i.set(e,t)}function al(e){const t=_i.get(e);return _i.delete(e),t}function ll(e){return typeof e=="string"||e&&typeof e=="object"}function lr(e){return typeof e=="string"||typeof e=="symbol"}let oe=(function(e){return e[e.MATCHER_NOT_FOUND=1]="MATCHER_NOT_FOUND",e[e.NAVIGATION_GUARD_REDIRECT=2]="NAVIGATION_GUARD_REDIRECT",e[e.NAVIGATION_ABORTED=4]="NAVIGATION_ABORTED",e[e.NAVIGATION_CANCELLED=8]="NAVIGATION_CANCELLED",e[e.NAVIGATION_DUPLICATED=16]="NAVIGATION_DUPLICATED",e})({});const ur=Symbol("");oe.MATCHER_NOT_FOUND+"",oe.NAVIGATION_GUARD_REDIRECT+"",oe.NAVIGATION_ABORTED+"",oe.NAVIGATION_CANCELLED+"",oe.NAVIGATION_DUPLICATED+"";function Bt(e,t){return W(new Error,{type:e,[ur]:!0},t)}function $e(e,t){return e instanceof Error&&ur in e&&(t==null||!!(e.type&t))}const ul=["params","query","hash"];function pl(e){if(typeof e=="string")return e;if(e.path!=null)return e.path;const t={};for(const o of ul)o in e&&(t[o]=e[o]);return JSON.stringify(t,null,2)}function ml(e){const t={};if(e===""||e==="?")return t;const o=(e[0]==="?"?e.slice(1):e).split("&");for(let i=0;i<o.length;++i){const n=o[i].replace(nr," "),s=n.indexOf("="),r=po(s<0?n:n.slice(0,s)),a=s<0?null:po(n.slice(s+1));if(r in t){let c=t[r];Te(c)||(c=t[r]=[c]),c.push(a)}else t[r]=a}return t}function Nn(e){let t="";for(let o in e){const i=e[o];if(o=Ka(o),i==null){i!==void 0&&(t+=(t.length?"&":"")+o);continue}(Te(i)?i.map(n=>n&&qi(n)):[i&&qi(i)]).forEach(n=>{n!==void 0&&(t+=(t.length?"&":"")+o,n!=null&&(t+="="+n))})}return t}function dl(e){const t={};for(const o in e){const i=e[o];i!==void 0&&(t[o]=Te(i)?i.map(n=>n==null?null:""+n):i==null?i:""+i)}return t}const fl=Symbol(""),Dn=Symbol(""),$o=Symbol(""),pr=Symbol(""),Si=Symbol("");function Kt(){let e=[];function t(i){return e.push(i),()=>{const n=e.indexOf(i);n>-1&&e.splice(n,1)}}function o(){e=[]}return{add:t,list:()=>e.slice(),reset:o}}function mt(e,t,o,i,n,s=r=>r()){const r=i&&(i.enterCallbacks[n]=i.enterCallbacks[n]||[]);return()=>new Promise((a,c)=>{const m=g=>{g===!1?c(Bt(oe.NAVIGATION_ABORTED,{from:o,to:t})):g instanceof Error?c(g):ll(g)?c(Bt(oe.NAVIGATION_GUARD_REDIRECT,{from:t,to:g})):(r&&i.enterCallbacks[n]===r&&typeof g=="function"&&r.push(g),a())},u=s(()=>e.call(i&&i.instances[n],t,o,m));let d=Promise.resolve(u);e.length<3&&(d=d.then(m)),d.catch(g=>c(g))})}function ui(e,t,o,i,n=s=>s()){const s=[];for(const r of e)for(const a in r.components){let c=r.components[a];if(!(t!=="beforeRouteEnter"&&!r.instances[a]))if(or(c)){const m=(c.__vccOpts||c)[t];m&&s.push(mt(m,o,i,r,a,n))}else{let m=c();s.push(()=>m.then(u=>{if(!u)throw new Error(`Couldn't resolve component "${a}" at "${r.path}"`);const d=Da(u)?u.default:u;r.mods[a]=u,r.components[a]=d;const g=(d.__vccOpts||d)[t];return g&&mt(g,o,i,r,a,n)()}))}}return s}function hl(e,t){const o=[],i=[],n=[],s=Math.max(t.matched.length,e.matched.length);for(let r=0;r<s;r++){const a=t.matched[r];a&&(e.matched.find(m=>Gt(m,a))?i.push(a):o.push(a));const c=e.matched[r];c&&(t.matched.find(m=>Gt(m,c))||n.push(c))}return[o,i,n]}let gl=()=>location.protocol+"//"+location.host;function mr(e,t){const{pathname:o,search:i,hash:n}=t,s=e.indexOf("#");if(s>-1){let r=n.includes(e.slice(s))?e.slice(s).length:1,a=n.slice(r);return a[0]!=="/"&&(a="/"+a),Cn(a,"")}return Cn(o,e)+i+n}function yl(e,t,o,i){let n=[],s=[],r=null;const a=({state:g})=>{const h=mr(e,location),M=o.value,_=t.value;let G=0;if(g){if(o.value=h,t.value=g,r&&r===M){r=null;return}G=_?g.position-_.position:0}else i(h);n.forEach(C=>{C(o.value,M,{delta:G,type:Oi.pop,direction:G?G>0?li.forward:li.back:li.unknown})})};function c(){r=o.value}function m(g){n.push(g);const h=()=>{const M=n.indexOf(g);M>-1&&n.splice(M,1)};return s.push(h),h}function u(){if(document.visibilityState==="hidden"){const{history:g}=window;if(!g.state)return;g.replaceState(W({},g.state,{scroll:Qo()}),"")}}function d(){for(const g of s)g();s=[],window.removeEventListener("popstate",a),window.removeEventListener("pagehide",u),document.removeEventListener("visibilitychange",u)}return window.addEventListener("popstate",a),window.addEventListener("pagehide",u),document.addEventListener("visibilitychange",u),{pauseListeners:c,listen:m,destroy:d}}function kn(e,t,o,i=!1,n=!1){return{back:e,current:t,forward:o,replaced:i,position:window.history.length,scroll:n?Qo():null}}function bl(e){const{history:t,location:o}=window,i={value:mr(e,o)},n={value:t.state};n.value||s(i.value,{back:null,current:i.value,forward:null,position:t.length-1,replaced:!0,scroll:null},!0);function s(c,m,u){const d=e.indexOf("#"),g=d>-1?(o.host&&document.querySelector("base")?e:e.slice(d))+c:gl()+e+c;try{t[u?"replaceState":"pushState"](m,"",g),n.value=m}catch(h){console.error(h),o[u?"replace":"assign"](g)}}function r(c,m){s(c,W({},t.state,kn(n.value.back,c,n.value.forward,!0),m,{position:n.value.position}),!0),i.value=c}function a(c,m){const u=W({},n.value,t.state,{forward:c,scroll:Qo()});s(u.current,u,!0),s(c,W({},kn(i.value,c,null),{position:u.position+1},m),!1),i.value=c}return{location:i,state:n,push:a,replace:r}}function vl(e){e=ol(e);const t=bl(e),o=yl(e,t.state,t.location,t.replace);function i(s,r=!0){r||o.pauseListeners(),history.go(s)}const n=W({location:"",base:e,go:i,createHref:nl.bind(null,e)},t,o);return Object.defineProperty(n,"location",{enumerable:!0,get:()=>t.location.value}),Object.defineProperty(n,"state",{enumerable:!0,get:()=>t.state.value}),n}function Ml(e){return e=location.host?e||location.pathname+location.search:"",e.includes("#")||(e+="#"),vl(e)}let wt=(function(e){return e[e.Static=0]="Static",e[e.Param=1]="Param",e[e.Group=2]="Group",e})({});var ne=(function(e){return e[e.Static=0]="Static",e[e.Param=1]="Param",e[e.ParamRegExp=2]="ParamRegExp",e[e.ParamRegExpEnd=3]="ParamRegExpEnd",e[e.EscapeNext=4]="EscapeNext",e})(ne||{});const El={type:wt.Static,value:""},wl=/[a-zA-Z0-9_]/;function ql(e){if(!e)return[[]];if(e==="/")return[[El]];if(!e.startsWith("/"))throw new Error(`Invalid path "${e}"`);function t(h){throw new Error(`ERR (${o})/"${m}": ${h}`)}let o=ne.Static,i=o;const n=[];let s;function r(){s&&n.push(s),s=[]}let a=0,c,m="",u="";function d(){m&&(o===ne.Static?s.push({type:wt.Static,value:m}):o===ne.Param||o===ne.ParamRegExp||o===ne.ParamRegExpEnd?(s.length>1&&(c==="*"||c==="+")&&t(`A repeatable param (${m}) must be alone in its segment. eg: '/:ids+.`),s.push({type:wt.Param,value:m,regexp:u,repeatable:c==="*"||c==="+",optional:c==="*"||c==="?"})):t("Invalid state to consume buffer"),m="")}function g(){m+=c}for(;a<e.length;){if(c=e[a++],c==="\\"&&o!==ne.ParamRegExp){i=o,o=ne.EscapeNext;continue}switch(o){case ne.Static:c==="/"?(m&&d(),r()):c===":"?(d(),o=ne.Param):g();break;case ne.EscapeNext:g(),o=i;break;case ne.Param:c==="("?o=ne.ParamRegExp:wl.test(c)?g():(d(),o=ne.Static,c!=="*"&&c!=="?"&&c!=="+"&&a--);break;case ne.ParamRegExp:c===")"?u[u.length-1]=="\\"?u=u.slice(0,-1)+c:o=ne.ParamRegExpEnd:u+=c;break;case ne.ParamRegExpEnd:d(),o=ne.Static,c!=="*"&&c!=="?"&&c!=="+"&&a--,u="";break;default:t("Unknown state");break}}return o===ne.ParamRegExp&&t(`Unfinished custom RegExp for param "${m}"`),d(),r(),n}const Ln="[^/]+?",Ol={sensitive:!1,strict:!1,start:!0,end:!0};var de=(function(e){return e[e._multiplier=10]="_multiplier",e[e.Root=90]="Root",e[e.Segment=40]="Segment",e[e.SubSegment=30]="SubSegment",e[e.Static=40]="Static",e[e.Dynamic=20]="Dynamic",e[e.BonusCustomRegExp=10]="BonusCustomRegExp",e[e.BonusWildcard=-50]="BonusWildcard",e[e.BonusRepeatable=-20]="BonusRepeatable",e[e.BonusOptional=-8]="BonusOptional",e[e.BonusStrict=.7000000000000001]="BonusStrict",e[e.BonusCaseSensitive=.25]="BonusCaseSensitive",e})(de||{});const _l=/[.+*?^${}()[\]/\\]/g;function Sl(e,t){const o=W({},Ol,t),i=[];let n=o.start?"^":"";const s=[];for(const m of e){const u=m.length?[]:[de.Root];o.strict&&!m.length&&(n+="/");for(let d=0;d<m.length;d++){const g=m[d];let h=de.Segment+(o.sensitive?de.BonusCaseSensitive:0);if(g.type===wt.Static)d||(n+="/"),n+=g.value.replace(_l,"\\$&"),h+=de.Static;else if(g.type===wt.Param){const{value:M,repeatable:_,optional:G,regexp:C}=g;s.push({name:M,repeatable:_,optional:G});const A=C||Ln;if(A!==Ln){h+=de.BonusCustomRegExp;try{`${A}`}catch(I){throw new Error(`Invalid custom RegExp for param "${M}" (${A}): `+I.message)}}let N=_?`((?:${A})(?:/(?:${A}))*)`:`(${A})`;d||(N=G&&m.length<2?`(?:/${N})`:"/"+N),G&&(N+="?"),n+=N,h+=de.Dynamic,G&&(h+=de.BonusOptional),_&&(h+=de.BonusRepeatable),A===".*"&&(h+=de.BonusWildcard)}u.push(h)}i.push(u)}if(o.strict&&o.end){const m=i.length-1;i[m][i[m].length-1]+=de.BonusStrict}o.strict||(n+="/?"),o.end?n+="$":o.strict&&!n.endsWith("/")&&(n+="(?:/|$)");const r=new RegExp(n,o.sensitive?"":"i");function a(m){const u=m.match(r),d={};if(!u)return null;for(let g=1;g<u.length;g++){const h=u[g]||"",M=s[g-1];d[M.name]=h&&M.repeatable?h.split("/"):h}return d}function c(m){let u="",d=!1;for(const g of e){(!d||!u.endsWith("/"))&&(u+="/"),d=!1;for(const h of g)if(h.type===wt.Static)u+=h.value;else if(h.type===wt.Param){const{value:M,repeatable:_,optional:G}=h,C=M in m?m[M]:"";if(Te(C)&&!_)throw new Error(`Provided param "${M}" is an array but it is not repeatable (* or + modifiers)`);const A=Te(C)?C.join("/"):C;if(!A)if(G)g.length<2&&(u.endsWith("/")?u=u.slice(0,-1):d=!0);else throw new Error(`Missing required param "${M}"`);u+=A}}return u||"/"}return{re:r,score:i,keys:s,parse:a,stringify:c}}function jl(e,t){let o=0;for(;o<e.length&&o<t.length;){const i=t[o]-e[o];if(i)return i;o++}return e.length<t.length?e.length===1&&e[0]===de.Static+de.Segment?-1:1:e.length>t.length?t.length===1&&t[0]===de.Static+de.Segment?1:-1:0}function dr(e,t){let o=0;const i=e.score,n=t.score;for(;o<i.length&&o<n.length;){const s=jl(i[o],n[o]);if(s)return s;o++}if(Math.abs(n.length-i.length)===1){if(Hn(i))return 1;if(Hn(n))return-1}return n.length-i.length}function Hn(e){const t=e[e.length-1];return e.length>0&&t[t.length-1]<0}const xl={strict:!1,end:!0,sensitive:!1};function Pl(e,t,o){const i=Sl(ql(e.path),o),n=W(i,{record:e,parent:t,children:[],alias:[]});return t&&!n.record.aliasOf==!t.record.aliasOf&&t.children.push(n),n}function Al(e,t){const o=[],i=new Map;t=In(xl,t);function n(d){return i.get(d)}function s(d,g,h){const M=!h,_=Bn(d);_.aliasOf=h&&h.record;const G=In(t,d),C=[_];if("alias"in d){const I=typeof d.alias=="string"?[d.alias]:d.alias;for(const $ of I)C.push(Bn(W({},_,{components:h?h.record.components:_.components,path:$,aliasOf:h?h.record:_})))}let A,N;for(const I of C){const{path:$}=I;if(g&&$[0]!=="/"){const re=g.record.path,te=re[re.length-1]==="/"?"":"/";I.path=g.record.path+($&&te+$)}if(A=Pl(I,g,G),h?h.alias.push(A):(N=N||A,N!==A&&N.alias.push(A),M&&d.name&&!zn(A)&&r(d.name)),fr(A)&&c(A),_.children){const re=_.children;for(let te=0;te<re.length;te++)s(re[te],A,h&&h.children[te])}h=h||A}return N?()=>{r(N)}:io}function r(d){if(lr(d)){const g=i.get(d);g&&(i.delete(d),o.splice(o.indexOf(g),1),g.children.forEach(r),g.alias.forEach(r))}else{const g=o.indexOf(d);g>-1&&(o.splice(g,1),d.record.name&&i.delete(d.record.name),d.children.forEach(r),d.alias.forEach(r))}}function a(){return o}function c(d){const g=Tl(d,o);o.splice(g,0,d),d.record.name&&!zn(d)&&i.set(d.record.name,d)}function m(d,g){let h,M={},_,G;if("name"in d&&d.name){if(h=i.get(d.name),!h)throw Bt(oe.MATCHER_NOT_FOUND,{location:d});G=h.record.name,M=W(Gn(g.params,h.keys.filter(N=>!N.optional).concat(h.parent?h.parent.keys.filter(N=>N.optional):[]).map(N=>N.name)),d.params&&Gn(d.params,h.keys.map(N=>N.name))),_=h.stringify(M)}else if(d.path!=null)_=d.path,h=o.find(N=>N.re.test(_)),h&&(M=h.parse(_),G=h.record.name);else{if(h=g.name?i.get(g.name):o.find(N=>N.re.test(g.path)),!h)throw Bt(oe.MATCHER_NOT_FOUND,{location:d,currentLocation:g});G=h.record.name,M=W({},g.params,d.params),_=h.stringify(M)}const C=[];let A=h;for(;A;)C.unshift(A.record),A=A.parent;return{name:G,path:_,params:M,matched:C,meta:Cl(C)}}e.forEach(d=>s(d));function u(){o.length=0,i.clear()}return{addRoute:s,resolve:m,removeRoute:r,clearRoutes:u,getRoutes:a,getRecordMatcher:n}}function Gn(e,t){const o={};for(const i of t)i in e&&(o[i]=e[i]);return o}function Bn(e){const t={path:e.path,redirect:e.redirect,name:e.name,meta:e.meta||{},aliasOf:e.aliasOf,beforeEnter:e.beforeEnter,props:Il(e),children:e.children||[],instances:{},leaveGuards:new Set,updateGuards:new Set,enterCallbacks:{},components:"components"in e?e.components||null:e.component&&{default:e.component}};return Object.defineProperty(t,"mods",{value:{}}),t}function Il(e){const t={},o=e.props||!1;if("component"in e)t.default=o;else for(const i in e.components)t[i]=typeof o=="object"?o[i]:o;return t}function zn(e){for(;e;){if(e.record.aliasOf)return!0;e=e.parent}return!1}function Cl(e){return e.reduce((t,o)=>W(t,o.meta),{})}function Tl(e,t){let o=0,i=t.length;for(;o!==i;){const s=o+i>>1;dr(e,t[s])<0?i=s:o=s+1}const n=Rl(e);return n&&(i=t.lastIndexOf(n,i-1)),i}function Rl(e){let t=e;for(;t=t.parent;)if(fr(t)&&dr(e,t)===0)return t}function fr({record:e}){return!!(e.name||e.components&&Object.keys(e.components).length||e.redirect)}function Un(e){const t=We($o),o=We(pr),i=ae(()=>{const c=_t(e.to);return t.resolve(c)}),n=ae(()=>{const{matched:c}=i.value,{length:m}=c,u=c[m-1],d=o.matched;if(!u||!d.length)return-1;const g=d.findIndex(Gt.bind(null,u));if(g>-1)return g;const h=Fn(c[m-2]);return m>1&&Fn(u)===h&&d[d.length-1].path!==h?d.findIndex(Gt.bind(null,c[m-2])):g}),s=ae(()=>n.value>-1&&Hl(o.params,i.value.params)),r=ae(()=>n.value>-1&&n.value===o.matched.length-1&&ar(o.params,i.value.params));function a(c={}){if(Ll(c)){const m=t[_t(e.replace)?"replace":"push"](_t(e.to)).catch(io);return e.viewTransition&&typeof document<"u"&&"startViewTransition"in document&&document.startViewTransition(()=>m),m}return Promise.resolve()}return{route:i,href:ae(()=>i.value.href),isActive:s,isExactActive:r,navigate:a}}function Nl(e){return e.length===1?e[0]:e}const Dl=Ss({name:"RouterLink",compatConfig:{MODE:3},props:{to:{type:[String,Object],required:!0},replace:Boolean,activeClass:String,exactActiveClass:String,custom:Boolean,ariaCurrentValue:{type:String,default:"page"},viewTransition:Boolean},useLink:Un,setup(e,{slots:t}){const o=Uo(Un(e)),{options:i}=We($o),n=ae(()=>({[Wn(e.activeClass,i.linkActiveClass,"router-link-active")]:o.isActive,[Wn(e.exactActiveClass,i.linkExactActiveClass,"router-link-exact-active")]:o.isExactActive}));return()=>{const s=t.default&&Nl(t.default(o));return e.custom?s:Xs("a",{"aria-current":o.isExactActive?e.ariaCurrentValue:null,href:o.href,onClick:o.navigate,class:n.value},s)}}}),kl=Dl;function Ll(e){if(!(e.metaKey||e.altKey||e.ctrlKey||e.shiftKey)&&!e.defaultPrevented&&!(e.button!==void 0&&e.button!==0)){if(e.currentTarget&&e.currentTarget.getAttribute){const t=e.currentTarget.getAttribute("target");if(/\b_blank\b/i.test(t))return}return e.preventDefault&&e.preventDefault(),!0}}function Hl(e,t){for(const o in t){const i=t[o],n=e[o];if(typeof i=="string"){if(i!==n)return!1}else if(!Te(n)||n.length!==i.length||i.some((s,r)=>s!==n[r]))return!1}return!0}function Fn(e){return e?e.aliasOf?e.aliasOf.path:e.path:""}const Wn=(e,t,o)=>e??t??o,Gl=Ss({name:"RouterView",inheritAttrs:!1,props:{name:{type:String,default:"default"},route:Object},compatConfig:{MODE:3},setup(e,{attrs:t,slots:o}){const i=We(Si),n=ae(()=>e.route||i.value),s=We(Dn,0),r=ae(()=>{let m=_t(s);const{matched:u}=n.value;let d;for(;(d=u[m])&&!d.components;)m++;return m}),a=ae(()=>n.value.matched[r.value]);qo(Dn,ae(()=>r.value+1)),qo(fl,a),qo(Si,n);const c=Ae();return to(()=>[c.value,a.value,e.name],([m,u,d],[g,h,M])=>{u&&(u.instances[d]=m,h&&h!==u&&m&&m===g&&(u.leaveGuards.size||(u.leaveGuards=h.leaveGuards),u.updateGuards.size||(u.updateGuards=h.updateGuards))),m&&u&&(!h||!Gt(u,h)||!g)&&(u.enterCallbacks[d]||[]).forEach(_=>_(m))},{flush:"post"}),()=>{const m=n.value,u=e.name,d=a.value,g=d&&d.components[u];if(!g)return Vn(o.default,{Component:g,route:m});const h=d.props[u],M=h?h===!0?m.params:typeof h=="function"?h(m):h:null,G=Xs(g,W({},M,t,{onVnodeUnmounted:C=>{C.component.isUnmounted&&(d.instances[u]=null)},ref:c}));return Vn(o.default,{Component:G,route:m})||G}}});function Vn(e,t){if(!e)return null;const o=e(t);return o.length===1?o[0]:o}const hr=Gl;function Bl(e){const t=Al(e.routes,e),o=e.parseQuery||ml,i=e.stringifyQuery||Nn,n=e.history,s=Kt(),r=Kt(),a=Kt(),c=Yr(at);let m=at;Ct&&e.scrollBehavior&&"scrollRestoration"in history&&(history.scrollRestoration="manual");const u=ci.bind(null,v=>""+v),d=ci.bind(null,Qa),g=ci.bind(null,po);function h(v,P){let j,T;return lr(v)?(j=t.getRecordMatcher(v),T=P):T=v,t.addRoute(T,j)}function M(v){const P=t.getRecordMatcher(v);P&&t.removeRoute(P)}function _(){return t.getRoutes().map(v=>v.record)}function G(v){return!!t.getRecordMatcher(v)}function C(v,P){if(P=W({},P||c.value),typeof v=="string"){const f=ai(o,v,P.path),b=t.resolve({path:f.path},P),E=n.createHref(f.fullPath);return W(f,b,{params:g(b.params),hash:po(f.hash),redirectedFrom:void 0,href:E})}let j;if(v.path!=null)j=W({},v,{path:ai(o,v.path,P.path).path});else{const f=W({},v.params);for(const b in f)f[b]==null&&delete f[b];j=W({},v,{params:d(f)}),P.params=d(P.params)}const T=t.resolve(j,P),z=v.hash||"";T.params=u(g(T.params));const l=Ja(i,W({},v,{hash:Va(z),path:T.path})),p=n.createHref(l);return W({fullPath:l,hash:z,query:i===Nn?dl(v.query):v.query||{}},T,{redirectedFrom:void 0,href:p})}function A(v){return typeof v=="string"?ai(o,v,c.value.path):W({},v)}function N(v,P){if(m!==v)return Bt(oe.NAVIGATION_CANCELLED,{from:P,to:v})}function I(v){return te(v)}function $(v){return I(W(A(v),{replace:!0}))}function re(v,P){const j=v.matched[v.matched.length-1];if(j&&j.redirect){const{redirect:T}=j;let z=typeof T=="function"?T(v,P):T;return typeof z=="string"&&(z=z.includes("?")||z.includes("#")?z=A(z):{path:z},z.params={}),W({query:v.query,hash:v.hash,params:z.path!=null?{}:v.params},z)}}function te(v,P){const j=m=C(v),T=c.value,z=v.state,l=v.force,p=v.replace===!0,f=re(j,T);if(f)return te(W(A(f),{state:typeof f=="object"?W({},z,f.state):z,force:l,replace:p}),P||j);const b=j;b.redirectedFrom=P;let E;return!l&&Xa(i,T,j)&&(E=Bt(oe.NAVIGATION_DUPLICATED,{to:b,from:T}),ke(T,T,!0,!1)),(E?Promise.resolve(E):Ne(b,T)).catch(y=>$e(y)?$e(y,oe.NAVIGATION_GUARD_REDIRECT)?y:ct(y):F(y,b,T)).then(y=>{if(y){if($e(y,oe.NAVIGATION_GUARD_REDIRECT))return te(W({replace:p},A(y.to),{state:typeof y.to=="object"?W({},z,y.to.state):z,force:l}),P||b)}else y=yt(b,T,!0,p,z);return rt(b,T,y),y})}function Re(v,P){const j=N(v,P);return j?Promise.reject(j):Promise.resolve()}function st(v){const P=Pt.values().next().value;return P&&typeof P.runWithContext=="function"?P.runWithContext(v):v()}function Ne(v,P){let j;const[T,z,l]=hl(v,P);j=ui(T.reverse(),"beforeRouteLeave",v,P);for(const f of T)f.leaveGuards.forEach(b=>{j.push(mt(b,v,P))});const p=Re.bind(null,v,P);return j.push(p),Se(j).then(()=>{j=[];for(const f of s.list())j.push(mt(f,v,P));return j.push(p),Se(j)}).then(()=>{j=ui(z,"beforeRouteUpdate",v,P);for(const f of z)f.updateGuards.forEach(b=>{j.push(mt(b,v,P))});return j.push(p),Se(j)}).then(()=>{j=[];for(const f of l)if(f.beforeEnter)if(Te(f.beforeEnter))for(const b of f.beforeEnter)j.push(mt(b,v,P));else j.push(mt(f.beforeEnter,v,P));return j.push(p),Se(j)}).then(()=>(v.matched.forEach(f=>f.enterCallbacks={}),j=ui(l,"beforeRouteEnter",v,P,st),j.push(p),Se(j))).then(()=>{j=[];for(const f of r.list())j.push(mt(f,v,P));return j.push(p),Se(j)}).catch(f=>$e(f,oe.NAVIGATION_CANCELLED)?f:Promise.reject(f))}function rt(v,P,j){a.list().forEach(T=>st(()=>T(v,P,j)))}function yt(v,P,j,T,z){const l=N(v,P);if(l)return l;const p=P===at,f=Ct?history.state:{};j&&(T||p?n.replace(v.fullPath,W({scroll:p&&f&&f.scroll},z)):n.push(v.fullPath,z)),c.value=v,ke(v,P,j,p),ct()}let De;function Ut(){De||(De=n.listen((v,P,j)=>{if(!bt.listening)return;const T=C(v),z=re(T,bt.currentRoute.value);if(z){te(W(z,{replace:!0,force:!0}),T).catch(io);return}m=T;const l=c.value;Ct&&cl(Rn(l.fullPath,j.delta),Qo()),Ne(T,l).catch(p=>$e(p,oe.NAVIGATION_ABORTED|oe.NAVIGATION_CANCELLED)?p:$e(p,oe.NAVIGATION_GUARD_REDIRECT)?(te(W(A(p.to),{force:!0}),T).then(f=>{$e(f,oe.NAVIGATION_ABORTED|oe.NAVIGATION_DUPLICATED)&&!j.delta&&j.type===Oi.pop&&n.go(-1,!1)}).catch(io),Promise.reject()):(j.delta&&n.go(-j.delta,!1),F(p,T,l))).then(p=>{p=p||yt(T,l,!1),p&&(j.delta&&!$e(p,oe.NAVIGATION_CANCELLED)?n.go(-j.delta,!1):j.type===Oi.pop&&$e(p,oe.NAVIGATION_ABORTED|oe.NAVIGATION_DUPLICATED)&&n.go(-1,!1)),rt(T,l,p)}).catch(io)}))}let jt=Kt(),se=Kt(),Q;function F(v,P,j){ct(v);const T=se.list();return T.length?T.forEach(z=>z(v,P,j)):console.error(v),Promise.reject(v)}function Ye(){return Q&&c.value!==at?Promise.resolve():new Promise((v,P)=>{jt.add([v,P])})}function ct(v){return Q||(Q=!v,Ut(),jt.list().forEach(([P,j])=>v?j(v):P()),jt.reset()),v}function ke(v,P,j,T){const{scrollBehavior:z}=e;if(!Ct||!z)return Promise.resolve();const l=!j&&al(Rn(v.fullPath,0))||(T||!j)&&history.state&&history.state.scroll||null;return Hi().then(()=>z(v,P,l)).then(p=>p&&rl(p)).catch(p=>F(p,v,P))}const ge=v=>n.go(v);let xt;const Pt=new Set,bt={currentRoute:c,listening:!0,addRoute:h,removeRoute:M,clearRoutes:t.clearRoutes,hasRoute:G,getRoutes:_,resolve:C,options:e,push:I,replace:$,go:ge,back:()=>ge(-1),forward:()=>ge(1),beforeEach:s.add,beforeResolve:r.add,afterEach:a.add,onError:se.add,isReady:Ye,install(v){v.component("RouterLink",kl),v.component("RouterView",hr),v.config.globalProperties.$router=bt,Object.defineProperty(v.config.globalProperties,"$route",{enumerable:!0,get:()=>_t(c)}),Ct&&!xt&&c.value===at&&(xt=!0,I(n.location).catch(T=>{}));const P={};for(const T in at)Object.defineProperty(P,T,{get:()=>c.value[T],enumerable:!0});v.provide($o,bt),v.provide(pr,bs(P)),v.provide(Si,c);const j=v.unmount;Pt.add(v),v.unmount=function(){Pt.delete(v),Pt.size<1&&(m=at,De&&De(),De=null,c.value=at,xt=!1,Q=!1),j()}}};function Se(v){return v.reduce((P,j)=>P.then(()=>st(j)),Promise.resolve())}return bt}function Ki(){return We($o)}const zl={__name:"App",setup(e){return(t,o)=>(ce(),To(_t(hr)))}},Ul={class:"page"},Fl={__name:"Home",setup(e){const t=Ki(),o=()=>{t.push("/quiz")},i=()=>{t.push("/settings")};return(n,s)=>(ce(),qe("div",Ul,[L("div",{class:"container"},[L("div",{class:"card text-center"},[s[0]||(s[0]=L("div",{class:"card-header"},[L("h2",null,"quiz")],-1)),L("div",{class:"btn-group"},[L("button",{onClick:o,class:"btn btn-primary btn-large"}," Start Quiz "),L("button",{onClick:i,class:"btn btn-secondary btn-large"}," Settings ")])])])]))}},Wl={class:"card fade-in"},Vl={class:"question-number"},Kl={class:"question-text"},Yl={class:"options-list"},Ql=["onClick"],$l={__name:"QuestionCard",props:{question:{type:Object,required:!0},questionNumber:{type:Number,required:!0},totalQuestions:{type:Number,required:!0}},emits:["answer"],setup(e,{emit:t}){const o=e,i=t,n=Ae(null),s=Ae(!1);to(()=>o.question,()=>{n.value=null,s.value=!1},{deep:!0});const r=c=>{if(s.value)return;n.value=c,s.value=!0;const m=c===o.question.correctOption;setTimeout(()=>{i("answer",m)},1e3)},a=c=>s.value?c===o.question.correctOption?"correct":c===n.value&&c!==o.question.correctOption?"incorrect":"":n.value===c?"selected":"";return(c,m)=>(ce(),qe("div",Wl,[L("div",Vl," Question "+we(e.questionNumber)+" of "+we(e.totalQuestions),1),L("div",Kl,we(e.question.question),1),L("ul",Yl,[(ce(!0),qe(je,null,gi(e.question.options,(u,d)=>(ce(),qe("li",{key:d,class:Bo(["option-item",a(d+1)]),onClick:g=>r(d+1)},[L("strong",null,we(String.fromCharCode(65+d))+".",1),$s(" "+we(u),1)],10,Ql))),128))])]))}},Zl={class:"card fade-in"},Jl={class:"score-display"},Xl={class:"score-number"},eu={class:"score-message"},tu={__name:"ScoreCard",props:{score:{type:Number,required:!0},totalQuestions:{type:Number,required:!0}},emits:["retry","home"],setup(e,{emit:t}){const o=e,i=t,n=ae(()=>Math.round(o.score/o.totalQuestions*100)),s=ae(()=>{const c=n.value;return c===100?" Perfect Score! Outstanding!":c>=80?" Excellent Work!":c>=60?" Good Job!":c>=40?" Keep Practicing!":" Don't Give Up!"}),r=()=>{i("retry")},a=()=>{i("home")};return(c,m)=>(ce(),qe("div",Zl,[L("div",Jl,[m[0]||(m[0]=L("h2",null," Quiz Complete!",-1)),L("div",Xl,we(e.score)+"/"+we(e.totalQuestions),1),L("div",eu,we(n.value)+"% - "+we(s.value),1),L("div",{class:"btn-group"},[L("button",{onClick:r,class:"btn btn-success btn-large"},"  Retry "),L("button",{onClick:a,class:"btn btn-secondary btn-large"},"  Go Home ")])])]))}},ou=[{id:1,question:"What is the correct syntax for referring to an external JavaScript file?",options:['<script href="app.js">','<script name="app.js">','<script src="app.js">','<script file="app.js">'],correctOption:3,subject:{name:"Web Development",topic:"JavaScript Basics"}},{id:2,question:"How do you declare a JavaScript variable?",options:["variable carName;","var carName;","v carName;","declare carName;"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"JavaScript",topic:"Variables"}},{id:3,question:"Which operator is used to assign a value to a variable?",options:["*","-","=","x"],correctOption:3,subject:{name:"JavaScript",topic:"Operators"}},{id:4,question:"Which built-in method returns the length of a string?",options:["length()","size()","index()","length"],correctOption:4,subject:{name:"JavaScript",topic:"String Methods"}}],iu=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,default:ou},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),nu=[{id:1,question:"The aggregate demand (AD) curve slopes downward primarily because:",options:["Substitution effect across goods","Wealth, interest rate, and net export effects as P falls","Giffen behavior","Sticky wages"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Models of aggregate demand and aggregate supply"}},{id:2,question:"In the AD-AS framework, a monetary expansion shifts:",options:["AD to the right","AD to the left","SRAS to the right","LRAS to the left"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Models of aggregate demand and aggregate supply"}},{id:3,question:"Short-run aggregate supply (SRAS) is typically:",options:["Vertical","Upward sloping due to sticky wages/prices","Downward sloping","Horizontal always"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Models of aggregate demand and aggregate supply"}},{id:4,question:"Long-run aggregate supply (LRAS) is:",options:["Upward sloping","Vertical at potential output","Downward sloping","Horizontal"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Models of aggregate demand and aggregate supply"}},{id:5,question:"A negative supply shock (e.g., oil price spike) causes:",options:["SRAS shifts right; inflation falls","SRAS shifts left; inflation rises and output falls","AD shifts left; output rises","LRAS shifts right"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Models of aggregate demand and aggregate supply"}},{id:6,question:"Demand-pull inflation arises from:",options:["Leftward shift in SRAS","Rightward shift in AD","Rightward shift in LRAS","Leftward shift in LRAS"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Models of aggregate demand and aggregate supply"}},{id:7,question:"Cost-push inflation arises when:",options:["AD increases","SRAS decreases","LRAS increases","Money supply falls"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Models of aggregate demand and aggregate supply"}},{id:8,question:"In the long run after a positive AD shock (with adaptive expectations), output:",options:["Remains above potential","Returns to potential output","Falls below potential permanently","Becomes unstable"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Models of aggregate demand and aggregate supply"}},{id:9,question:"Expectations-augmented SRAS implies that higher expected inflation:",options:["Shifts SRAS right","Shifts SRAS left","Shifts AD right","Shifts LRAS left"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Models of aggregate demand and aggregate supply"}},{id:10,question:"Stagflation refers to:",options:["High growth, low inflation","High inflation with stagnant or falling output","Low inflation and high unemployment","Deflation with high growth"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Models of aggregate demand and aggregate supply"}},{id:11,question:"Deriving AD from IS-LM: as P rises, real money balances fall and:",options:["LM shifts right; Y rises","LM shifts left; Y falls","IS shifts left; Y rises","IS shifts right; Y falls"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Models of aggregate demand and aggregate supply"}},{id:12,question:"LRAS shifts to the right due to:",options:["Higher money supply","Technological progress or factor accumulation","Higher taxes","Temporary subsidies"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Models of aggregate demand and aggregate supply"}},{id:13,question:"A credible disinflation policy (anchored expectations) causes SRAS to:",options:["Shift left strongly","Shift right relative to adaptive expectations case","Not shift","Coincide with LRAS"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Models of aggregate demand and aggregate supply"}},{id:14,question:"A fiscal contraction (lower G) in AD-AS causes:",options:["AD left; lower inflation and lower Y in short run","AD right; higher inflation","SRAS left","LRAS right"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Models of aggregate demand and aggregate supply"}},{id:15,question:"If wages are sticky downward, a negative demand shock may cause:",options:["Rapid deflation and output recovery","Prolonged unemployment and output gap","Higher potential output","SRAS to shift right immediately"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Models of aggregate demand and aggregate supply"}},{id:16,question:"Supply-side policies that raise productivity will:",options:["Shift LRAS and SRAS right","Shift AD right only","Shift AD left","Lower LRAS"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Models of aggregate demand and aggregate supply"}},{id:17,question:"Menu costs and price stickiness help explain:",options:["Vertical SRAS","Upward-sloping SRAS in short run","Downward-sloping LRAS","Horizontal LRAS"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Models of aggregate demand and aggregate supply"}},{id:18,question:"If expected inflation equals actual inflation, the economy is on:",options:["Short-run Phillips curve away from natural rate","Long-run Phillips curve at natural rate","LRAS shifted left","AD shifted right"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Models of aggregate demand and aggregate supply"}},{id:19,question:"An oil price decline (positive supply shock) will:",options:["Shift SRAS right; lower inflation and raise Y","Shift AD left","Shift LRAS left","Raise inflation and lower Y"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Models of aggregate demand and aggregate supply"}},{id:20,question:"A temporary VAT cut (indirect tax) may:",options:["Shift SRAS right via lower costs","Shift AD left","Shift LRAS right","Not affect inflation"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Models of aggregate demand and aggregate supply"}},{id:21,question:"In the AD-AS model, deflationary gap refers to:",options:["Y > Y*","Y < Y* at current AD and SRAS","P above equilibrium","LRAS left of SRAS"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Models of aggregate demand and aggregate supply"}},{id:22,question:"A positive demand shock with static expectations initially moves the economy:",options:["Up along SRAS to higher P and Y","Down along SRAS to lower P and Y","Left along LRAS","Right along LRAS"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Models of aggregate demand and aggregate supply"}},{id:23,question:"In the long run, monetary neutrality implies that higher money growth:",options:["Raises real output permanently","Raises inflation but not real output","Lowers unemployment permanently","Shifts LRAS left"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Models of aggregate demand and aggregate supply"}},{id:24,question:"A negative demand shock with credible policy response that lowers expected inflation will:",options:["Shift SRAS left","Shift SRAS right, softening the output fall","Shift AD right only","No effect"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Models of aggregate demand and aggregate supply"}},{id:25,question:"The output gap is defined as:",options:["Actual inflation minus expected inflation","Actual output minus potential output (often percent deviation)","Unemployment minus natural rate","AD minus AS"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Models of aggregate demand and aggregate supply"}},{id:26,question:"If nominal wages are set based on expected prices, an unanticipated disinflation will:",options:["Shift SRAS left","Shift SRAS right","Shift AD right","Shift LRAS right"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Models of aggregate demand and aggregate supply"}},{id:27,question:"A rightward shift of LRAS with unchanged AD leads to:",options:["Higher inflation","Lower inflation and higher potential output","Lower output and higher inflation","No change"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Models of aggregate demand and aggregate supply"}},{id:28,question:"Under rational expectations and flexible prices, anticipated monetary expansion:",options:["Raises real output","Only raises the price level","Lowers unemployment permanently","Shifts LRAS"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Models of aggregate demand and aggregate supply"}},{id:29,question:"Which policy best counters a negative supply shock without raising inflation?",options:["Fiscal expansion","Monetary expansion","Supply-side measures to raise productivity","Price controls"],correctOption:3,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Models of aggregate demand and aggregate supply"}},{id:30,question:"If AD increases persistently beyond potential, in the medium run:",options:["SRAS shifts left as expectations adjust, returning Y to potential at higher inflation","LRAS shifts left permanently","Y stays above potential","Inflation falls"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Models of aggregate demand and aggregate supply"}}],su=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,default:nu},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),ru=[{id:1,question:"In the Harrod-Domar model, the warranted growth rate equals:",options:["s/v","v/s","sv","s  v"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Harrod-Domar Model"}},{id:2,question:"The parameter v in Harrod-Domar denotes:",options:["Marginal propensity to save","Incremental capital-output ratio (ICOR)","Depreciation rate","Population growth"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Harrod-Domar Model"}},{id:3,question:"According to Harrod-Domar, growth is driven primarily by:",options:["Labor supply","Savings and capital accumulation given a fixed ICOR","Technological progress","Government spending only"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Harrod-Domar Model"}},{id:4,question:"The model exhibits knife-edge instability because:",options:["Any deviation from warranted growth is self-correcting","Deviations from warranted growth are not automatically corrected","Technology adjusts to close gaps","Fiscal policy instantly stabilizes"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Harrod-Domar Model"}},{id:5,question:"If s rises holding v constant, the warranted growth rate:",options:["Falls","Unchanged","Rises","Becomes negative"],correctOption:3,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Harrod-Domar Model"}},{id:6,question:"The natural growth rate in Harrod-Domar is determined by:",options:["Saving rate","Population (labor force) growth and technical progress","Government spending","Inflation"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Harrod-Domar Model"}},{id:7,question:"For steady growth without inflationary/deflationary pressure, the model requires:",options:["Actual = warranted = natural growth","Actual > natural growth","Warranted < actual growth","Natural < warranted growth"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Harrod-Domar Model"}},{id:8,question:"Policy to raise growth in Harrod-Domar focuses on:",options:["Raising s or lowering v via investment efficiency","Lowering population","Cutting technology","Lowering capital formation"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Harrod-Domar Model"}},{id:9,question:"A higher ICOR (v) implies:",options:["More output from given capital","Less output per unit of capital (less efficient)","Unchanged output","Lower savings"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Harrod-Domar Model"}},{id:10,question:"Investment plays a dual role by:",options:["Reducing capacity and demand","Creating demand now and capacity for future output","Only creating demand","Only creating capacity"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Harrod-Domar Model"}},{id:11,question:"A financing gap approach in development planning based on Harrod-Domar posits:",options:["FDI reduces growth","Aid inflows can relax savings constraints to meet target growth","Imports do not matter","Domestic savings are irrelevant"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Harrod-Domar Model"}},{id:12,question:"The incremental capital-output ratio is best interpreted as:",options:["K/Y","Y/K","K/Y","Y/K"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Harrod-Domar Model"}},{id:13,question:"If depreciation rises, then to maintain growth the saving rate must:",options:["Fall","Rise","Unchanged","Become zero"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Harrod-Domar Model"}},{id:14,question:"Harrod-Domar assumes the capital-output ratio is:",options:["Variable and flexible","Fixed (or proportional)","Declining with scale","Increasing with technology"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Harrod-Domar Model"}},{id:15,question:"Instability in Harrod-Domar arises from:",options:["Flexible prices","Lack of mechanisms to align actual with warranted growth","Perfect foresight","Rational expectations"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Harrod-Domar Model"}},{id:16,question:"To achieve a target growth g* with ICOR v, required s is approximately:",options:["s  g* / v","s  v / g*","s  g*  v","s  g*  v"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Harrod-Domar Model"}},{id:17,question:"In Harrod-Domar, unemployment or inflation pressures emerge when:",options:["Actual growth equals warranted","Actual below warranted (unemployment) or above (inflation)","Natural equals warranted","Savings equal investment"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Harrod-Domar Model"}},{id:18,question:"A policy that lowers v could be:",options:["Investing in efficient technology and maintenance","Cutting education","Raising trade barriers","Reducing savings"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Harrod-Domar Model"}},{id:19,question:"The Harrod-Domar model is often contrasted with Solow because:",options:["Solow emphasizes a fixed ICOR","Solow allows factor substitution and diminishing returns","Solow has no capital","Solow excludes savings"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Harrod-Domar Model"}},{id:20,question:"If s = 0.24 and v = 4, warranted growth is:",options:["6%","4%","8%","2%"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Harrod-Domar Model"}},{id:21,question:"External financing that raises investment without raising savings may in Harrod-Domar:",options:["Leave growth unchanged","Raise growth by relaxing savings constraint","Lower growth","Reduce efficiency"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Harrod-Domar Model"}},{id:22,question:"Natural growth exceeding warranted growth implies:",options:["Persistent inflation pressure","Underutilization of capacity (unemployment)","Balanced growth","Falling capital"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Harrod-Domar Model"}},{id:23,question:"A key critique of Harrod-Domar is that it:",options:["Ignores savings","Assumes fixed coefficients and lacks substitution, overstating instability","Has too much microfoundation","Ignores capital"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Harrod-Domar Model"}},{id:24,question:"Planned investment determines growth because:",options:["It sets government spending","It sets capital accumulation given ICOR","It determines money supply","It fixes consumption"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Harrod-Domar Model"}},{id:25,question:"If v falls due to efficiency gains, then for fixed s:",options:["Warranted growth rises","Warranted growth falls","Unchanged","Becomes negative"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Harrod-Domar Model"}},{id:26,question:"In the Harrod-Domar setup, a savings shortfall relative to warranted growth target implies:",options:["Output target is met","Need for external finance or raise s","Lower capital-output ratio immediately","Higher depreciation"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Harrod-Domar Model"}},{id:27,question:"If actual growth persistently exceeds natural growth, then:",options:["Unemployment rises","Inflationary pressure emerges","Deflation occurs","No imbalance"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Harrod-Domar Model"}},{id:28,question:"The accelerator principle in Harrod-Domar implies investment depends on:",options:["Current output level only","Changes in output (growth)","Interest rate only","Government policy only"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Harrod-Domar Model"}},{id:29,question:"For a target growth of 7% with v = 3, required s is about:",options:["21%","10%","3%","7%"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Harrod-Domar Model"}},{id:30,question:"Harrod-Domar is most applicable to contexts where:",options:["Capital is abundant","Capital scarcity and savings constraints limit growth","Labor shortage dominates","Technology grows endogenously"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Harrod-Domar Model"}}],cu=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,default:ru},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),au=[{id:1,question:"The IS curve represents combinations of income and interest rates such that:",options:["Money market is in equilibrium","Goods market is in equilibrium","Both markets are in equilibrium","Labor market is in equilibrium"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"IS-LM Model"}},{id:2,question:"The LM curve shifts right when:",options:["Money supply increases","Government spending increases","Taxes increase","Price level rises"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"IS-LM Model"}},{id:3,question:"An increase in government spending (with fixed money supply) causes:",options:["IS shifts right; interest rate down","IS shifts right; interest rate up","LM shifts right; interest rate up","LM shifts left; output up"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"IS-LM Model"}},{id:4,question:"Money demand typically depends positively on income and:",options:["Positively on interest rate","Negatively on interest rate","Not on interest rate","Only on prices"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"IS-LM Model"}},{id:5,question:"A liquidity trap corresponds to:",options:["Vertical LM curve","Horizontal LM curve at low interest rates","Downward-sloping LM curve","Upward-sloping IS curve"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"IS-LM Model"}},{id:6,question:"If money supply falls, ceteris paribus:",options:["LM shifts left; output falls","IS shifts left; output rises","LM shifts right; output rises","IS shifts right; output falls"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"IS-LM Model"}},{id:7,question:"Crowding out in IS-LM occurs because:",options:["Higher Y lowers investment","Higher interest rates reduce investment when fiscal policy expands","Money demand falls with Y","Prices fall"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"IS-LM Model"}},{id:8,question:"The slope of the IS curve depends on:",options:["Interest sensitivity of money demand","Interest sensitivity of investment and multiplier size","Price elasticity of demand","Tax rate only"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"IS-LM Model"}},{id:9,question:"An increase in the price level (P) shifts the LM curve:",options:["Right (real balances rise)","Left (real balances fall)","Does not shift","Rotates the IS curve"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"IS-LM Model"}},{id:10,question:"Monetary expansion in IS-LM leads to:",options:["Lower i and higher Y","Higher i and lower Y","Higher i and higher Y","No change"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"IS-LM Model"}},{id:11,question:"If investment is very interest-inelastic, fiscal expansion:",options:["Raises Y strongly with little crowding out","Has no effect","Lowers Y","Raises i only"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"IS-LM Model"}},{id:12,question:"If money demand is very interest-elastic (almost flat LM), monetary policy:",options:["Is very powerful","Is weak in changing Y","Raises prices only","Shifts IS"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"IS-LM Model"}},{id:13,question:"The real money balances equal:",options:["M/P","MP","P/M","MP"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"IS-LM Model"}},{id:14,question:"The goods market clearing condition in IS-LM is:",options:["Y = C(Y  T) + I(i) + G","M/P = L(Y, i)","S = I only","G = T"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"IS-LM Model"}},{id:15,question:"A rightward shift in money demand (L) leads to:",options:["Higher i and lower Y","Lower i and higher Y","Higher i and higher Y","Lower i and lower Y"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"IS-LM Model"}},{id:16,question:"An increase in taxes (T > 0), ceteris paribus:",options:["Shifts IS right","Shifts IS left","Shifts LM right","Shifts LM left"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"IS-LM Model"}},{id:17,question:"If the central bank raises M while prices are sticky, in short run:",options:["Y rises, i falls","Y falls, i rises","Y rises, i rises","No change"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"IS-LM Model"}},{id:18,question:"Under classical case (vertical LM due to interest-insensitive money demand), fiscal expansion:",options:["Raises Y strongly","Crowds out completely (i rises, Y unchanged)","Lowers i","Shifts LM"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"IS-LM Model"}},{id:19,question:"What shifts the IS curve?",options:["Changes in taxes, government spending, or autonomous investment","Changes in money supply","Changes in price level only","Changes in labor supply"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"IS-LM Model"}},{id:20,question:"What shifts the LM curve?",options:["Government purchases","Autonomous consumption","Money supply or money demand changes","Technology"],correctOption:3,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"IS-LM Model"}},{id:21,question:"Real balance effect of a fall in P implies:",options:["LM shifts left","LM shifts right, raising Y","IS shifts right","IS shifts left"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"IS-LM Model"}},{id:22,question:"In IS-LM, a combination of fiscal expansion and monetary contraction tends to:",options:["Raise i with ambiguous effect on Y","Lower i and raise Y","Lower both i and Y","Raise both i and Y"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"IS-LM Model"}},{id:23,question:"Money market equilibrium condition is:",options:["Y = C + I + G","M/P = L(Y, i)","S = I","NX = 0"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"IS-LM Model"}},{id:24,question:"If investment depends also on income, the IS curve becomes:",options:["Steeper","Flatter","Vertical","Horizontal"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"IS-LM Model"}},{id:25,question:"Which policy mix best lowers i while raising Y?",options:["Fiscal expansion + monetary contraction","Fiscal contraction + monetary expansion","Both expansionary","Both contractionary"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"IS-LM Model"}},{id:26,question:"Endogenous money models differ by assuming:",options:["Money supply is fixed exogenously","Bank lending creates deposits and money supply responds to demand","Velocity is constant","No role for interest rates"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"IS-LM Model"}},{id:27,question:"The interest elasticity of money demand affects the LM slope by:",options:["Higher elasticity makes LM flatter","Higher elasticity makes LM steeper","No effect","Reverses slope"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"IS-LM Model"}},{id:28,question:"If the central bank targets interest rate, the LM curve is:",options:["Horizontal at target i","Vertical","Downward sloping","Upward sloping"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"IS-LM Model"}},{id:29,question:"A negative shock to autonomous consumption shifts:",options:["IS left","IS right","LM left","LM right"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"IS-LM Model"}},{id:30,question:"In IS-LM, if prices adjust fully in the long run:",options:["Y remains above potential","Monetary neutrality restores Y to potential","Fiscal policy has permanent real effects","LM does not shift"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"IS-LM Model"}}],lu=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,default:au},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),uu=[{id:1,question:"Which is not a primary function of money?",options:["Medium of exchange","Store of value","Unit of account","Source of government revenue"],correctOption:4,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Money, banking and inflation"}},{id:2,question:"In fractional reserve banking, the money multiplier (simplest form) is roughly:",options:["1/rr","1  rr","rr","1 + rr"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Money, banking and inflation"}},{id:3,question:"Open market purchases by the central bank tend to:",options:["Reduce the monetary base","Increase the monetary base and lower interest rates","Raise reserve requirements","Raise discount rate"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Money, banking and inflation"}},{id:4,question:"According to the Quantity Theory (MV = PY), if V is constant and M grows 5% while Y grows 2%:",options:["Inflation  7%","Inflation  3%","Inflation  3%","Inflation  5%"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Money, banking and inflation"}},{id:5,question:"The Fisher equation relates:",options:["Nominal rate to expected inflation: i  r + ^e","Real rate to money growth","Output to money growth","Unemployment to inflation"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Money, banking and inflation"}},{id:6,question:"Seigniorage refers to:",options:["Revenue from taxes","Revenue from money creation","Bank profits","Foreign aid"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Money, banking and inflation"}},{id:7,question:"Inflation tax is borne primarily by holders of:",options:["Real assets","Money balances","Government bonds indexed to inflation","Equities"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Money, banking and inflation"}},{id:8,question:"In the long run, money is:",options:["Neutral for real variables","Determinant of real output","Always contractionary","Expansionary for growth"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Money, banking and inflation"}},{id:9,question:"Banks create money when they:",options:["Hold excess reserves","Make loans that create deposits","Destroy deposits","Raise capital"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Money, banking and inflation"}},{id:10,question:"Hyperinflation is typically associated with:",options:["Fiscal dominance and money financing of deficits","Strong central bank independence","Commodity standards","Falling velocity"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Money, banking and inflation"}},{id:11,question:"Menu costs are:",options:["Costs of changing prices","Costs of printing money","Costs of paying taxes","Costs of holding cash"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Money, banking and inflation"}},{id:12,question:"Shoe-leather costs arise because:",options:["Inflation raises interest on money","Inflation reduces the opportunity cost of holding money","Inflation raises the opportunity cost of holding money","Inflation lowers nominal rates"],correctOption:3,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Money, banking and inflation"}},{id:13,question:"If the central bank raises reserve requirements:",options:["Money multiplier increases","Money multiplier falls","Base money rises automatically","Velocity rises"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Money, banking and inflation"}},{id:14,question:"Ex-ante real interest rate equals:",options:["i  ","i  ^e","  i","i + ^e"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Money, banking and inflation"}},{id:15,question:"Credit channel of monetary policy emphasizes:",options:["Only interest rate effects","Bank balance sheet and borrower net worth effects","Only exchange rate effects","Only fiscal policy"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Money, banking and inflation"}},{id:16,question:"A fixed nominal interest rate target with rising inflation implies real rates:",options:["Rise","Fall","Unchanged","Become negative only if deflation"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Money, banking and inflation"}},{id:17,question:"Monetary base (high-powered money) consists of:",options:["Currency in circulation and bank reserves","M1 and M2","Currency and time deposits","Government bonds"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Money, banking and inflation"}},{id:18,question:"Under inflation targeting, the central bank primarily uses:",options:["Money supply growth target","Interest rate policy (policy rate) guided by forecasts","Exchange rate pegs","Reserve requirement adjustments only"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Money, banking and inflation"}},{id:19,question:"Unanticipated inflation tends to redistribute wealth from:",options:["Borrowers to lenders","Lenders to borrowers","Workers to firms only","Government to households"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Money, banking and inflation"}},{id:20,question:"The money demand function L(Y, i) implies that as income rises:",options:["Money demand falls","Money demand rises","Money demand unchanged","Velocity falls to zero"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Money, banking and inflation"}},{id:21,question:"If inflation expectations become anchored lower, then for given policy rate:",options:["Real rates rise","Real rates fall","No change","Money demand collapses"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Money, banking and inflation"}},{id:22,question:"Quantitative easing primarily changes:",options:["Policy rate directly","Composition and size of central bank balance sheet to affect term premia","Reserve requirements","Tax revenues"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Money, banking and inflation"}},{id:23,question:"Currency-deposit ratio rise (c) with fixed base implies money multiplier:",options:["Rises","Falls","Unchanged","Becomes infinite"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Money, banking and inflation"}},{id:24,question:"Deflation can be problematic because:",options:["Raises real debt burdens","Lowers real interest rates automatically","Raises nominal wages","Eliminates unemployment"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Money, banking and inflation"}},{id:25,question:"Under a money growth rule with constant velocity, steady inflation equals:",options:["Money growth + output growth","Money growth  output growth","Output growth  money growth","Zero"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Money, banking and inflation"}},{id:26,question:"Bank capital adequacy affects monetary transmission because:",options:["Higher capital tightens credit supply in stress","Capital is irrelevant to lending","Reserves equal capital","Capital raises base money"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Money, banking and inflation"}},{id:27,question:"If expected inflation rises one-for-one with money growth, then in the long run:",options:["Real interest rate rises","Nominal interest rate rises roughly one-for-one","Real output rises","Unemployment falls permanently"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Money, banking and inflation"}},{id:28,question:"Central bank independence is associated empirically with:",options:["Higher average inflation","Lower and more stable inflation","No relation","Higher output growth"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Money, banking and inflation"}},{id:29,question:"Velocity of money tends to be:",options:["Perfectly constant","Stable in some periods but can vary with interest rates and financial innovation","Always falling","Always rising"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Money, banking and inflation"}},{id:30,question:"In a banks balance sheet, reserves are:",options:["Liabilities","Assets held at the central bank and in vault cash","Equity","Off-balance-sheet items"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Money, banking and inflation"}}],pu=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,default:uu},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),mu=[{id:1,question:"Gross Domestic Product (GDP) is best defined as:",options:["The market value of all final goods and services produced by nationals anywhere","The market value of all final goods and services produced within a country in a period","Total income received by residents from abroad","Total output excluding government"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"National income accounting"}},{id:2,question:"The expenditure approach to GDP equals:",options:["C + I + G + (X  M)","C + S + T","W + R + i + ","Y  T + TR"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"National income accounting"}},{id:3,question:"Which is counted in GDP?",options:["Sale of used car","Intermediate goods used in production","Imputed rental value of owner-occupied housing","Household unpaid work"],correctOption:3,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"National income accounting"}},{id:4,question:"Gross National Income (GNI) differs from GDP by:",options:["Adding net taxes","Subtracting depreciation","Adding net factor income from abroad","Subtracting government spending"],correctOption:3,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"National income accounting"}},{id:5,question:"Net Domestic Product (NDP) equals:",options:["GDP minus indirect taxes","GDP minus depreciation (consumption of fixed capital)","GNI minus depreciation","Personal income minus taxes"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"National income accounting"}},{id:6,question:"Inventory investment in GDP is recorded when:",options:["Firms sell goods from inventory","Firms add unsold goods to inventory","Consumers pre-order goods","Imports increase"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"National income accounting"}},{id:7,question:"To avoid double counting, GDP includes:",options:["Value of intermediate goods","Value added at each stage","Total sales of all firms","Only household consumption"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"National income accounting"}},{id:8,question:"Real GDP differs from nominal GDP by:",options:["Excluding government spending","Valuing output at constant prices","Valuing at current prices","Excluding investment"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"National income accounting"}},{id:9,question:"The GDP deflator is defined as:",options:["Nominal GDP / Real GDP  100","CPI / PPI  100","Real GDP / Nominal GDP  100","PPI / CPI  100"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"National income accounting"}},{id:10,question:"Which item is excluded from GDP?",options:["Government purchases","Net exports","Transfer payments","Gross private investment"],correctOption:3,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"National income accounting"}},{id:11,question:"Personal Disposable Income (PDI) equals:",options:["National income minus depreciation","Personal income minus personal taxes","GNI minus transfers","GDP minus government purchases"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"National income accounting"}},{id:12,question:"If imports rise holding other components fixed, GDP:",options:["Rises","Falls","Unchanged","Depends on inflation"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"National income accounting"}},{id:13,question:"Household production is typically:",options:["Valued at market prices in GDP","Excluded due to lack of market transactions","Included via imputation for all activities","Treated as investment"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"National income accounting"}},{id:14,question:"Which index better captures all domestically produced goods prices?",options:["CPI","GDP deflator","PPI","Core CPI"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"National income accounting"}},{id:15,question:"Chain-weighted real GDP is used to:",options:["Fix base-year prices forever","Account for changing relative prices over time","Exclude government consumption","Eliminate depreciation"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"National income accounting"}},{id:16,question:"In the income approach, GDP sums:",options:["Consumption, investment, government, net exports","Wages, rent, interest, profits plus taxes less subsidies and depreciation","Only wages and profits","Personal income only"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"National income accounting"}},{id:17,question:"Underground economy activity is:",options:["Fully captured in GDP","Partly missed, leading to underestimation","Overstated in CPI","Recorded as transfers"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"National income accounting"}},{id:18,question:"Capital gains on existing assets are:",options:["Included in GDP","Excluded from GDP","Included in NNP","Included in GNI only"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"National income accounting"}},{id:19,question:"If a domestic firm produces abroad, the output contributes to:",options:["Home country GDP","Host country GNI","Home country GNI","Neither countrys accounts"],correctOption:3,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"National income accounting"}},{id:20,question:"Net exports equal:",options:["Exports + Imports","Exports  Imports","Imports  Exports","Exports  Transfers"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"National income accounting"}},{id:21,question:"Depreciation is also called:",options:["Capital widening","Consumption of fixed capital","Net investment","Inventory drawdown"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"National income accounting"}},{id:22,question:"Gross vs. net investment differ by:",options:["Government purchases","Depreciation","Imports","Transfers"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"National income accounting"}},{id:23,question:"Which raises GDP directly?",options:["An increase in transfers","An increase in government purchases of goods and services","A higher CPI","A stock market boom"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"National income accounting"}},{id:24,question:"Value added is defined as:",options:["Sales minus wages","Sales minus intermediate inputs","Profits minus taxes","Output minus depreciation"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"National income accounting"}},{id:25,question:"Net factor income from abroad equals:",options:["Exports  Imports","Income received from abroad by residents minus income paid to foreigners","Transfers from abroad","Foreign aid"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"National income accounting"}},{id:26,question:"The CPI differs from the GDP deflator because CPI:",options:["Covers domestically produced goods only","Covers a fixed basket of consumer goods including imports","Excludes services","Uses chain weights"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"National income accounting"}},{id:27,question:"Seasonal adjustment in GDP aims to:",options:["Remove long-run trends","Remove predictable seasonal patterns","Eliminate inflation","Convert to PPP terms"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"National income accounting"}},{id:28,question:"Purchasing Power Parity adjustments are used to:",options:["Compare poverty lines within a country","Compare output across countries at common prices","Measure inflation within a country","Compute budget deficits"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"National income accounting"}},{id:29,question:"If nominal GDP grows 8% and the deflator grows 5%, real GDP growth is approximately:",options:["13%","3%","3%","5%"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"National income accounting"}},{id:30,question:"Which is an example of intermediate goods?",options:["Flour purchased by a bakery","Bread bought by a household","Government purchase of a new vehicle","New residential construction"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"National income accounting"}}],du=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,default:mu},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),fu=[{id:1,question:"The nominal exchange rate is defined as:",options:["Relative price of domestic and foreign goods","Price of foreign currency in terms of domestic currency","Domestic price level divided by foreign price level","Real exchange rate"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Elementary open economy macroeconomics"}},{id:2,question:"The real exchange rate (q) approximately equals:",options:["E  P*/P","E  P/P*","P/P*","E/P"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Elementary open economy macroeconomics"}},{id:3,question:"Net exports (NX) tend to:",options:["Rise when domestic income rises","Fall when the real exchange rate appreciates","Be independent of exchange rates","Equal zero always"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Elementary open economy macroeconomics"}},{id:4,question:"Savings-investment identity in an open economy implies:",options:["S = I","S  I = NX","S + I = NX","S  I = 0 always"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Elementary open economy macroeconomics"}},{id:5,question:"Uncovered interest parity (UIP) condition states:",options:["i = i*","i  i* + expected depreciation","i  i*  expected depreciation","i  r + "],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Elementary open economy macroeconomics"}},{id:6,question:"Under floating exchange rates with perfect capital mobility (Mundell-Fleming), expansionary monetary policy:",options:["Is ineffective","Is highly effective; currency depreciates, NX rises","Shifts IS only","Appreciates currency"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Elementary open economy macroeconomics"}},{id:7,question:"Under fixed exchange rates with high capital mobility, fiscal expansion:",options:["Is powerful; requires monetary accommodation","Is ineffective","Depreciates currency","Raises inflation only"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Elementary open economy macroeconomics"}},{id:8,question:"A current account deficit corresponds to:",options:["S > I","S < I","S = I","NX > 0"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Elementary open economy macroeconomics"}},{id:9,question:"The J-curve effect suggests that after a depreciation, the trade balance:",options:["Improves immediately","Initially worsens then improves","Is unchanged","Improves then worsens"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Elementary open economy macroeconomics"}},{id:10,question:"Sterilized intervention involves:",options:["FX intervention offset by open market operations to keep money base unchanged","Unsterilized monetary expansion","Capital controls","Tariffs"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Elementary open economy macroeconomics"}},{id:11,question:"Real interest parity holds when:",options:["UIP and equal expected inflation hold","PPP holds","Money is neutral","Capital controls bind"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Elementary open economy macroeconomics"}},{id:12,question:"Purchasing Power Parity (PPP) implies in the long run:",options:["Real exchange rate is constant (1)","Nominal exchange rate equals one","NX = 0","Equal money growth"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Elementary open economy macroeconomics"}},{id:13,question:"An exogenous rise in world interest rate i* under flexible rates tends to:",options:["Appreciate domestic currency and lower output","Depreciate currency and raise output","Raise money demand only","No effect"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Elementary open economy macroeconomics"}},{id:14,question:"Capital account surplus implies:",options:["Current account surplus","Current account deficit (approximately)","NX rises","No change in reserves"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Elementary open economy macroeconomics"}},{id:15,question:"Marshall-Lerner condition states that a depreciation improves the trade balance if:",options:["Sum of export and import demand elasticities (in absolute value) exceeds 1","Exports are inelastic","Imports are perfectly elastic","Income rises"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Elementary open economy macroeconomics"}},{id:16,question:"Under fixed exchange rates, persistent current account deficits tend to:",options:["Raise reserves","Reduce reserves until devaluation/defense","Have no effect on reserves","Raise interest parity"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Elementary open economy macroeconomics"}},{id:17,question:"Expenditure-switching policies refer to:",options:["Fiscal consolidation","Policies (like devaluation) that alter relative prices between domestic and foreign goods","Monetary tightening only","Capital controls"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Elementary open economy macroeconomics"}},{id:18,question:"The absorption approach to current account posits that NX = Y  A, where A is:",options:["Autonomous spending","Total domestic absorption (C + I + G)","Imports only","Exports only"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Elementary open economy macroeconomics"}},{id:19,question:"If domestic inflation exceeds foreign inflation persistently under a peg:",options:["Real appreciation erodes competitiveness","Real depreciation improves competitiveness","No change","Reserves rise"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Elementary open economy macroeconomics"}},{id:20,question:"A capital control that limits outflows under pressure may:",options:["Relieve temporary balance of payments pressure","Improve long-run productivity","Lower inflation immediately","Anchor expectations permanently"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Elementary open economy macroeconomics"}},{id:21,question:"Covered interest parity (CIP) uses:",options:["Spot and forward rates to eliminate arbitrage","Only spot rates","Only expected inflation","Only real rates"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Elementary open economy macroeconomics"}},{id:22,question:"An import tariff generally:",options:["Improves trade balance unambiguously","Distorts relative prices and may worsen overall welfare","Lowers domestic prices","Raises potential output directly"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Elementary open economy macroeconomics"}},{id:23,question:"A credible peg under high mobility forces monetary policy to:",options:["Target domestic goals","Accommodate the peg (import foreign interest rate)","Be independent","Ignore UIP"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Elementary open economy macroeconomics"}},{id:24,question:"Elasticity approach to the balance of trade focuses on:",options:["Price elasticities of exports and imports","Income elasticities only","Money supply","Capital flows"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Elementary open economy macroeconomics"}},{id:25,question:"When domestic output rises faster than trading partners output:",options:["NX rises","NX falls (imports rise faster)","NX unchanged","Exchange rate fixed"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Elementary open economy macroeconomics"}},{id:26,question:"A credible disinflation under a floating regime may:",options:["Appreciate the currency via higher real rates","Depreciate currency","Leave exchange rate unchanged","Lower NX"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Elementary open economy macroeconomics"}},{id:27,question:"In Mundell-Fleming with fixed rates, monetary expansion:",options:["Is offset by reserve outflows (sterilization aside)","Raises Y strongly","Depreciates currency","Raises NX"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Elementary open economy macroeconomics"}},{id:28,question:"Real interest rate differentials in small open economies are limited by:",options:["Capital mobility and UIP","Fiscal policy only","Money supply","PPP"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Elementary open economy macroeconomics"}},{id:29,question:"A terms-of-trade improvement (P_X/P_M rises) tends to:",options:["Raise real income for given volumes","Lower real income","Lower exports","Raise imports prices relative to exports"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Elementary open economy macroeconomics"}},{id:30,question:"Current account equals:",options:["Trade balance only","Trade balance plus net income from abroad plus transfers","Capital account plus financial account","Change in reserves only"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Elementary open economy macroeconomics"}}],hu=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,default:fu},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),gu=[{id:1,question:"The original Phillips curve suggested a negative relationship between:",options:["Inflation and money growth","Inflation and unemployment","Unemployment and output","Prices and wages"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Phillips curve"}},{id:2,question:"The expectations-augmented Phillips curve can be written as:",options:[" = ^e  (u  u_n) + v"," = (u  u_n)","u = u_n  (  ^e)"," = ^e + Y"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Phillips curve"}},{id:3,question:"In the long run, the Phillips curve is:",options:["Downward sloping","Vertical at the natural rate of unemployment","Horizontal","Upward sloping"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Phillips curve"}},{id:4,question:"The NAIRU refers to:",options:["Non-accelerating inflation rate of unemployment","Non-adjusting inflation rate","Natural average inflation rate","Nominal anchor in real units"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Phillips curve"}},{id:5,question:"A supply shock (e.g., oil shock) shifts the short-run Phillips curve:",options:["Down","Up","Left","Makes it vertical"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Phillips curve"}},{id:6,question:"Under adaptive expectations, a disinflation policy typically involves:",options:["No output cost","A temporary increase in unemployment (sacrifice ratio)","Permanent increase in output","Immediate credibility"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Phillips curve"}},{id:7,question:"Rational expectations imply that anticipated monetary policy:",options:["Can systematically lower unemployment","Has no systematic effect on unemployment in the long run","Always lowers inflation","Raises output permanently"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Phillips curve"}},{id:8,question:"The sacrifice ratio measures:",options:["Inflation lost per point of unemployment","Cumulative loss of output needed to reduce inflation by one percentage point","Tax burden of inflation","Change in wages per inflation"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Phillips curve"}},{id:9,question:"If expected inflation falls due to credible policy, the short-run Phillips curve:",options:["Shifts up","Shifts down","Becomes vertical","Shifts right"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Phillips curve"}},{id:10,question:"Hysteresis in unemployment implies that a recession:",options:["Has no effect on natural unemployment","Can raise the natural unemployment rate","Lowers the NAIRU","Only affects inflation"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Phillips curve"}},{id:11,question:"The expectations-augmented Phillips curve links inflation surprises to:",options:["Temporary deviations of unemployment from its natural rate","Permanent unemployment changes","Permanent output changes","Money supply only"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Phillips curve"}},{id:12,question:"If unemployment equals the natural rate, then (ignoring shocks):",options:["Inflation accelerates","Inflation decelerates","Inflation equals expected inflation","Inflation is zero"],correctOption:3,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Phillips curve"}},{id:13,question:"Anchored inflation expectations make disinflation:",options:["More costly","Less costly (lower sacrifice)","Impossible","Always costless"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Phillips curve"}},{id:14,question:"An upward shift in the SR Phillips curve can result from:",options:["Positive supply shock","Negative supply shock or higher expected inflation","Lower taxes","Higher productivity"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Phillips curve"}},{id:15,question:"The long-run Phillips curve being vertical implies monetary neutrality:",options:["Only in the short run","In the long run for unemployment","Never","Always for output"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Phillips curve"}},{id:16,question:"If policymakers exploit a perceived Phillips trade-off without adjusting expectations, then over time:",options:["Inflation falls","Unemployment falls permanently","Expectations rise and the curve shifts up","LR curve shifts left"],correctOption:3,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Phillips curve"}},{id:17,question:"The accelerationist hypothesis posits that constant unemployment below the natural rate leads to:",options:["Stable inflation","Accelerating inflation","Deflation","No change"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Phillips curve"}},{id:18,question:"If actual inflation is below expected inflation, unemployment tends to:",options:["Fall below natural rate","Equal natural rate","Exceed natural rate","Be unaffected"],correctOption:3,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Phillips curve"}},{id:19,question:"Time-inconsistency problem suggests policymakers may:",options:["Achieve zero inflation costlessly","Have an incentive to create surprise inflation","Prefer rules over discretion always","Ignore unemployment"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Phillips curve"}},{id:20,question:"Credible policy rules can:",options:["Worsen inflation expectations","Anchor expectations and lower disinflation costs","Eliminate unemployment","Create hyperinflation"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Phillips curve"}},{id:21,question:"A positive demand shock moves the economy along the SR Phillips curve to:",options:["Lower inflation and higher unemployment","Higher inflation and lower unemployment","Lower inflation and lower unemployment","Higher inflation and higher unemployment"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Phillips curve"}},{id:22,question:"A negative supply shock moves the SR Phillips curve:",options:["Down","Up (higher inflation at any unemployment)","Left","Vertical"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Phillips curve"}},{id:23,question:"If the natural rate falls due to labor market reforms, the long-run Phillips curve:",options:["Shifts right","Shifts left","Shifts up","Unchanged"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Phillips curve"}},{id:24,question:"Lucas critique warns that:",options:["Parameters are policy invariant","Estimated relationships may change when policy rules change","Expectations are irrelevant","Phillips curve is stable"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Phillips curve"}},{id:25,question:"If ^e declines by 2 percentage points with unchanged u and shocks, :",options:["Rises by 2","Falls by 2","Unchanged","Becomes negative"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Phillips curve"}},{id:26,question:"The short-run Phillips curve is flatter when:",options:["Expectations adjust quickly","Expectations adjust slowly and price rigidity is high","Labor markets are flexible","Supply shocks dominate"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Phillips curve"}},{id:27,question:"Okuns law connects unemployment to:",options:["Inflation directly","Output gap (growth deviations)","Money growth","Interest rates"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Phillips curve"}},{id:28,question:"If inflation targeting becomes more credible, the SR Phillips curve:",options:["Shifts up","Shifts down","Becomes vertical immediately","Disappears"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Phillips curve"}},{id:29,question:"Disinflation under rational expectations with credible pre-announced policy can be:",options:["Costly with high unemployment","Nearly costless (if fully credible)","Impossible","Always inflationary"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Phillips curve"}},{id:30,question:"The natural rate of unemployment depends on:",options:["Monetary policy only","Structural factors like matching efficiency, demographics, institutions","Inflation expectations only","Fiscal deficits"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Phillips curve"}}],yu=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,default:gu},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),bu=[{id:1,question:"In the simple Keynesian model (closed economy, no taxes), equilibrium output satisfies:",options:["Y = C + I","Y = C + S","Y = C + G","Y = C + X"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Simple Keynesian Model of income determination and the multiplier"}},{id:2,question:"If C = c0 + c1Y and I is autonomous, the multiplier equals:",options:["1/(1  c1)","1/(1 + c1)","c1/(1  c1)","1  c1"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Simple Keynesian Model of income determination and the multiplier"}},{id:3,question:"An increase in autonomous investment by I changes equilibrium income by approximately:",options:["I","c1I","I/(1  c1)","(1  c1)I"],correctOption:3,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Simple Keynesian Model of income determination and the multiplier"}},{id:4,question:"The marginal propensity to save (MPS) equals:",options:["1  MPC","MPC","APC","1 + MPC"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Simple Keynesian Model of income determination and the multiplier"}},{id:5,question:"The paradox of thrift suggests that an increase in desired saving (lower c0) leads to:",options:["Higher equilibrium income","Lower equilibrium income in the short run","No change in income","Higher investment automatically"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Simple Keynesian Model of income determination and the multiplier"}},{id:6,question:"With proportional taxes T = tY, the government spending multiplier is:",options:["1/(1  c1)","1/(1  c1(1  t))","c1/(1  c1)","1/(1  t)"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Simple Keynesian Model of income determination and the multiplier"}},{id:7,question:"The tax multiplier (for lump-sum taxes) is approximately:",options:["1/(1  c1)","c1/(1  c1)","c1/(1  c1)","1"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Simple Keynesian Model of income determination and the multiplier"}},{id:8,question:"The balanced-budget multiplier (G = T) in the simple model equals:",options:["Zero","One","Greater than one","Less than zero"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Simple Keynesian Model of income determination and the multiplier"}},{id:9,question:"In the simple model, inventories adjust when:",options:["Y > AE, inventories rise","Y < AE, inventories rise","Y = AE, inventories rise","Inventories are fixed"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Simple Keynesian Model of income determination and the multiplier"}},{id:10,question:"In an open economy with imports M = mY (no taxes), the multiplier is:",options:["1/(1  c1)","1/(1  c1 + m)","1/(1  c1  m)","1/(1  m)"],correctOption:3,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Simple Keynesian Model of income determination and the multiplier"}},{id:11,question:"An increase in marginal propensity to consume (c1) makes the multiplier:",options:["Larger","Smaller","Unchanged","Negative"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Simple Keynesian Model of income determination and the multiplier"}},{id:12,question:"Autonomous spending includes:",options:["Income-induced consumption","Autonomous consumption and investment","Only government spending","Only net exports"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Simple Keynesian Model of income determination and the multiplier"}},{id:13,question:"If planned expenditure exceeds output, firms will:",options:["Cut production","Raise prices only","Run down inventories and raise output","Increase taxes"],correctOption:3,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Simple Keynesian Model of income determination and the multiplier"}},{id:14,question:"Crowding out of private investment is absent in the simple model because:",options:["Interest rates are fixed/not modeled","Prices are flexible","Taxes are distortionary","Imports adjust"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Simple Keynesian Model of income determination and the multiplier"}},{id:15,question:"If c1 = 0.8 in a closed economy without taxes, a G = 50 raises Y by:",options:["50","200","250","400"],correctOption:3,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Simple Keynesian Model of income determination and the multiplier"}},{id:16,question:"The condition for equilibrium in the goods market is:",options:["S = T","I = S in equilibrium","G = T","X = M"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Simple Keynesian Model of income determination and the multiplier"}},{id:17,question:"With both proportional taxes (t) and imports (m), the multiplier becomes:",options:["1/[1  c1(1  t) + m]","1/[1  c1(1  t)  m]","1/(1  c1  t  m)","1/(1  t  m)"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Simple Keynesian Model of income determination and the multiplier"}},{id:18,question:"If autonomous taxes rise (lump-sum), equilibrium output:",options:["Rises","Falls by tax multiplier times T","Unchanged","Rises by balanced-budget multiplier"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Simple Keynesian Model of income determination and the multiplier"}},{id:19,question:"The average propensity to consume (APC) equals:",options:["C/Y","C/Y","1  MPS","1  APS"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Simple Keynesian Model of income determination and the multiplier"}},{id:20,question:"An increase in autonomous exports (X) in an open economy:",options:["Has no effect on Y","Raises Y by the open-economy multiplier","Lowers imports only","Raises prices only"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Simple Keynesian Model of income determination and the multiplier"}},{id:21,question:"If c1 is lower, the size of the multiplier is:",options:["Larger","Smaller","Unchanged","Infinite"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Simple Keynesian Model of income determination and the multiplier"}},{id:22,question:"In the Keynesian cross, the 45-degree line represents:",options:["Y = AE","C = Y","I = S","G = T"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Simple Keynesian Model of income determination and the multiplier"}},{id:23,question:"Planned investment is assumed:",options:["Endogenous to income","Autonomous in the simple model","Equal to savings always","A function of interest rate only"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Simple Keynesian Model of income determination and the multiplier"}},{id:24,question:"The multiplier process converges provided:",options:["MPC > 1","MPC < 1","MPC = 1","MPS = 0"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Simple Keynesian Model of income determination and the multiplier"}},{id:25,question:"If imports depend on income, a rise in Y:",options:["Has no effect on M","Raises M, acting as a leakage","Lowers M","Raises X"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Simple Keynesian Model of income determination and the multiplier"}},{id:26,question:"In the simple model with fixed prices, output adjusts via:",options:["Price changes","Quantity changes (production)","Wage changes","Exchange rate changes"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Simple Keynesian Model of income determination and the multiplier"}},{id:27,question:"Suppose c1 = 0.75 and t = 0.2, the government spending multiplier is:",options:["1/(1  0.75) = 4","1/(1  0.750.8)  2.5","1/(1  0.750.2)  1.25","1/(1  0.2) = 1.25"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Simple Keynesian Model of income determination and the multiplier"}},{id:28,question:"If G = 40 and c1 = 0.8 (closed, no taxes), Y equals:",options:["40","80","160","200"],correctOption:3,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Simple Keynesian Model of income determination and the multiplier"}},{id:29,question:"Autonomous consumption (c0) increases when:",options:["Income rises","Interest rates fall, wealth rises","Taxes rise proportionally","Imports rise"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Simple Keynesian Model of income determination and the multiplier"}},{id:30,question:"The condition S + T + M = I + G + X reflects:",options:["Household budget","Leakages equal injections at equilibrium","Government budget balance","External balance"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"Simple Keynesian Model of income determination and the multiplier"}}],vu=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,default:bu},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),Mu=[{id:1,question:"In the Solow model without technological progress, the steady state satisfies:",options:["sf(k) = (n + )k","sf(k) = k","f'(k) = s","y = k"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Solow Model"}},{id:2,question:"With technology growth g and population growth n, steady-state condition is:",options:["sf(k) = (n + g + )k","sf(k) = (g + )k","sf(k) = (n + )k","sf(k) = k"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Solow Model"}},{id:3,question:"An increase in the saving rate s in Solow (without TFP growth) raises:",options:["Long-run growth rate of output per worker","Long-run level of output per worker","Unemployment permanently","Inflation"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Solow Model"}},{id:4,question:"The Golden Rule capital stock satisfies:",options:["f'(k*) = n + g + ","sf(k*) = (n + g + )k*","f(k*) = ","s = n + g + "],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Solow Model"}},{id:5,question:"Conditional convergence in Solow means poorer countries grow faster if:",options:["They have identical savings, population growth, and technology parameters","They have higher inflation","They have higher deficits","They have fixed exchange rates"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Solow Model"}},{id:6,question:"A permanent increase in population growth n causes steady-state k (per effective worker) to:",options:["Rise","Fall","Unchanged","Become infinite"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Solow Model"}},{id:7,question:"In Solow with Cobb-Douglas y = k^, steady-state k increases with:",options:["Higher s and lower n + g + ","Lower s and higher n","Higher ","Lower productivity"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Solow Model"}},{id:8,question:"Technological progress in Solow implies that long-run growth of output per worker equals:",options:["Zero","g (the rate of technology growth)","n","s"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Solow Model"}},{id:9,question:"If s is below the Golden Rule, raising s will:",options:["Lower steady-state consumption","Raise steady-state consumption per effective worker","Leave consumption unchanged","Lower output"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Solow Model"}},{id:10,question:"Transitional dynamics in Solow imply that after a rise in s:",options:["Output jumps immediately to new steady state","Output per worker grows temporarily faster until reaching new level","Growth rate falls to zero immediately","Capital falls"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Solow Model"}},{id:11,question:"Capital deepening refers to:",options:["Rising capital per worker","Rising labor force","Falling savings","Higher depreciation"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Solow Model"}},{id:12,question:"The steady-state investment share equals:",options:["s","(n + g + )k/y","1  s",""],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Solow Model"}},{id:13,question:"Higher depreciation  shifts the (n + g + )k line:",options:["Down","Up","Left","Right"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Solow Model"}},{id:14,question:"In the Solow model, a one-time increase in s has what effect on long-run growth of y?",options:["Raises permanently","Lowers permanently","No effect on long-run growth rate, only level","Makes it negative"],correctOption:3,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Solow Model"}},{id:15,question:"If technology is labor-augmenting (A grows at g), then variables per effective worker are:",options:["Stationary at steady state","Explosive","Declining","Undefined"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Solow Model"}},{id:16,question:"The capital accumulation equation per effective worker is:",options:["k = sf(k)  (n + g + )k","k = s  ","k = f(k)  s","k = (n + g + )k  sf(k)"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Solow Model"}},{id:17,question:"A fall in the saving rate s from above-Golden Rule level will:",options:["Raise steady-state consumption","Lower steady-state consumption","No effect","Raise steady-state output"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Solow Model"}},{id:18,question:"If  < 1 in Cobb-Douglas, diminishing returns to capital imply:",options:["Higher k raises y at increasing rate","Higher k raises y at decreasing rate","No effect","Negative returns"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Solow Model"}},{id:19,question:"With no population or technology growth (n = g = 0), the Golden Rule is:",options:["f'(k*) = ","sf(k*) = k*","s = ","k* = 0"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Solow Model"}},{id:20,question:"A temporary investment tax credit that raises s for a few years will:",options:["Raise steady-state permanently","Temporarily raise growth and the level; long-run growth unchanged","Lower steady-state level","Raise long-run growth"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Solow Model"}},{id:21,question:"An increase in n shifts the break-even investment line and causes:",options:["Higher k*","Lower k* and y*","No change","Higher consumption"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Solow Model"}},{id:22,question:"Solow residual measures:",options:["Growth due to capital only","Growth due to labor only","Total factor productivity (unexplained by K and L)","Inflation"],correctOption:3,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Solow Model"}},{id:23,question:"If s rises while n, g,  constant, the steady-state capital-output ratio:",options:["Rises","Falls","Unchanged","Becomes infinite"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Solow Model"}},{id:24,question:"In Solow, policies that raise g (technology growth) will:",options:["Raise long-run growth of output per worker","Lower long-run growth","No effect","Only lower inflation"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Solow Model"}},{id:25,question:"The steady-state consumption per effective worker equals:",options:["f(k*)  (n + g + )k*","sf(k*)","(1  s)f(k*)","f'(k*)"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Solow Model"}},{id:26,question:"A fall in  (depreciation) causes steady-state k* to:",options:["Fall","Rise","Unchanged","Become zero"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Solow Model"}},{id:27,question:"Convergence speed in Solow depends on:",options:["Elasticity of substitution only","Capital share  and rates n, g, ","Inflation rate","Government debt"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Solow Model"}},{id:28,question:"If two countries have the same s, n, g,  and technology, Solow predicts:",options:["No convergence","Conditional convergence to similar income levels","Divergence","Random walk"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Solow Model"}},{id:29,question:"An increase in s above Golden Rule implies in the long-run steady state:",options:["Higher consumption","Lower consumption despite higher output","No change","Lower output"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Solow Model"}},{id:30,question:"With Cobb-Douglas, the capital share  equals:",options:["MPK  K/Y","MPL  L/Y","s","n + g + "],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Macro Economics",topic:"the Solow Model"}}],Eu=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,default:Mu},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),wu=JSON.parse('[{"id":1,"question":"In a standard Cournot duopoly with identical firms and linear demand, each firm chooses which variable?","options":["Its output quantity","Its price","Its advertising level","Its tax payment"],"correctOption":1,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Duopoly with Cournot and Bertrand competition"}},{"id":2,"question":"In a Bertrand duopoly with identical products and constant marginal costs, the Nash equilibrium price under usual assumptions is equal to:","options":["Monopoly price","Average cost","Marginal cost","Zero"],"correctOption":3,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Duopoly with Cournot and Bertrand competition"}},{"id":3,"question":"Which assumption is crucial for the Bertrand paradox result in a duopoly?","options":["Capacity constraints","Homogeneous products and identical constant marginal costs","Differentiated products","Collusion between firms"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Duopoly with Cournot and Bertrand competition"}},{"id":4,"question":"In Cournot competition, each firms best response function describes:","options":["Its optimal price given rivals prices","Its optimal quantity given rivals quantities","Its optimal cost given rivals costs","Its optimal tax given government policy"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Duopoly with Cournot and Bertrand competition"}},{"id":5,"question":"Consider a Cournot duopoly with market demand P = a  bQ and identical firms with constant marginal cost c < a. In equilibrium, total quantity is:","options":["(a  c) / b","(a  c) / (2b)","2(a  c) / (3b)","3(a  c) / (4b)"],"correctOption":3,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Duopoly with Cournot and Bertrand competition"}},{"id":6,"question":"In a Cournot duopoly with identical firms and linear demand, equilibrium price relative to monopoly and perfect competition prices is typically:","options":["Higher than monopoly price","Equal to monopoly price","Between monopoly and marginal cost prices","Below marginal cost"],"correctOption":3,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Duopoly with Cournot and Bertrand competition"}},{"id":7,"question":"Which of the following tends to increase total output in a Cournot duopoly?","options":["Higher marginal cost for both firms","Entry of another identical firm","Stronger product differentiation","Collusive agreement between firms"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Duopoly with Cournot and Bertrand competition"}},{"id":8,"question":"In a Bertrand duopoly with homogeneous products and no capacity constraints, if one firm slightly undercuts the rivals price above marginal cost, its demand becomes:","options":["Half the market","Zero","The entire market","Unchanged"],"correctOption":3,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Duopoly with Cournot and Bertrand competition"}},{"id":9,"question":"In Cournot competition, each firms residual demand curve depends on:","options":["Only its own cost function","Market demand minus rivals chosen quantities","Government-imposed price ceiling","Consumer income distribution only"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Duopoly with Cournot and Bertrand competition"}},{"id":10,"question":"Which market structure is most closely approximated by a Cournot duopoly as the number of identical firms becomes very large?","options":["Monopoly","Perfect competition","Monopsony","Natural monopoly"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Duopoly with Cournot and Bertrand competition"}},{"id":11,"question":"In a symmetric Cournot duopoly, if both firms reduce their marginal costs, the equilibrium outcome will feature:","options":["Lower output and higher price","Higher output and lower price","Unchanged output and price","Higher output and higher price"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Duopoly with Cournot and Bertrand competition"}},{"id":12,"question":"Bertrand competition with differentiated products typically leads to equilibrium prices that are:","options":["Equal to marginal cost","Below marginal cost","Above marginal cost","Undefined"],"correctOption":3,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Duopoly with Cournot and Bertrand competition"}},{"id":13,"question":"In a simple Cournot duopoly, each firm assumes that its rivals output:","options":["Will adjust immediately to any change it makes","Is fixed when choosing its own output","Is chosen to maximize joint profits","Is equal to zero"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Duopoly with Cournot and Bertrand competition"}},{"id":14,"question":"Which of the following is a key difference between Cournot and Bertrand duopoly models?","options":["Number of firms in the industry","Time horizon of firms decisions","Choice variable: quantity versus price","Presence of marginal cost"],"correctOption":3,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Duopoly with Cournot and Bertrand competition"}},{"id":15,"question":"In a Bertrand duopoly with identical costs and homogeneous products, if both firms set the same price equal to marginal cost, then each firms profit is:","options":["Positive","Negative","Zero economic profit","Infinite"],"correctOption":3,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Duopoly with Cournot and Bertrand competition"}},{"id":16,"question":"Suppose a Cournot duopoly faces linear demand and symmetric costs. If one firm increases its output along the best response function, the other firms best response is to:","options":["Increase its own output","Decrease its own output","Keep output constant","Exit the market"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Duopoly with Cournot and Bertrand competition"}},{"id":17,"question":"In Cournot duopoly, a reaction function that is downward sloping indicates that outputs are:","options":["Strategic complements","Strategic substitutes","Perfectly correlated","Independent"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Duopoly with Cournot and Bertrand competition"}},{"id":18,"question":"In Bertrand competition with capacity constraints, the equilibrium price relative to marginal cost is most likely:","options":["Exactly equal to marginal cost","Below marginal cost","Above marginal cost","Unrelated to marginal cost"],"correctOption":3,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Duopoly with Cournot and Bertrand competition"}},{"id":19,"question":"Which statement about profits is typically correct in a symmetric Cournot duopoly versus Bertrand duopoly with homogeneous goods and identical costs?","options":["Cournot profits are lower than Bertrand profits","Cournot and Bertrand profits are always equal","Cournot profits are higher than Bertrand profits","Both yield zero profits"],"correctOption":3,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Duopoly with Cournot and Bertrand competition"}},{"id":20,"question":"In a linear demand Cournot duopoly with zero marginal cost, which outcome holds for total quantity compared to monopoly?","options":["Duopoly quantity is lower than monopoly quantity","Duopoly quantity equals monopoly quantity","Duopoly quantity lies between monopoly and perfect competition quantities","Duopoly quantity equals perfect competition quantity"],"correctOption":3,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Duopoly with Cournot and Bertrand competition"}},{"id":21,"question":"In the Stackelberg model compared to the Cournot model, the leader firm typically:","options":["Produces less output and earns lower profit","Produces more output and earns higher profit","Produces the same output and profit","Always earns zero profit"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Duopoly with Cournot and Bertrand competition"}},{"id":22,"question":"Which assumption erodes the Bertrand paradox by preventing price from being bid down to marginal cost?","options":["Perfect information","Infinite capacity","Product differentiation","Identical firms"],"correctOption":3,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Duopoly with Cournot and Bertrand competition"}},{"id":23,"question":"In Cournot duopoly, the Nash equilibrium is obtained by:","options":["Maximizing joint profits","Solving each firms best response simultaneously","Setting price equal to average cost","Allocating market shares equally by assumption"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Duopoly with Cournot and Bertrand competition"}},{"id":24,"question":"If two firms in a Bertrand duopoly with homogeneous products collude perfectly, the resulting price is closest to:","options":["Marginal cost","Monopoly price","Average variable cost","Zero"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Duopoly with Cournot and Bertrand competition"}},{"id":25,"question":"Which of the following best describes the strategic variable in Bertrand competition?","options":["Quantity of output","Quality level","Price of the product","Number of employees"],"correctOption":3,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Duopoly with Cournot and Bertrand competition"}},{"id":26,"question":"In a simple Cournot duopoly, if one firm unilaterally reduces its output from the Nash equilibrium quantity, holding the rivals quantity fixed, its profit will typically:","options":["Increase","Decrease","Remain unchanged","Become negative"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Duopoly with Cournot and Bertrand competition"}},{"id":27,"question":"Under Bertrand competition with identical firms and homogeneous products, if marginal cost increases for both firms, the equilibrium price will:","options":["Remain at the old marginal cost","Fall below the new marginal cost","Rise to the new marginal cost","Remain unchanged at zero"],"correctOption":3,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Duopoly with Cournot and Bertrand competition"}},{"id":28,"question":"In Cournot duopoly, if market demand becomes more elastic while costs are unchanged, the equilibrium mark-up over marginal cost tends to:","options":["Increase","Decrease","Stay the same","Become negative"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Duopoly with Cournot and Bertrand competition"}},{"id":29,"question":"When the number of Cournot competitors increases without bound, the market outcome converges to:","options":["Monopoly outcome","Bertrand outcome with differentiation","Perfectly competitive outcome","Monopsony outcome"],"correctOption":3,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Duopoly with Cournot and Bertrand competition"}},{"id":30,"question":"In a Cournot duopoly with identical costs, each firms equilibrium quantity compared to monopoly quantity is:","options":["Equal to the entire monopoly quantity","Equal to half the monopoly quantity","Equal to one-third of monopoly quantity","Equal to two-thirds of monopoly quantity"],"correctOption":3,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Duopoly with Cournot and Bertrand competition"}}]'),qu=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,default:wu},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),Ou=[{id:1,question:"An externality exists when:",options:["A firm faces market power","An action imposes costs or benefits on others not reflected in prices","Government sets taxes","Consumers have perfect information"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Externalities"}},{id:2,question:"A negative production externality implies:",options:["Marginal private cost equals marginal social cost","Marginal social cost exceeds marginal private cost","Marginal private benefit exceeds marginal social benefit","No deadweight loss"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Externalities"}},{id:3,question:"The Pigouvian tax is set equal to:",options:["Average external cost","Marginal external cost at the efficient quantity","Total external cost","Marginal private cost"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Externalities"}},{id:4,question:"Coase theorem suggests efficiency is achievable when:",options:["Property rights are undefined","Transaction costs are low and rights are well-defined","Taxes are high","Markets are perfectly competitive"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Externalities"}},{id:5,question:"A positive consumption externality causes:",options:["Over-consumption relative to social optimum","Under-consumption relative to social optimum","No change in consumption","Monopoly outcomes"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Externalities"}},{id:6,question:"Tradable pollution permits aim to:",options:["Fix prices directly","Set quantity cap and let market determine price","Eliminate property rights","Increase total pollution"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Externalities"}},{id:7,question:"Under Pigouvian taxation, the competitive equilibrium becomes efficient because:",options:["Private marginal cost shifts to equal social marginal cost","Demand increases","Supply becomes perfectly elastic","Prices fall below marginal cost"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Externalities"}},{id:8,question:"With heterogeneous abatement costs, a permit system is efficient because:",options:["It allocates permits to high-cost firms","It equalizes marginal abatement costs across firms","It encourages uniform standards","It lowers transaction costs to zero"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Externalities"}},{id:9,question:"A Pigouvian subsidy is appropriate for:",options:["Negative externalities","Positive externalities","Public goods","Monopolies"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Externalities"}},{id:10,question:"Command-and-control regulation often leads to inefficiency because:",options:["It ignores technological heterogeneity","It sets quantity caps","It allows trading","It uses taxes"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Externalities"}},{id:11,question:"In the presence of external costs, the competitive equilibrium quantity is:",options:["Equal to the efficient quantity","Higher than the efficient quantity","Lower than the efficient quantity","Unchanged"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Externalities"}},{id:12,question:"Network externalities are unique because:",options:["They are always negative","They affect utility through the number of users","They only apply to firms","They eliminate deadweight loss"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Externalities"}},{id:13,question:"A congestion externality is best addressed by:",options:["Price ceilings","Tolls or congestion pricing","Subsidies","Import tariffs"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Externalities"}},{id:14,question:"If transaction costs are high, Coasean bargaining:",options:["Likely achieves efficiency","Fails to achieve efficiency","Is unnecessary","Leads to monopoly"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Externalities"}},{id:15,question:"The socially optimal level of pollution is typically:",options:["Zero","Positive where marginal abatement cost equals marginal damage","Maximized","Undefined"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Externalities"}},{id:16,question:"Double-dividend hypothesis claims that Pigouvian taxes:",options:["Always reduce efficiency","Can improve environment and reduce distortionary taxes","Only raise revenue","Eliminate externalities"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Externalities"}},{id:17,question:"A spillover benefit leads to:",options:["Under-provision of the activity","Over-provision of the activity","No effect","Price above marginal cost"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Externalities"}},{id:18,question:"Marginal damage function measures:",options:["Change in private cost from output","Additional harm from one more unit of pollution","Total harm from pollution","Average cost of abatement"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Externalities"}},{id:19,question:"A standard vs. tax trade-off depends on:",options:["Information about marginal damages and abatement costs","Market power of firms","Government budget","Consumer preferences only"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Externalities"}},{id:20,question:"Cap-and-trade achieves cost-effectiveness by:",options:["Assigning equal abatement to all firms","Allowing firms with low abatement cost to reduce more","Setting uniform taxes","Eliminating monitoring"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Externalities"}},{id:21,question:"Internalizing an externality means:",options:["Ignoring external costs","Reflecting external costs or benefits in decision-making via prices or regulations","Setting lower output","Creating a monopoly"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Externalities"}},{id:22,question:"A common-pool resource faces externalities due to:",options:["Non-rivalry","Non-excludability and rivalry leading to overuse","Perfect exclusion","Increasing returns"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Externalities"}},{id:23,question:"When marginal damage is highly uncertain, a policy choice may favor:",options:["Price instrument (tax) over quantity (cap)","Quantity instrument over price","No regulation","Command-and-control"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Externalities"}},{id:24,question:"The Weitzman prices vs. quantities result suggests:",options:["Choose tax if marginal damages are steep","Choose tax if marginal abatement cost is steeper than marginal damage","Choose cap if marginal damage is steeper than marginal abatement cost","Taxes are always better"],correctOption:3,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Externalities"}},{id:25,question:"With asymmetric information, Pigouvian taxes may be:",options:["Hard to calibrate to true marginal damage","Always accurate","Unnecessary","Strictly dominated by standards"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Externalities"}},{id:26,question:"A subsidy for R&D addresses externalities by:",options:["Penalizing innovation","Encouraging activities with spillover benefits","Reducing competition","Increasing monopoly power"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Externalities"}},{id:27,question:"Local air pollution with immobile sources likely favors:",options:["International treaties","Local standards or taxes","No policy","Import quotas"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Externalities"}},{id:28,question:"A liability rule can reduce externalities by:",options:["Removing property rights","Making polluters pay for damages","Subsidizing output","Setting price ceilings"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Externalities"}},{id:29,question:"Network congestion in platforms is best mitigated by:",options:["Flat fees","Dynamic pricing and capacity management","Import tariffs","Quantity rationing"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Externalities"}},{id:30,question:"The deadweight loss from a negative externality reflects:",options:["Underproduction relative to optimum","Overproduction relative to optimum","Perfect efficiency","Zero consumer surplus"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Externalities"}}],_u=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,default:Ou},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),Su=[{id:1,question:"In a two-good, two-consumer exchange economy, a Walrasian equilibrium is defined by:",options:["Prices and allocations where markets clear and agents maximize given budgets","Uniform allocations regardless of preferences","Zero prices for all goods","Government-imposed quantities"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"General equilibrium"}},{id:2,question:"The Edgeworth box represents:",options:["Production possibilities","Consumption allocations and preferences of two agents","Government budgets","Market supply curves"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"General equilibrium"}},{id:3,question:"A Pareto efficient allocation in the Edgeworth box occurs where:",options:["Indifference curves are parallel","Indifference curves are tangent (MRS equalized)","One agents utility is maximized","Prices are zero"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"General equilibrium"}},{id:4,question:"The First Welfare Theorem states that under certain conditions, competitive equilibria are:",options:["Always inefficient","Pareto efficient","Always unique","Government optimal"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"General equilibrium"}},{id:5,question:"The Second Welfare Theorem requires:",options:["Convex preferences and technologies","Non-convexities","Externalities","Incomplete markets"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"General equilibrium"}},{id:6,question:"In a pure exchange economy, the Walrasian auctioneers role is to:",options:["Set quantities directly","Adjust prices to clear markets","Collect taxes","Subsidize producers"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"General equilibrium"}},{id:7,question:"Excess demand function properties include:",options:["Homogeneity of degree one in prices","Walras Law (value of excess demand sums to zero)","Symmetry across goods","Decreasing in income"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"General equilibrium"}},{id:8,question:"Walras Law implies:",options:["If all but one market clear, the remaining market must also clear","Prices are constant","Budget constraints are irrelevant","Government budget must balance"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"General equilibrium"}},{id:9,question:"A competitive equilibrium with production additionally requires:",options:["Profit maximization and zero profits under constant returns","Price-taking behavior only","Government intervention","Non-convex technology"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"General equilibrium"}},{id:10,question:"The contract curve in the Edgeworth box is:",options:["Set of allocations where MRS are equalized","Set of initial endowments","Set of production plans","Set of price vectors"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"General equilibrium"}},{id:11,question:"Gross substitutability of goods helps ensure:",options:["Existence of equilibrium","Uniqueness and stability of equilibrium in tatonnement","Non-convexities","Externalities"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"General equilibrium"}},{id:12,question:"In general equilibrium, a change in one market affects others via:",options:["Income and substitution effects across markets","Only substitution effects","Only income effects","No linkage"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"General equilibrium"}},{id:13,question:"The Arrow-Debreu model assumes:",options:["Complete markets and convexity","Incomplete markets and non-convexity","Monopoly","Government pricing"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"General equilibrium"}},{id:14,question:"Existence of competitive equilibrium generally requires:",options:["Continuity, convexity, and local non-satiation","Discontinuity and non-convexity","Satiation","Externalities"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"General equilibrium"}},{id:15,question:"Local non-satiation ensures that:",options:["Agents prefer less to more","Agents can improve utility with small changes","Markets do not clear","Prices are negative"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"General equilibrium"}},{id:16,question:"A transfer (lump-sum tax/subsidy) can achieve any Pareto efficient allocation under:",options:["Non-convex preferences","Convex preferences and technologies","Incomplete markets","Externalities"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"General equilibrium"}},{id:17,question:"General equilibrium analysis differs from partial equilibrium by:",options:["Considering a single market","Considering all markets simultaneously","Ignoring income effects","Assuming fixed prices"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"General equilibrium"}},{id:18,question:"In production economies, the equality of MRTS across firms implies:",options:["Technical inefficiency","Cost minimization and productive efficiency","Profit maximization","Monopoly power"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"General equilibrium"}},{id:19,question:"The marginal rate of transformation (MRT) equals:",options:["Ratio of marginal utilities","Slope of the production possibility frontier","Income elasticity","Price ratio"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"General equilibrium"}},{id:20,question:"At a competitive equilibrium with production, allocative efficiency requires:",options:["MRS = MRT = price ratio","MRS = MRTS","MRTS = price","MRS > MRT"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"General equilibrium"}},{id:21,question:"Tatonnement is a process where:",options:["Quantities adjust","Prices adjust to excess demand without trades until equilibrium","Government sets quotas","Firms collude"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"General equilibrium"}},{id:22,question:"A core allocation lies:",options:["Outside the contract curve","Within the set of Pareto efficient allocations not blocked by coalitions","Only at initial endowments","Always unique"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"General equilibrium"}},{id:23,question:"Incomplete markets can lead to:",options:["First-best outcomes","Constrained Pareto inefficiency","No effect","Perfect insurance"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"General equilibrium"}},{id:24,question:"In Arrow-Debreu with uncertainty, contingent commodities allow:",options:["No risk sharing","Complete risk sharing through state-contingent claims","Monopoly pricing","Only spot markets"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"General equilibrium"}},{id:25,question:"Gross complementarity may cause tatonnement:",options:["To converge","To diverge or oscillate","To be unique","To require subsidies"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"General equilibrium"}},{id:26,question:"At equilibrium, each firm maximizes profits where:",options:["Price equals average cost","Price equals marginal cost under perfect competition","Price exceeds marginal cost","Cost is minimized without profit"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"General equilibrium"}},{id:27,question:"Walrasian equilibrium prices are determined up to:",options:["Absolute level","A numeraire (only relative prices matter)","Zero","Government fiat"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"General equilibrium"}},{id:28,question:"A social planners problem in general equilibrium seeks:",options:["Profit maximization","Utility maximization subject to feasibility","Tax revenue maximization","Price stabilization"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"General equilibrium"}},{id:29,question:"Comparative statics in general equilibrium analyze:",options:["Only supply shifts","Effects of parameter changes on the entire system","Government policies only","Single-market demand shifts"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"General equilibrium"}},{id:30,question:"If all agents have identical homothetic preferences, then:",options:["Income distribution affects relative demands","Income distribution does not affect aggregate Engel curves","Prices are irrelevant","Markets fail"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"General equilibrium"}}],ju=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,default:Su},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),xu=JSON.parse('[{"id":1,"question":"Which condition is essential for a perfectly competitive market?","options":["Product differentiation","Free entry and exit","Few sellers","High transaction costs"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Market structure under perfect competition"}},{"id":2,"question":"In perfect competition, firms are considered:","options":["Price makers","Price takers","Collusive decision makers","Regulated monopolists"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Market structure under perfect competition"}},{"id":3,"question":"In the long run under perfect competition, firms earn:","options":["Supernormal profit","Normal profit","Losses","Unlimited returns"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Market structure under perfect competition"}},{"id":4,"question":"The supply curve of a perfectly competitive firm is given by the portion of:","options":["MC above AVC","AC above MC","AVC above AC","MC below AVC"],"correctOption":1,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Market structure under perfect competition"}},{"id":5,"question":"In perfect competition, price equals:","options":["Marginal cost","Average cost","Marginal revenue","All of the above"],"correctOption":4,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Market structure under perfect competition"}},{"id":6,"question":"A perfectly elastic demand curve for a firm implies:","options":["Firm can increase price","Firm controls market demand","Infinite buyers at market price","Downward sloping demand"],"correctOption":3,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Market structure under perfect competition"}},{"id":7,"question":"Shortrun profit maximization occurs where:","options":["MR = AR","MR = MC","MC = AC","AC = AR"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Market structure under perfect competition"}},{"id":8,"question":"A firm shuts down in the short run when:","options":["P < MC","P < MR","P < AVC","P < AC"],"correctOption":3,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Market structure under perfect competition"}},{"id":9,"question":"Which feature ensures identical prices in perfect competition?","options":["Barriers to entry","Homogeneous product","Government price regulation","Brand loyalty"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Market structure under perfect competition"}},{"id":10,"question":"In perfect competition, allocative efficiency occurs because:","options":["P > MC","P = MC","P < MC","MC is irrelevant"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Market structure under perfect competition"}},{"id":11,"question":"In a perfectly competitive market, the demand curve facing an individual firm is:","options":["Downward sloping","Horizontal","Vertical","Kinked"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Market structure under perfect competition"}},{"id":12,"question":"Which factor does NOT characterize perfect competition?","options":["Many buyers and sellers","Perfect information","Product branding","Homogeneous goods"],"correctOption":3,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Market structure under perfect competition"}},{"id":13,"question":"Productive efficiency in perfect competition occurs because firms produce at:","options":["Minimum AC","Maximum AC","Rising MC","Declining AVC"],"correctOption":1,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Market structure under perfect competition"}},{"id":14,"question":"In the long run, entry and exit of firms lead the market to:","options":["Losses","Normal profit","Supernormal profits","Monopoly"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Market structure under perfect competition"}},{"id":15,"question":"The marginal revenue curve for a perfectly competitive firm is:","options":["Downward sloping","Equal to price","Above demand curve","Vertical"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Market structure under perfect competition"}},{"id":16,"question":"Which of the following does a firm maximize under perfect competition?","options":["Total revenue","Market share","Profit","Cost minimization only"],"correctOption":3,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Market structure under perfect competition"}},{"id":17,"question":"If P = AC in the long run, it implies:","options":["Normal profit","Loss","Supernormal profit","Shutdown condition"],"correctOption":1,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Market structure under perfect competition"}},{"id":18,"question":"Perfect competition leads to:","options":["Underproduction","Overproduction","Socially optimal output","Deadweight loss"],"correctOption":3,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Market structure under perfect competition"}},{"id":19,"question":"A firm increases output as long as:","options":["MR > MC","MC > MR","AC > MR","AVC > MR"],"correctOption":1,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Market structure under perfect competition"}},{"id":20,"question":"Which assumption ensures no firm influences price?","options":["Single seller","Large number of firms","Product innovation","Patent ownership"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Market structure under perfect competition"}},{"id":21,"question":"In perfect competition, longrun supply curve is:","options":["Upward sloping","Horizontal","Vertical","Kinked"],"correctOption":1,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Market structure under perfect competition"}},{"id":22,"question":"Economic profit in short run can be:","options":["Positive only","Zero only","Negative only","Positive, zero, or negative"],"correctOption":4,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Market structure under perfect competition"}},{"id":23,"question":"Which curve is identical to the demand curve of a competitive firm?","options":["MC","AC","AR","AVC"],"correctOption":3,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Market structure under perfect competition"}},{"id":24,"question":"Entry of new firms in the market causes:","options":["Price to rise","Price to fall","Cost to fall","Demand to increase"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Market structure under perfect competition"}},{"id":25,"question":"A firm exits the market in long run when:","options":["P < AC","P > MC","P > MR","P = AVC"],"correctOption":1,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Market structure under perfect competition"}},{"id":26,"question":"Perfect competition assumes mobility of:","options":["Labor only","Capital only","Labor and capital","Neither labor nor capital"],"correctOption":3,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Market structure under perfect competition"}},{"id":27,"question":"Consumer surplus in perfect competition is:","options":["Zero","Maximized","Minimized","Negative"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Market structure under perfect competition"}},{"id":28,"question":"Producer surplus in long run is:","options":["Positive","Negative","Zero","Unlimited"],"correctOption":3,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Market structure under perfect competition"}},{"id":29,"question":"Perfect competition results in:","options":["Xinefficiency","No productive efficiency","Minimum cost production","Welfare loss"],"correctOption":3,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Market structure under perfect competition"}},{"id":30,"question":"Which curve determines shortrun supply?","options":["AC","AVC","MC above AVC","MR"],"correctOption":3,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Market structure under perfect competition"}}]'),Pu=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,default:xu},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),Au=[{id:1,question:"Which characteristic best defines a pure public good?",options:["Rivalrous and excludable","Rivalrous but non-excludable","Non-rivalrous and non-excludable","Non-rivalrous but excludable"],correctOption:3,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Public goods"}},{id:2,question:"The free-rider problem arises because:",options:["Producers charge too high a price","Consumers cannot be excluded from benefits","Goods are always rivalrous","Government sets inefficient taxes"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Public goods"}},{id:3,question:"For a public good, Samuelsons condition for optimal provision is that:",options:["Sum of marginal costs equals marginal benefit","Sum of individual marginal benefits equals marginal cost","Average benefit equals marginal cost","Price equals marginal cost"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Public goods"}},{id:4,question:"Non-rivalry implies that:",options:["Consumption by one reduces availability for others","Consumption by one increases costs for others","Consumption by one does not reduce availability for others","Producers face increasing marginal costs"],correctOption:3,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Public goods"}},{id:5,question:"National defense is typically modeled as:",options:["A private good","A club good","A common-pool resource","A pure public good"],correctOption:4,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Public goods"}},{id:6,question:"A club good is:",options:["Non-rivalrous and excludable","Rivalrous and non-excludable","Non-rivalrous and non-excludable","Rivalrous and excludable"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Public goods"}},{id:7,question:"The Lindahl equilibrium addresses public goods by:",options:["Setting a uniform tax rate","Assigning personalized prices equal to marginal benefits","Privatizing the good","Eliminating non-excludability"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Public goods"}},{id:8,question:"In a two-person economy, the efficient quantity of a public good occurs where:",options:["Individual marginal benefit equals marginal cost","Sum of marginal benefits equals marginal cost","Average marginal benefit equals marginal cost","Total benefit equals total cost"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Public goods"}},{id:9,question:"Crowding in public goods provision refers to:",options:["Private donations displacing government spending","Government spending stimulating private contributions","Excess demand causing shortages","Congestion reducing utility"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Public goods"}},{id:10,question:"Congestible public goods are:",options:["Always non-rivalrous","Non-rivalrous up to a capacity limit","Rivalrous at all levels","Non-excludable and rivalrous"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Public goods"}},{id:11,question:"Mechanism design for public goods often fails due to:",options:["Dominant strategy truth-telling always holds","Preference revelation problems","Zero marginal cost","Complete information"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Public goods"}},{id:12,question:"The voluntary contribution game typically yields:",options:["Pareto efficient outcomes","Under-provision relative to social optimum","Over-provision relative to social optimum","Perfect information equilibria"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Public goods"}},{id:13,question:"Excludability for public goods can be improved by:",options:["Lowering marginal cost","Introducing subscription or toll systems","Increasing rivalry","Setting price caps"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Public goods"}},{id:14,question:"The marginal social benefit curve for a public good is:",options:["Horizontal sum of individual MB curves","Vertical sum of individual MB curves","Average of individual MB curves","Equal to marginal private benefit"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Public goods"}},{id:15,question:"When preferences are quasi-linear, the Lindahl mechanism:",options:["Cannot reach efficiency","Simplifies to uniform pricing","May reach efficiency under certain conditions","Always fails due to free-riding"],correctOption:3,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Public goods"}},{id:16,question:"A public bad is characterized by:",options:["Positive externalities","Non-rivalrous negative effects","Rivalrous negative effects","Non-excludable positive effects"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Public goods"}},{id:17,question:"Tiebout sorting suggests efficiency can be approximated by:",options:["Centralized taxation","Mobility across jurisdictions revealing preferences","Monopoly provision","Random allocation"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Public goods"}},{id:18,question:"The median voter theorem implies for public goods that:",options:["Provision equals social optimum","Provision reflects median preference under majority rule","Provision minimizes total cost","Provision maximizes producer surplus"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Public goods"}},{id:19,question:"A common policy to address under-provision is:",options:["Price ceilings","Pigouvian subsidies","Quantity rationing","Import tariffs"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Public goods"}},{id:20,question:"Non-excludability can lead to:",options:["Market power","Moral hazard","Free-riding","Adverse selection"],correctOption:3,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Public goods"}},{id:21,question:"In the Samuelson rule, each individuals marginal rate of substitution is:",options:["Equal to price","Summed across individuals at optimum","Minimized at equilibrium","Equal to marginal cost individually"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Public goods"}},{id:22,question:"Public provision may be preferred when:",options:["Transaction costs are negligible","Preferences are homogeneous","Exclusion costs are high","Private sector has better information"],correctOption:3,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Public goods"}},{id:23,question:"The VCG (Vickrey-Clarke-Groves) mechanism can:",options:["Always achieve budget balance","Achieve efficiency but often fails budget balance","Never achieve efficiency","Eliminate preference heterogeneity"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Public goods"}},{id:24,question:"In the presence of crowding, the efficient provision condition becomes:",options:["Sum of MB equals MC plus congestion cost","Sum of MB equals average cost","MB equals MC for each individual","Total benefit equals total cost"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Public goods"}},{id:25,question:"Warm-glow giving implies:",options:["Altruism reduces private utility","Donors derive utility from giving itself","Public goods become rivalrous","Taxes crowd out giving completely"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Public goods"}},{id:26,question:"A shared lighthouse is best modeled as:",options:["Private good","Common-pool resource","Club good","Pure public good"],correctOption:4,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Public goods"}},{id:27,question:"When exclusion is possible but costly, optimal policy often:",options:["Privatizes fully","Uses mixed financing with user fees","Sets zero price","Bans consumption"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Public goods"}},{id:28,question:"If individual demand for a public good is linear, the aggregate demand is:",options:["Horizontal sum of quantities","Vertical sum of willingness-to-pay","Average of individual demands","Product of demands"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Public goods"}},{id:29,question:"Public goods create market failures primarily due to:",options:["Information asymmetry","Non-rivalry and non-excludability","Scale economies","Regulatory capture"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Public goods"}},{id:30,question:"A practical approach to provision under heterogeneous preferences is:",options:["Uniform taxation","Menu of contribution schemes","Quantity rationing","Monopoly pricing"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Public goods"}}],Iu=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,default:Au},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),Cu=JSON.parse(`[{"id":1,"question":"In game theory, a strategy is defined as:","options":["A single action taken at one stage","A comprehensive plan of actions across all possible scenarios","A prediction of the opponent's move","A government policy"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Elementary strategic interaction"}},{"id":2,"question":"The Nash equilibrium is a set of strategies such that:","options":["No player can improve their payoff by changing strategies unilaterally","Players cooperate to maximize joint payoff","Each player chooses the strategy that maximizes opponents loss","Players alternate moves"],"correctOption":1,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Elementary strategic interaction"}},{"id":3,"question":"Dominant strategy is one that:","options":["Always gives the highest payoff regardless of opponents' actions","Is chosen by the strongest player","Requires cooperation","Is never a Nash equilibrium"],"correctOption":1,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Elementary strategic interaction"}},{"id":4,"question":"In the Prisoner's Dilemma, mutual defection is:","options":["Pareto optimal","A Nash equilibrium","Socially optimal","Impossible"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Elementary strategic interaction"}},{"id":5,"question":"A zero-sum game is characterized by:","options":["All players gain together","All payoffs sum to zero","All strategies are identical","No strategic interaction"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Elementary strategic interaction"}},{"id":6,"question":"Which concept refers to making decisions based on the assumption that other players are rational?","options":["Pareto optimality","Strategic dominance","Rational expectations","Backward induction"],"correctOption":3,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Elementary strategic interaction"}},{"id":7,"question":"The process of deducing optimal moves from the end of the game back to the start is called:","options":["Dominance","Backward induction","Strategic interaction","Forward reasoning"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Elementary strategic interaction"}},{"id":8,"question":"If a player in a game never benefits from choosing a particular strategy, that strategy is:","options":["Dominant","Strictly dominated","Best response","Mixed"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Elementary strategic interaction"}},{"id":9,"question":"Mixed strategy equilibria are relevant when:","options":["Players randomize among strategies","Players always have a dominant strategy","Games are cooperative","Payoffs are fixed"],"correctOption":1,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Elementary strategic interaction"}},{"id":10,"question":"Best response in game theory refers to:","options":["The strategy that guarantees the highest possible payoff","The strategy that maximizes a player's payoff given rivals strategies","A dominant strategy","Any Nash equilibrium strategy"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Elementary strategic interaction"}},{"id":11,"question":"A symmetric game is one where:","options":["All players have access to the same strategies and payoffs depend only on strategy profiles","All players have identical payoffs","All players play simultaneously","All strategies are strictly dominated"],"correctOption":1,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Elementary strategic interaction"}},{"id":12,"question":"In repeated games, cooperation may emerge because:","options":["Players are irrational","Future payoffs matter","Players choose strictly dominated strategies","Each stage is a zero-sum game"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Elementary strategic interaction"}},{"id":13,"question":"Payoff matrices are used primarily to analyze:","options":["Repeated games","Simultaneous-move games","Continuous strategies","Randomized payoffs"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Elementary strategic interaction"}},{"id":14,"question":"A pure strategy involves:","options":["Randomizing actions","Choosing a single action with certainty","Switching between actions each round","Low payoffs"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Elementary strategic interaction"}},{"id":15,"question":"Which game does not necessarily have a dominant strategy for each player?","options":["Prisoners Dilemma","Matching Pennies","Battle of the Sexes","All of the above"],"correctOption":4,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Elementary strategic interaction"}},{"id":16,"question":"A focal point in game theory is:","options":["An outcome that players tend to select by intuition or convention","A Nash equilibrium","The dominant strategy","A strictly dominated strategy"],"correctOption":1,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Elementary strategic interaction"}},{"id":17,"question":"The strategy of tit-for-tat is commonly studied in:","options":["Single-shot games","Repeated Prisoners Dilemma","Matching Pennies","Zero-sum games"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Elementary strategic interaction"}},{"id":18,"question":"The Minimax theorem is central to:","options":["Cooperative games","Zero-sum games","Stochastic games","Repeated games"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Elementary strategic interaction"}},{"id":19,"question":"In a sequential game, the order of moves impacts outcomes because:","options":["Players may commit to strategies","Players cannot observe past actions","Payoffs are fixed","Players only have one strategy each"],"correctOption":1,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Elementary strategic interaction"}},{"id":20,"question":"A strategy is weakly dominant if:","options":["It strictly outperforms all others","It performs at least as well as every other strategy, and better in some cases","It is always strictly dominated","It is chosen by both players"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Elementary strategic interaction"}},{"id":21,"question":"Which of the following games has no pure strategy Nash equilibrium?","options":["Prisoner's Dilemma","Matching Pennies","Battle of the Sexes","Stag Hunt"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Elementary strategic interaction"}},{"id":22,"question":"The concept of subgame perfect equilibrium is relevant for:","options":["Simultaneous-move games","Sequential games","Zero-sum games","Random games"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Elementary strategic interaction"}},{"id":23,"question":"If a player randomizes between two strategies to make their opponent indifferent, this is:","options":["Backward induction","Best response","Mixed strategy Nash equilibrium","Dominant strategy"],"correctOption":3,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Elementary strategic interaction"}},{"id":24,"question":"Two players must coordinate to achieve the highest payoff. This describes a:","options":["Coordination game","Zero-sum game","Prisoner's Dilemma","Dominance game"],"correctOption":1,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Elementary strategic interaction"}},{"id":25,"question":"What is the key challenge in the Battle of the Sexes game?","options":["Finding dominant strategies","Coordination without communication","Maximizing total payoff","Randomization"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Elementary strategic interaction"}},{"id":26,"question":"A Nash equilibrium can exist in:","options":["Pure strategies only","Mixed strategies only","Either pure or mixed strategies","Not at all"],"correctOption":3,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Elementary strategic interaction"}},{"id":27,"question":"If a player always gets a lower payoff by choosing a certain strategy, this strategy is:","options":["Dominant","Strictly dominated","Best response","Mixed"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Elementary strategic interaction"}},{"id":28,"question":"Which is true of Nash equilibrium?","options":["It is always Pareto efficient","No player can improve their payoff by changing strategies unilaterally","It must involve dominant strategies","It does not require mutual best responses"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Elementary strategic interaction"}},{"id":29,"question":"A strategic move is:","options":["An action that changes the structure or payoffs of the game","A Nash equilibrium","A dominant strategy","Always illegal"],"correctOption":1,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Elementary strategic interaction"}},{"id":30,"question":"Best-response dynamics refer to:","options":["Players choosing their strategies sequentially to maximize payoffs against current choices","Players alternating dominant strategies","Randomized strategies only","Always leading to zero-sum outcomes"],"correctOption":1,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Elementary strategic interaction"}}]`),Tu=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,default:Cu},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),Ru=[{id:1,question:"Which of the following best describes the concept of diminishing marginal utility?",options:["Total satisfaction increases as consumption increases","Additional satisfaction from consuming one more unit declines","Consumers always prefer more of a good","Utility remains constant regardless of consumption"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Theory of consumer behaviour"}},{id:2,question:"Indifference curves are typically convex to the origin because:",options:["Consumers prefer extremes of goods","Marginal rate of substitution increases","Marginal rate of substitution diminishes","Utility decreases with more consumption"],correctOption:3,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Theory of consumer behaviour"}},{id:3,question:"A consumer reaches equilibrium when:",options:["The indifference curve lies above the budget line","The budget line is tangent to the indifference curve","The consumer spends all income on one good","The slope of the budget line is zero"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Theory of consumer behaviour"}},{id:4,question:"The budget line shifts parallel to the right when:",options:["Price of the good rises","Price of the good falls","Consumer income increases","Consumer preferences change"],correctOption:3,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Theory of consumer behaviour"}},{id:5,question:"If two goods are perfect substitutes, the indifference curves will be:",options:["L-shaped","Downward sloping straight lines","Upward sloping curves","Convex to the origin"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Theory of consumer behaviour"}},{id:6,question:"According to the law of equi-marginal utility, a consumer allocates income such that:",options:["Total utility from each good is equal","Marginal utility per unit of money spent is equal across goods","Average utility is maximized","Marginal utility is constant"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Theory of consumer behaviour"}},{id:7,question:"The point where an indifference curve touches but does not cross the budget line represents:",options:["Inefficient consumption","Consumer equilibrium","Negative utility","Marginal utility maximization only for one good"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Theory of consumer behaviour"}},{id:8,question:"A higher indifference curve represents:",options:["Lower level of satisfaction","Higher price of goods","Higher level of satisfaction","No change in utility"],correctOption:3,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Theory of consumer behaviour"}},{id:9,question:"The marginal rate of substitution (MRS) measures:",options:["The rate at which income increases utility","The trade-off between goods to maintain utility","The slope of the budget line","Elasticity of demand"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Theory of consumer behaviour"}},{id:10,question:"If an indifference curve is concave to the origin, it violates the assumption of:",options:["Transitivity","Completeness","Diminishing MRS","Rationality"],correctOption:3,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Theory of consumer behaviour"}},{id:11,question:"A Giffen good is characterized by:",options:["Negative income elasticity","Upward sloping demand curve","Perfectly elastic demand","Zero substitution effect"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Theory of consumer behaviour"}},{id:12,question:"The substitution effect occurs when:",options:["Income increases holding prices constant","Relative prices change holding utility constant","Preferences change","All prices change proportionally"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Theory of consumer behaviour"}},{id:13,question:"The income effect of a price fall for a normal good will:",options:["Reduce quantity demanded","Increase quantity demanded","Have no impact on demand","Reverse the substitution effect"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Theory of consumer behaviour"}},{id:14,question:"Hicksian demand curves hold which variable constant?",options:["Income","Utility","Market prices","Consumer tastes"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Theory of consumer behaviour"}},{id:15,question:"Slutsky decomposition separates price effect into:",options:["Income and wealth effects","Income and substitution effects","Income and price elasticity","Indifference and budget effects"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Theory of consumer behaviour"}},{id:16,question:"Engel curves show the relationship between:",options:["Price and quantity demanded","Income and quantity demanded","Utility and consumption","Price and utility"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Theory of consumer behaviour"}},{id:17,question:"If two goods are perfect complements, the indifference curves will be:",options:["Straight lines","L-shaped","Convex curves","Parallel to the axes"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Theory of consumer behaviour"}},{id:18,question:"Revealed preference theory assumes that consumers:",options:["Maximize cardinal utility","Make consistent choices","Do not face budget constraints","Prefer less to more"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Theory of consumer behaviour"}},{id:19,question:"Cardinal utility theory differs from ordinal utility theory because it:",options:["Ranks preferences without measurement","Measures utility in absolute terms","Rejects the concept of marginal utility","Does not assume rationality"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Theory of consumer behaviour"}},{id:20,question:"The slope of the budget line represents:",options:["Marginal utility ratio","Opportunity cost between goods","Total spending capacity","Income elasticity"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Theory of consumer behaviour"}},{id:21,question:"A price consumption curve traces the consumers equilibrium at:",options:["Different income levels","Different price levels of a good","Different preference schedules","Different utility levels"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Theory of consumer behaviour"}},{id:22,question:"A good with zero income elasticity of demand is classified as:",options:["Normal good","Inferior good","Giffen good","Neutral good"],correctOption:4,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Theory of consumer behaviour"}},{id:23,question:"The elasticity of substitution measures:",options:["Change in income relative to demand","Ease of substituting one good for another","Change in demand due to price","Satisfaction level from consumption"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Theory of consumer behaviour"}},{id:24,question:"Consumer surplus represents:",options:["Difference between marginal cost and price","Difference between willingness to pay and actual price","Total utility from consumption","Income saved after consumption"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Theory of consumer behaviour"}},{id:25,question:"The assumption of transitivity implies that:",options:["Consumers prefer more to less","Preferences remain constant over time","If A is preferred to B and B to C, then A is preferred to C","Utility is measurable"],correctOption:3,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Theory of consumer behaviour"}}],Nu=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,default:Ru},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),Du=JSON.parse('[{"id":1,"question":"The law of diminishing marginal returns applies when:","options":["All inputs are increased proportionally","At least one input is fixed while others are variable","Inputs are used in perfect proportions","Firms operate in the long run"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Theory of Production"}},{"id":2,"question":"The isoquant curve represents:","options":["Combinations of inputs producing the same output","Combinations of outputs with the same profit","Combinations of prices that remain constant","Combinations of utility levels"],"correctOption":1,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Theory of Production"}},{"id":3,"question":"A production function showing constant returns to scale implies:","options":["Output increases less than proportionately with inputs","Output increases more than proportionately with inputs","Output increases proportionately with inputs","Output remains unchanged with increased inputs"],"correctOption":3,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Theory of Production"}},{"id":4,"question":"Marginal product becomes negative when:","options":["Total product is at its maximum","Total product begins to fall","Average product is increasing","Marginal cost is constant"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Theory of Production"}},{"id":5,"question":"An isoquant is convex to the origin because of:","options":["Increasing marginal rate of technical substitution","Constant marginal rate of technical substitution","Diminishing marginal rate of technical substitution","Negative marginal productivity"],"correctOption":3,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Theory of Production"}},{"id":6,"question":"The expansion path shows:","options":["Optimal input combinations at different output levels","Optimal consumption at different income levels","Cost curves of the firm","Profit maximization levels"],"correctOption":1,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Theory of Production"}},{"id":7,"question":"Increasing returns to scale occur when:","options":["Output increases less than input increases","Output increases more than input increases","Input increases but output remains constant","Marginal product equals zero"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Theory of Production"}},{"id":8,"question":"In short run production, the shape of the marginal product curve is primarily due to:","options":["Law of supply","Law of diminishing marginal returns","Law of demand","Perfect competition"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Theory of Production"}},{"id":9,"question":"Total product increases at an increasing rate when:","options":["Marginal product is rising","Marginal product is falling but positive","Marginal product is zero","Average product is constant"],"correctOption":1,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Theory of Production"}},{"id":10,"question":"Returns to scale refer to changes in:","options":["Output when all inputs change","Output when only one input changes","Cost when wages change","Profit when price changes"],"correctOption":1,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Theory of Production"}},{"id":11,"question":"The marginal rate of technical substitution measures:","options":["Rate at which output substitutes capital","Rate at which labor substitutes output","Rate at which labor substitutes capital","Rate at which cost substitutes profit"],"correctOption":3,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Theory of Production"}},{"id":12,"question":"If total product is maximum, marginal product is:","options":["Positive","Negative","Zero","Maximum"],"correctOption":3,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Theory of Production"}},{"id":13,"question":"The Cobb-Douglas production function typically exhibits:","options":["Constant elasticity of substitution","Infinite elasticity of substitution","Zero elasticity of substitution","Negative elasticity of substitution"],"correctOption":1,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Theory of Production"}},{"id":14,"question":"A ridge line in production theory indicates:","options":["Area of rational production","Point of profit maximization","Cost minimization area","Consumer equilibrium"],"correctOption":1,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Theory of Production"}},{"id":15,"question":"Labor becomes inefficient when marginal product is:","options":["Constant","Increasing","Zero or negative","Equal to average product"],"correctOption":3,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Theory of Production"}},{"id":16,"question":"The point where marginal product equals average product is where average product is:","options":["Minimum","Maximum","Constant","Negative"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Theory of Production"}},{"id":17,"question":"Isoquants cannot intersect because:","options":["Marginal product is constant","Different output levels cannot have the same combination of inputs","Costs remain the same","Firms maximize utility"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Theory of Production"}},{"id":18,"question":"A homogeneous production function of degree one implies:","options":["Decreasing returns to scale","Increasing returns to scale","Constant returns to scale","Zero returns to scale"],"correctOption":3,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Theory of Production"}},{"id":19,"question":"Short run production involves:","options":["All inputs variable","At least one input fixed","No fixed inputs","Only capital variable"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Theory of Production"}},{"id":20,"question":"The long run is defined as a period in which:","options":["Only labor varies","Capital is fixed","All inputs are variable","Output is constant"],"correctOption":3,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Theory of Production"}},{"id":21,"question":"The law of variable proportions applies to:","options":["Long run production","Short run production","Perfect competition","Monopoly"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Theory of Production"}},{"id":22,"question":"Inputs that cannot be easily adjusted in short run are called:","options":["Variable inputs","Fixed inputs","Marginal inputs","Derived inputs"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Theory of Production"}},{"id":23,"question":"When average product is falling, marginal product must be:","options":["Above average product","Equal to average product","Below average product","Zero"],"correctOption":3,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Theory of Production"}},{"id":24,"question":"A firm chooses an input combination where:","options":["MRTS equals the ratio of input prices","MRTS is zero","MRTS is infinite","Costs equal revenue"],"correctOption":1,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Theory of Production"}},{"id":25,"question":"Neutral technical progress implies:","options":["Output decreases with same inputs","Marginal product of labor increases more than capital","Marginal products of inputs rise proportionately","Capital becomes obsolete"],"correctOption":3,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Theory of Production"}},{"id":26,"question":"Stage II of production is considered rational because:","options":["Marginal product is negative","Average product is increasing","Marginal product is positive and falling","Total product is decreasing"],"correctOption":3,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Theory of Production"}},{"id":27,"question":"Total product decreases when marginal product is:","options":["Positive","Zero","Negative","Constant"],"correctOption":3,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Theory of Production"}},{"id":28,"question":"Production functions indicate:","options":["Relationship between cost and output","Relationship between inputs and output","Relationship between price and demand","Relationship between utility and consumption"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Theory of Production"}},{"id":29,"question":"The elasticity of substitution measures:","options":["Ease of substituting output for profit","Ease of substituting one input for another","Ease of substituting income for consumption","Ease of substituting wage for rent"],"correctOption":2,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Theory of Production"}},{"id":30,"question":"The point of inflection on the total product curve corresponds to:","options":["Maximum marginal product","Zero marginal product","Negative marginal product","Minimum marginal product"],"correctOption":1,"subject":{"name":"Micro Economics","topic":"Theory of Production"}}]'),ku=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,default:Du},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),Lu=[{id:1,question:"A social welfare function aggregates:",options:["Firm profits","Individual utilities according to a normative criterion","Government revenue","Market prices"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Welfare economics"}},{id:2,question:"Utilitarian social welfare maximizes:",options:["Minimum utility","Sum of utilities","Product of utilities","Median utility"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Welfare economics"}},{id:3,question:"Rawlsian (maximin) criterion focuses on:",options:["Average utility","Utility of the richest","Utility of the poorest","Sum of utilities"],correctOption:3,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Welfare economics"}},{id:4,question:"Kaldor-Hicks efficiency allows policy changes if:",options:["Winners can potentially compensate losers","Losers can block any change","Only Pareto improvements are allowed","Taxes are zero"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Welfare economics"}},{id:5,question:"The compensation test is criticized because:",options:["It requires actual compensation","It ignores distributional concerns","It always fails","It is purely descriptive"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Welfare economics"}},{id:6,question:"Pareto efficiency implies:",options:["No one can be made better off without making someone worse off","Everyone is equally well-off","Government revenue is maximized","Prices are minimized"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Welfare economics"}},{id:7,question:"Arrows impossibility theorem shows that:",options:["Majority rule is always efficient","No social choice rule can satisfy a set of fairness axioms simultaneously","Markets cannot be efficient","Utility cannot be measured"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Welfare economics"}},{id:8,question:"The Bergson-Samuelson social welfare function is:",options:["Positive economics","Normative and value-laden","A market mechanism","A taxation rule"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Welfare economics"}},{id:9,question:"The marginal cost of public funds measures:",options:["Cost of producing a public good","Excess burden of raising revenue through distortionary taxation","Administrative cost only","Zero under lump-sum taxes"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Welfare economics"}},{id:10,question:"Deadweight loss from a tax arises because:",options:["Government spends the revenue","Prices change","Tax distorts choices away from efficient levels","Tax is too small"],correctOption:3,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Welfare economics"}},{id:11,question:"Equivalent variation (EV) and compensating variation (CV) are measures of:",options:["Producer surplus","Welfare change based on expenditure required under different prices","Government revenue","Tax incidence"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Welfare economics"}},{id:12,question:"At the optimum in a utilitarian framework with identical individuals, policy equates:",options:["MRS across individuals","Marginal utilities of income","Average utility to zero","Taxes to zero"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Welfare economics"}},{id:13,question:"Distributional weights in cost-benefit analysis are used to:",options:["Ignore inequality","Give greater weight to benefits accruing to the poor","Increase government revenue","Eliminate deadweight loss"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Welfare economics"}},{id:14,question:"Second-best theory states that when one constraint cannot be satisfied:",options:["The remaining first-best conditions remain optimal","The remaining conditions may need adjustment for overall welfare","No solution exists","Taxes must be zero"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Welfare economics"}},{id:15,question:"The Atkinson index measures:",options:["Inflation","Inequality based on social welfare assumptions","Unemployment","Growth"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Welfare economics"}},{id:16,question:"A Pigouvian tax improves welfare by:",options:["Increasing monopoly power","Internalizing external costs","Reducing producer surplus only","Eliminating deadweight loss in perfectly competitive markets without externalities"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Welfare economics"}},{id:17,question:"The excess burden of a tax is larger when:",options:["Demand and supply are inelastic","Demand or supply are elastic","Tax revenue is high","Market is small"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Welfare economics"}},{id:18,question:"Social welfare maximization with concave utility reflects:",options:["Risk neutrality","Preference for equality due to diminishing marginal utility","Preference for inequality","Perfect information"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Welfare economics"}},{id:19,question:"Tax incidence depends on:",options:["Who legally pays","Relative elasticities of demand and supply","Government choice only","Prices being fixed"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Welfare economics"}},{id:20,question:"The social marginal cost of public funds exceeds one when:",options:["Taxes are lump-sum","Taxes are distortionary","Preferences are quasilinear","Markets are complete"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Welfare economics"}},{id:21,question:"A utilitarian planner facing heterogeneous individuals would:",options:["Ignore inequality","Equalize marginal utility of income across individuals","Maximize the utility of the richest","Set zero taxes"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Welfare economics"}},{id:22,question:"The Gini coefficient measures:",options:["Efficiency","Inequality in income distribution","Inflation","Externalities"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Welfare economics"}},{id:23,question:"A lump-sum transfer is preferred in welfare terms because:",options:["It raises revenue","It is non-distortionary compared to commodity taxes","It eliminates inequality","It increases prices"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Welfare economics"}},{id:24,question:"The marginal excess burden of taxation refers to:",options:["Average burden","Additional deadweight loss from raising an extra unit of revenue","Administrative burden","Zero under perfect competition"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Welfare economics"}},{id:25,question:"Cost-benefit analysis uses net present value to:",options:["Measure current profits","Aggregate discounted benefits minus costs over time","Set taxes","Define market equilibrium"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Welfare economics"}},{id:26,question:"Interpersonal utility comparisons are:",options:["Always possible and objective","Normative and require value judgments","Irrelevant to policy","Purely positive"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Welfare economics"}},{id:27,question:"Social welfare with inequality aversion is often modeled using:",options:["Linear utility","Convex utility","Concave utility functions","Random utility"],correctOption:3,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Welfare economics"}},{id:28,question:"Equivalent and compensating variation differ because:",options:["They measure producer surplus","They evaluate welfare change at different reference prices/income","They are identical measures","They only apply to taxes"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Welfare economics"}},{id:29,question:"A social planners first-best policy set is feasible when:",options:["All markets are complete and there are no externalities","There are externalities","Preferences are non-convex","Taxes are distortionary"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Welfare economics"}},{id:30,question:"A Pareto improvement is:",options:["Any change that raises total surplus","A change that makes at least one person better off without making anyone worse off","A change that increases government revenue","A change that lowers prices"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Micro Economics",topic:"Welfare economics"}}],Hu=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,default:Lu},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),Gu=[{id:5,question:"Which CSS property is used to change the text color?",options:["font-color","text-color","color","text-style"],correctOption:3,subject:{name:"Web Development",topic:"CSS Basics"}},{id:6,question:"What does CSS stand for?",options:["Creative Style Sheets","Cascading Style Sheets","Computer Style Sheets","Colorful Style Sheets"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Web Development",topic:"CSS Basics"}},{id:7,question:"Which CSS property controls the text size?",options:["font-style","text-size","font-size","text-style"],correctOption:3,subject:{name:"Web Development",topic:"CSS Basics"}},{id:8,question:"Which CSS display value hides an element?",options:["display: hidden;","display: none;","display: invisible;","display: hide;"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Web Development",topic:"CSS Basics"}}],Bu=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,default:Gu},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),zu=[{id:9,question:"What does HTML stand for?",options:["Hyper Text Markup Language","High Tech Modern Language","Home Tool Markup Language","Hyperlinks and Text Markup Language"],correctOption:1,subject:{name:"Web Development",topic:"HTML Basics"}},{id:10,question:"Which HTML tag is used to define an internal style sheet?",options:["<css>","<script>","<style>","<styles>"],correctOption:3,subject:{name:"Web Development",topic:"HTML Basics"}},{id:11,question:"Which HTML attribute is used to define inline styles?",options:["styles","style","class","font"],correctOption:2,subject:{name:"Web Development",topic:"HTML Basics"}}],Uu=Object.freeze(Object.defineProperty({__proto__:null,default:zu},Symbol.toStringTag,{value:"Module"})),Kn=Object.assign({"./questions/js_basics.json":iu,"./questions/macro_eco_ad_as_models.json":su,"./questions/macro_eco_harrod_domar_model.json":cu,"./questions/macro_eco_is_lm_model.json":lu,"./questions/macro_eco_money_banking_inflation.json":pu,"./questions/macro_eco_national_income_accounting.json":du,"./questions/macro_eco_open_economy_elementary.json":hu,"./questions/macro_eco_phillips_curve.json":yu,"./questions/macro_eco_simple_keynesian_model.json":vu,"./questions/macro_eco_solow_model.json":Eu,"./questions/micro_eco_duopoly.json":qu,"./questions/micro_eco_externalities.json":_u,"./questions/micro_eco_general_equilibrium.json":ju,"./questions/micro_eco_perfect_competitions.json":Pu,"./questions/micro_eco_public_goods.json":Iu,"./questions/micro_eco_strategy_interaction.json":Tu,"./questions/micro_eco_theory_of_consumer_behaviour.json":Nu,"./questions/micro_eco_theory_of_production.json":ku,"./questions/micro_eco_welfare_economics.json":Hu,"./questions/webdev_css.json":Bu,"./questions/webdev_html.json":Uu}),no=[];for(const e in Kn){const t=Kn[e],o=t&&t.default||[];Array.isArray(o)&&no.push(...o)}const So=new Map;for(const e of no){const t=e?.subject?.name||"General",o=e?.subject?.topic||"General";So.has(t)||So.set(t,new Set),So.get(t).add(o)}function Fu(){const e={};for(const[t,o]of So.entries())e[t]=Array.from(o).sort();return e}function Wu({selectedSubject:e="all",selectedTopic:t="all"}={}){return e==="all"?[...no]:t==="all"?no.filter(o=>o?.subject?.name===e):no.filter(o=>o?.subject?.name===e&&o?.subject?.topic===t)}const Vu={class:"page"},Ku={class:"container"},Yu={key:0,class:"progress-bar"},Qu={key:3,class:"card text-center"},$u={__name:"Quiz",setup(e){const t=Ki(),o=Ae(0),i=Ae(0),n=Ae(!1),s=Ae([]),r=h=>{const M=[...h];for(let _=M.length-1;_>0;_--){const G=Math.floor(Math.random()*(_+1));[M[_],M[G]]=[M[G],M[_]]}return M},a=async()=>{const h=localStorage.getItem("quizSettings");let M={questionCount:10,shuffleQuestions:!0,selectedSubject:"all",selectedTopic:"all"};h&&(M={...M,...JSON.parse(h)});let _=Wu({selectedSubject:M.selectedSubject,selectedTopic:M.selectedTopic});M.shuffleQuestions&&(_=r(_));const G=Math.min(M.questionCount,_.length);s.value=_.slice(0,G),o.value=0,i.value=0,n.value=!1},c=ae(()=>s.value[o.value]),m=ae(()=>(o.value/s.value.length*100).toFixed(0)),u=h=>{h&&i.value++,o.value<s.value.length-1?setTimeout(()=>{o.value++},300):setTimeout(()=>{n.value=!0},300)},d=()=>{a()},g=()=>{t.push("/")};return zi(()=>{a()}),(h,M)=>(ce(),qe("div",Vu,[M[2]||(M[2]=L("div",{class:"nav-header"},[L("div",{class:"nav-title"},"Quiz App")],-1)),L("div",Ku,[n.value?Eo("",!0):(ce(),qe("div",Yu,[L("div",{class:"progress-fill",style:Go({width:m.value+"%"})},null,4)])),!n.value&&c.value?(ce(),To($l,{key:1,question:c.value,"question-number":o.value+1,"total-questions":s.value.length,onAnswer:u},null,8,["question","question-number","total-questions"])):Eo("",!0),n.value?(ce(),To(tu,{key:2,score:i.value,"total-questions":s.value.length,onRetry:d,onHome:g},null,8,["score","total-questions"])):Eo("",!0),!n.value&&!c.value?(ce(),qe("div",Qu,[M[0]||(M[0]=L("h2",null,"No Questions Available",-1)),M[1]||(M[1]=L("p",{class:"mb-3"},"Please adjust your settings and try again.",-1)),L("button",{onClick:g,class:"btn btn-primary"},"Go Home")])):Eo("",!0)])]))}},Zu={class:"page"},Ju={class:"container"},Xu={class:"card"},ep={class:"form-group"},tp={class:"form-group"},op=["value"],ip={class:"form-group"},np=["value"],sp={class:"checkbox-group"},Yn=20,rp={__name:"Settings",setup(e){const t=Ki(),o=Ae(10),i=Ae(!0),n=Ae("all"),s=Ae("all"),r=Fu(),a=ae(()=>["all",...Object.keys(r)]),c=ae(()=>{if(n.value==="all"){const h=Object.values(r).flat();return["all",...Array.from(new Set(h))]}return["all",...r[n.value]||[]]});zi(()=>{const g=localStorage.getItem("quizSettings");if(g){const h=JSON.parse(g);o.value=h.questionCount||10,i.value=h.shuffleQuestions!==!1,n.value=h.selectedSubject||"all",s.value=h.selectedTopic||"all"}});const m=()=>{const g={questionCount:o.value,shuffleQuestions:i.value,selectedSubject:n.value,selectedTopic:s.value};localStorage.setItem("quizSettings",JSON.stringify(g)),t.push("/")},u=()=>{t.push("/")},d=()=>{s.value="all"};return(g,h)=>(ce(),qe("div",Zu,[L("div",Ju,[L("div",Xu,[h[7]||(h[7]=L("div",{class:"card-header"},[L("h2",null," Settings")],-1)),L("div",ep,[L("label",{class:"form-label",for:"questionCount"}," Number of Questions (max "+we(Yn)+") "),Mo(L("input",{id:"questionCount","onUpdate:modelValue":h[0]||(h[0]=M=>o.value=M),type:"number",class:"form-control",min:1,max:Yn},null,512),[[Pa,o.value,void 0,{number:!0}]])]),L("div",tp,[h[4]||(h[4]=L("label",{class:"form-label",for:"subject"},"Subject",-1)),Mo(L("select",{id:"subject","onUpdate:modelValue":h[1]||(h[1]=M=>n.value=M),class:"form-control",onChange:d},[(ce(!0),qe(je,null,gi(a.value,M=>(ce(),qe("option",{key:M,value:M},we(M==="all"?"All Subjects":M),9,op))),128))],544),[[xn,n.value]])]),L("div",ip,[h[5]||(h[5]=L("label",{class:"form-label",for:"topic"},"Topic",-1)),Mo(L("select",{id:"topic","onUpdate:modelValue":h[2]||(h[2]=M=>s.value=M),class:"form-control"},[(ce(!0),qe(je,null,gi(c.value,M=>(ce(),qe("option",{key:M,value:M},we(M==="all"?"All Topics":M),9,np))),128))],512),[[xn,s.value]])]),L("div",sp,[Mo(L("input",{id:"shuffle","onUpdate:modelValue":h[3]||(h[3]=M=>i.value=M),type:"checkbox"},null,512),[[Aa,i.value]]),h[6]||(h[6]=L("label",{for:"shuffle",class:"form-label",style:{"margin-bottom":"0"}}," Shuffle questions ",-1))]),L("div",{class:"btn-group mt-3"},[L("button",{onClick:m,class:"btn btn-primary btn-block"}," Save Settings "),L("button",{onClick:u,class:"btn btn-secondary btn-block"}," Cancel ")])])])]))}},cp=[{path:"/",name:"Home",component:Fl},{path:"/quiz",name:"Quiz",component:$u},{path:"/settings",name:"Settings",component:rp}],ap=Bl({history:Ml(),routes:cp});Ta(zl).use(ap).mount("#app");
